<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows Phone 7 on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/windows-phone-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows Phone 7 on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 20:37:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/windows-phone-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What are your target platforms for games?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 20:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</guid>
      <description>I decided to run a little poll to track what platforms do you target as a game developer. I think this should be interesting. Please share this post link or the direct link to the poll (http://twtpoll.com/dar51l) so that we can have more accurate results.
The poll closes in about 6 days and you can select various options of course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who wants to try Vizati Demo?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/who-wants-to-try-vizati-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 22:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/who-wants-to-try-vizati-demo/</guid>
      <description>Ok, I know I’ve been making far too much posts about Vizati but this time it’s for a good reason, anyone interested in trying out the game can do it…right about NOW…
http://www.differentpixel.com/2010/06/vizati-demo-available/
Also on a quick update, yesterday I had the chance to test Vizati at Windows Phone 7 Developer’s Hub on a real WP7 device, which was awesome. I want to thank João Antão, Nuno Costa, Ben Riga and Neil Hutson for the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yay, my first Game as Indie Developer is almost out</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/yay-my-first-game-as-indie-developer-is-almost-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 20:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/yay-my-first-game-as-indie-developer-is-almost-out/</guid>
      <description>No, I’m not dead….yet…
It’s just that I’ve been stuck on Different Pixel development dungeon for the past weeks finishing and polishing (bug hunting) my first game, Vizati.
Most of you have been following the process and asking things every since we showed the beta version at XNA Pizza Night, after which we decided to finish the game and try to sell it to see how it goes.
Three months later and here I am, making the final touches on the game before it’s release on 11th June.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati on Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/vizati-in-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 20:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/vizati-in-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>It’s been awhile since my last post. I’ve been utterly busy so I haven’t had the time for any tutorials.
This week I got an invitation from João Antão to showcase Vizati as part of his XNA Framework presentation. This occurred during the Imagine Cup final on Portugal.
I’ve been playing with the WP7 tools and I decided to try and port Vizati to XNA 4.0 and give it a try on the emulator so I could show all 3 versions running simultaneous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA 4.0 CTP and Windows Phone Developer Tools CTP now available for download</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-4-0-ctp-and-windows-phone-developer-tools-ctp-now-available-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 23:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-4-0-ctp-and-windows-phone-developer-tools-ctp-now-available-for-download/</guid>
      <description>So I was watching Microsoft Mix10 and while talking about the new Windows Phone 7 Series, Scott Guthrie announced the availability of the Windows Phone Developer Tools CTP. What? But like now now?
I went to http://developer.windowsphone.com/ and XNA Creator’s Club and there it was. The packages contains:
A CTP of the new Visual Studio 2010 Express for Windows Phone Tools and framework to develop Windows Phone applications and games with Silverlight A CTP of XNA Game Studio 4.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
