<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XCode on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/xcode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XCode on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 20:03:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/xcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Puwang - a 5 day work</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 20:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</guid>
      <description>Hi, how’s everyone doing?
So this was a different week for me. It’s been a long time that I had the chance to work on a small prototype or a 48H competition because of my work on Dary’s Legend so I decided to stop for a couple of days and do something else.
Also my cat’s been quite sick, and between the Vet and taking care of him, working on a fun project gave me more time do everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing dark borders sprites on iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 12:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>I ran into this issue a couple hours ago working on the iPhone sdk:
See the darker borders around the image?
It’s a png image and that’s was supposed to be a gradient of alpha. So why am I getting this strange stuff around it?
Well that’s because that alpha isn’t 0 or 1 or 0 or 255.
The first thing I found out is that XCode grabs the png images and multiplies the RGB component with the alpha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing iPhone Sdk and MacOSX</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/testing-iphone-sdk-and-macosx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 11:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/testing-iphone-sdk-and-macosx/</guid>
      <description>So last weekend I finally got my hands on a fully operational Mac OSX with the iPhone SDK so I decided to give it a try.
First of all I had to set myself comfortable with this new OS since I’ve always used Windows. It’s not that hard and most of the things are straitgh forward.
I booted up X-Code and decided to test an iPhone Application and after 3-4 hours of researching and testing I managed to get a sprite on screen that moves to were I press on screen.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
