<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sapphire on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/sapphire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sapphire on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 12:40:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/sapphire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time for some new tools and editor</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</guid>
      <description>Holy cow, this is my 100th post. “Insert epic sentence”
Depending on how much time you follow my blog or Different Pixel activity you may know that we have an internal Editor called Sapphire
Past
It was developed over a year ago with the intent of being a “All in one” 2D game editor for our games, built on XNA. It started out pretty well and I’m very happy with the outcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates about Different Pixel and Sapphire</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</guid>
      <description>Like some of you already know I’m currently out of job, the company where I worked like many out there closed due to, I don’t know, financial issues, bad management, who knows. Even worse the news got out just before Christmas and it was not the holidays I intended to have. Times have been hard, since the last pay check I got was in November.
I worked there since 2006, almost 4 years, I joined the team back then in the hopes of joining something in the games industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt and Sapphire Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</guid>
      <description>Lately all my free time has been spent adding new features to Basalt and developing Sapphire.
Some months ago, I started building Sapphire, a 2D editor for helping me creating to create my maps. Unfortunately I made a bad choice and decided to integrate XNA with Windows Forms, although I managed to do it it was a real pain to add something simple and eventually I dropped it.
Here’s a screenshot of the previous alpha version:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xna 2d Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</guid>
      <description>Lately whenever I’m off work and I have the time I’ve been working on a 2d Engine in XNA. We named it Basalt.
Cool hum? lol
I have almost everything done, since sprites, to sprite animations, scenes, layers, resolution independent engine, game state and a lot of other cool things.
On a recent post I’ve showed a 4 split screen prototype, that was made in Basalt.
Also I’ve been working, even though on a slower pace on Shappire, the editor and a sprite sheet editor, for the animations etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
