<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sapphire on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/sapphire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sapphire on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 12:40:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/sapphire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time for some new tools and editor</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</guid>
      <description>Holy cow, this is my 100th post. “Insert epic sentence”
Depending on how much time you follow my blog or Different Pixel activity you may know that we have an internal Editor called Sapphire
Past
It was developed over a year ago with the intent of being a “All in one” 2D game editor for our games, built on XNA. It started out pretty well and I’m very happy with the outcome.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Holy cow, this is my 100th post. “Insert epic sentence”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Depending on how much time you follow my blog or <a href="http://www.differentpixel.com">Different Pixel</a> activity you may know that we have an internal Editor called Sapphire</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire1-300x193.jpg" alt=""  title="sapphire"  />
</a></p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D33185iWTQU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p><strong>Past</strong><br>
It was developed over a year ago with the intent of being a “All in one” 2D game editor for our games, built on XNA. It started out pretty well and I’m very happy with the outcome. It served it’s purpose. The problem now is, most of the stuff we need, apart from the generic sprites positioning, rotation etc, are very specific stuff to the game/project in hands.</p>
<p><strong>Considerations</strong></p>
<p>I now find myself in the need of a Cut-scene editor, it will need the obvious drag-drop, open image etc, but the rest is specific to animation.</p>
<p>How about a generic editor with plug-ins?</p>
<p>Grabbing the current editor and making another working mode that cooperates well in the existent ecosystem is hard work. I don’t have as much time as I would like. It takes too much work and effort and building for specific case takes much lesser time. Since the tools are for internal use only I don’t need to have a all in one friendly editor. Just something that I and Rita can use and that she can quickly learn.</p>
<p>So here I’m not using the “correct road” but the “I need this stuff working” solution.</p>
<p>I decided to make a reusable empty framework with basic handling of common stuff and having an “open canvas” for the rest.</p>
<p><strong>Framework</strong></p>
<p>After some research I decided to use wxWidgets. I’ve used it in the past and it’s a major headache for some stuff, but it’s not an unfamiliar ground for me and I know first hand you can embed DirectX and OpenGL windows there pretty easily. Being cross-platform is a bonus, I intend to focus on Windows only but we never know what lies ahead the road.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates about Different Pixel and Sapphire</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</guid>
      <description>Like some of you already know I’m currently out of job, the company where I worked like many out there closed due to, I don’t know, financial issues, bad management, who knows. Even worse the news got out just before Christmas and it was not the holidays I intended to have. Times have been hard, since the last pay check I got was in November.
I worked there since 2006, almost 4 years, I joined the team back then in the hopes of joining something in the games industry.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like some of you already know I’m currently out of job, the company where I worked like many out there closed due to, I don’t know, financial issues, bad management, who knows. Even worse the news got out just before Christmas and it was not the holidays I intended to have. Times have been hard, since the last pay check I got was in November.</p>
<p>I worked there since 2006, almost 4 years, I joined the team back then in the hopes of joining something in the games industry. It was funny, built a couple of games, made part of big projects, learned much, learned that even more is to be learned. One year after I started making small prototype games on my free times as a joke and websites now and then for a couple of extra bucks.</p>
<p>Around August 2006 I approached <a href="http://www.twitter.com/_m0r3n4">Rita Silva</a> with an idea of building a small creative company. I knew her work, she’s very talented, check her <a href="http://www.rita-silva.com">blog</a> and a person like her creating all the looks and stuff for my projects would be a great help.</p>
<p>After a few weeks we came up with the name Different Pixel and registered in on October 10th. Made our first layout and we started selling hosting packages, we didn’t get many clients but some of them are still with us and are pleased.</p>
<p>Due to our full-time job things were always kind of slow on Different Pixel evolution, we couldn’t accept many jobs due to time restrictions.</p>
<p>Now and without jobs we decided to try and take this small project to higher grounds, we are no longer inexperienced and without background. We currently are working on two small games, but our main focus is still web development, since we have to pay bills =P</p>
<p>I’m not going to reveal much of the games now, this is just a small experience to see how the public reacts, if positive we can move to bigger projects.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire1-300x193.jpg" alt=""  title="sapphire"  />
</a></p>
<p>Also I’ve been working like crazy on the past days on our internal xna map editor Sapphire. The idea is that you can use it with your own engine. Many features are done and much more are on the works.</p>
<p>Here’s a video showing an alpha version. Keep in mind that this is a work in progress.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GexS0y9Y2kM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I’ll be posting an update soon and possibly a beta to the public, the idea is to sell at a low price.</p>
<p>Stay tuned on our <a href="http://www.differentpixel.com">website</a>, <a href="http://www.twitter.com/DifferentPixel">Twitter </a>or <a href="http://www.facebook.com/DifferentPixel">Facebook </a>for updates, we promise lot’s of news soon.</p>
<p>Wish us luck!!</p>
<p>HAPPY NEW YEAR to everyone 😀</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt and Sapphire Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</guid>
      <description>Lately all my free time has been spent adding new features to Basalt and developing Sapphire.
Some months ago, I started building Sapphire, a 2D editor for helping me creating to create my maps. Unfortunately I made a bad choice and decided to integrate XNA with Windows Forms, although I managed to do it it was a real pain to add something simple and eventually I dropped it.
Here’s a screenshot of the previous alpha version:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately all my free time has been spent adding new features to <a href="/tags/basalt/">Basalt</a> and developing <a href="/tags/sapphire/">Sapphire</a>.</p>
<p>Some months ago, I started building Sapphire, a 2D editor for helping me creating to create my maps. Unfortunately I made a bad choice and decided to integrate XNA with Windows Forms, although I managed to do it it was a real pain to add something simple and eventually I dropped it.</p>
<p>Here’s a screenshot of the previous alpha version:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/Sapphire-Level-Editor.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/Sapphire-Level-Editor-150x150.jpg" alt="Sapphire Level Editor"  title="Sapphire Level Editor"  />
</a></p>
<p>I kept working on the engine itself and just making small prototypes for testing it. Finally 2 weeks ago I decided to start from scratch and just use xna to build it. Not much is done but I have little time after work to develop. Anyway I’m happy since I already have textures import, basic object positioning, scaling and a Layer System.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/sapphire-150x150.jpg" alt="sapphire"  title="sapphire"  />
</a></p>
<p>This is an early stage of the new editor, it’s from last week.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D33185iWTQU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>When I have some cool stuff I’ll update a new video.</p>
<p>On the engine side, today I decided to add a Console component to the engine, much like Source Engine and Quake consoles, to input commands, here’s the result:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZYNBfdu5UqM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Hopefully by the beginning of next year I’ll have a beta version that I can release to the public for testing. I intend to launch a free and a payed version of the engine+ editor. My only dout is if I trim down some functions or just release it as free for non-commercial usage only.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xna 2d Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</guid>
      <description>Lately whenever I’m off work and I have the time I’ve been working on a 2d Engine in XNA. We named it Basalt.
Cool hum? lol
I have almost everything done, since sprites, to sprite animations, scenes, layers, resolution independent engine, game state and a lot of other cool things.
On a recent post I’ve showed a 4 split screen prototype, that was made in Basalt.
Also I’ve been working, even though on a slower pace on Shappire, the editor and a sprite sheet editor, for the animations etc.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately whenever I’m off work and I have the time I’ve been working on a 2d Engine in XNA. We named it Basalt.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/basalt.gif"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/basalt-300x221.gif" alt="basalt"  title="basalt"  />
</a></p>
<p>Cool hum? lol</p>
<p>I have almost everything done, since sprites, to sprite animations, scenes, layers, resolution independent engine, game state and a lot of other cool things.</p>
<p>On a recent post I’ve showed a <a href="/2009/08/pugna-prototype/">4 split screen prototype</a>, that was made in Basalt.</p>
<p>Also I’ve been working, even though on a slower pace on Shappire, the editor and a sprite sheet editor, for the animations etc.</p>
<p>I should have something cool to show very soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
