<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Competition on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/game-competition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Competition on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:02:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/game-competition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Made a small game for Ludum Dare 42</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</guid>
      <description>Hey,
It’s been ages since my last post, feel like things keep getting in the way, also not much exciting stuff lately.
But decided to take a break from my current project to participate in Ludum Dare 42, it’s been years since the last time, also I liked the theme “Running out of Space” so I decided to hack something. To try and get out of my comfort zone I made my first game in Unity, so that was a fun experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Competition</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/09/game-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/09/game-competition/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I decided to launch a new website with a 48h Game Competition.
We are now 2 days away from the Compo#1. This is for every indie game developer wannabe =)
[Edit]
The first competition is now over. Check the results here
One of the games made in the competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DBP deadline is over, maybe next year.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/dbp-deadline-is-over-maybe-next-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 15:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/dbp-deadline-is-over-maybe-next-year/</guid>
      <description>Dream Build Play submission deadline is over. Unfortunatly I didn’t had the time to put my prototype working. Maybe next year. I always had the impression I would finish it on time cause the main goal was always IGF.
Meanwhile I’ve been busy making the arrangements for The Indie Bay 48 hour game development competition.
The idea is for every entrant to make a game in 48 hours using a given theme or topic.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
