<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xbox One on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/xbox-one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xbox One on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:29:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/xbox-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make your own QoD Xbox One controller</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/make-your-own-qod-xbox-one-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/make-your-own-qod-xbox-one-controller/</guid>
      <description>A lot of you asked me how they could have their Xbox One controller to look like this
So today I’m sharing the template that you can use to print your own controller 😀
Start by downloading this image: (Right click, open in new tab, Hi-res download)
For my own controller I used a website called decalGirl, but use whatever similar service you prefer or a local store if you have it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available on Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/</guid>
      <description>It’s alive!!!!
Quest of Dungeons finally landed on the Xbox One, and it’s available to buy right NOW!!
Xbox Store link: https://store.xbox.com/en-US/Xbox-One/Games/Quest-of-Dungeons/c5fc3166-ea13-4a23-becb-9e52ed638652</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons coming to Xbox One on September 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 18:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone!
You know that thing you’ve been asking me these past few weeks? I finally have a release day.
I’m very pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Xbox One on September 4th via the ID@Xbox self-publishing program.
After months of development I’m very excited to finally be able say that it will be available on your console on that day.
Quest of Dungeons is a turn based roguelike game, featuring that good old 16-bit art style we grew up with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about the new stuff in Quest of Dungeons for Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been talking about some of the new stuff here and then, but it’s time to show the Xbox version in more detail. A lot of the UI was remade to allow proper gamepad support, several bugs and tweaks were made, and even new features. Lets take a closer look.
In game First of all, here’s how it looks in game, a very minimalist UI if I might say so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Necrodancer is joining</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 11:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/</guid>
      <description>Hi!
I’ve been keeping this one a secret, but there’s going to a be a new class, a Necrodancer.
Yes you guessed it, it’s an homage to Cadence from the awesome game Crypt of the Necrodancer, you should buy it btw!
I’ve been thinking about adding a new class for some time but never quite found anything interesting, each character, in my mind has it’s own personality and charisma and I was having a hard time finding any other interesting class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons GDC 2015 Trailer for the Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/03/quest-of-dungeons-gdc-2015-trailer-for-the-xbox-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 10:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/03/quest-of-dungeons-gdc-2015-trailer-for-the-xbox-one/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, just a small update. GDC 2015 is happening right now and last night a trailer was released for Quest of Dungeons running on the Xbox One.
I made all new footage, running at 1080p in 60FPS for this new trailer, but kept more or less the structure of the original one since I think it reflects well what the game is all about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD XO devlog 3</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 18:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/</guid>
      <description>Last time we talked I was porting the engine to run on the actual Xbox One hardware, since them I managed to port the whole engine, it’s now running (not 100% stable), sound, rending, and input, all working. Since that part is a bit better now I decided to focus some time on new content, such as localization, the new dungeons and stuff that still doesn’t properly work with a controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD XO devlog 2</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been tweaking a lot of the gameplay to be suitable to use with a game controller and I’m starting to like the way it’s headed, it’s much more streamlined, faster and easy to use than the first attempt I made, some beta testing with a group of people helped with that.
Last week I started porting the engine to DirectX, yeah it’s that fun moment where nothing works, crashes everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD XO devlog 1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 18:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been doing a lot of menus and gamepad specifics related work lately.
My first step has been to make sure all menus are easy to use with a Xbox One controller, and while most of the menus in the main screen are usable, inside the game they are not.
Everything was made with mouse in mind at first so I decided to remake all of them again in a different way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-xbox-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 10:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-xbox-one/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Xbox One.
The game was released for the first time on Steam in March 25th and the response has been super positive so I’m excited to bring QoD to new players in a “home console”. I’ll be handling the port myself, because that’s what a one man team means 🙂 I will keep you in the loop to what’s happening in the backstage so keep tuned…</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
