<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Quest of Dungeons on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/quest-of-dungeons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quest of Dungeons on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/quest-of-dungeons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 10 years old!</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-10-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-10-years-old/</guid>
      <description>📝 It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years It&amp;rsquo;s around 11 a.m. as start to type this. 10 years ago at this hour, I was at my day job, trying to focus and not be distracted by the fact that later that day, at around 18h, Quest of Dungeons was being released on Steam and iOS. For the first time, players around the world could try it. I was quite anxious about this; it had been a few years in the making, mostly nights and weekends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="-its-been-10-years">📝 It&rsquo;s been 10 years</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s around 11 a.m. as start to type this. 10 years ago at this hour, I was at my day job, trying to focus and not be distracted by the fact that later that day, at around 18h, <a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a> was being released on Steam and iOS. For the first time, players around the world could try it. I was quite anxious about this; it had been a few years in the making, <a href="/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/">mostly nights and weekends</a>. I had little idea of what to expect, but being on Steam was simultaneously exciting and terrifying. What if people hated it?</p>
<p>What follows for the rest of the post, is a brain dump of the timeline of some of the most crucial events of this silly little project for anyone who is curious.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/pixel_logo_v1_4x.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons characters"  />
</p>
<h1 id="-2011-2013">🤯 2011-2013</h1>
<p>✔️ Failing can help</p>
<p>Before the game launched, I had a few years of terrible prototypes, cancelled projects, and other unexpected life events. One day, though, all those mistakes fell into place, and QoD was born—a flow of ideas came to my mind, after seeing a bunch of stuff failed in front of me, but that maybe I could make them work. I knew what I wanted to avoid now and what I things I would like to experiment with. Within this time I also made a simple iOS game called <a href="/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/">Puwang</a>, a gamejam compo, where most of the goal was to make a quick game and hopefully make $100 that year to cover the iOS developer account expenses. For QoD I wanted to make a small game that I could play on my phone during commute, and that&rsquo;s why it started as a mobile-only game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_characters.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons characters"  />
</p>
<p>⌨️ Expanding</p>
<p>During the time I was the only person to ever played it, I found myself enjoying it on a bigger screen/tablet, and after giving it a 2-3 friends to test and having confirmation, I thought it would be good to launch a desktop version along the iPhone/iPad versions, Windows and Mac.
This added some development time, but also allowed me to expand the game a bit more, the mobile version was virtually identical to desktop/tabled, but they shared a bigger UI, more suited for Mouse and the higher resolutions.
This turned out to be one of the best decisions, as the desktop version is foundation for everything after. At this point I was already <a href="/tags/basalt/">rolling my own engine</a> for prior games on mobile and desktop, so most of the development was indeed for game stuff, and not engine. While I&rsquo;ve made the mistake often of &ldquo;build the engine instead of game&rdquo;, here the engine was built around the game, that&rsquo;s how it should be.</p>
<h1 id="20140325---steam-and-ios-launch">2014/03/25 - Steam and iOS launch</h1>
<p>I had tried to bring games to Steam before but with no success. The focus was on Mobile, with Desktop in mind, but where to sell it? Before Steam I was able to get confirmation for the new Humble Store, but Steam was still on my mind. In the past I had higher hopes for my first game <a href="/tags/vizati/">Vizati</a>, looked more polished, so QoD didn&rsquo;t seemed to have a chance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Screenshot-2022-11-01-at-19.38.50.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>But I decided to make a trailer and launch a GL page, and imagine my surprise when QoD was approved on Steam Greenlight within a week or so. Just look at my dumb face here that I just digged from some old Tweets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/david_amador_celebrating_qod_greenlight_2014-01-24_22.38.07.jpg" alt="David celebrating QoD approval on Steam Greenlight"  />
</p>
<p>With the trailer out, people seemed to enjoyed what they saw, I also thought I was near completing the game, there&rsquo;s always something right? So I pretty much crunched the entire rest of time between my day job and finishing the game.</p>
<p>Finally on March 25th it was out, everyone could play it. Since the game was only releasing around 18h on Steam, I went to my day job that day, and only took the next day off for checking &amp; fixing bugs etc.</p>
<p>Initially all I was getting was a flow of emails with some bugs and suggestions, but overall people seemed to like it, which was a relief. There was still tons of stuff to fix, but slowly, and for the next few weeks went through issues and suggestions. On the mobile side of things things were smoother, that version was the older one, had more testing, also less hardware configurations. I recall before launch, a conversation with some coworkers, that making it paid on mobile was probably a mistake, but I don&rsquo;t know how to design games around F2P/Ads, so I made it paid.  But, thankfully, even being a paid game, at $1.99, people were happy with what they were getting.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_tablet_iphone_desktop.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Android"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20140530---linux">2014/05/30 - Linux</h1>
<p>This one was something that I had in the back on my mind for a while, theoretically my engine could be ported to Linux, but I was scared of having too many versions at launch, handing those 4 SKUs was already a handful, so this was left for later. This actually ended up being a factor in Humble Bundle contacting me to participate in one of their bundles, back then having a game on all 3 platforms was a must.
Technically speaking it wasn&rsquo;t extremely complicated, by this time the engine was already relatively split in ways that it was easy to integrate new OS, it was just a matter of implementation.
Also, now that Steam Deck is a thing, it just worked out of the box.</p>
<h1 id="20140826---android">2014/08/26 - Android</h1>
<p>With Desktops and iOS versions being well received I started getting requests for an Android version, I had never worked on this platform, but with most of the know bugs fixed, I bought a cheap Android phone and I moved into porting the game to this platform, you can read more about that <a href="/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/">here</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_android_2014-05-29_00.05.50.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Android"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2014---ouya-cancelled">2014 - OUYA (cancelled)</h1>
<p>The hot thing around the time was OUYA, games like TowerFall were born there, so since I had an Android version I started to work on that, because it would be the closest to a traditional console that I thought I could put this game on. I started working on it, but once Microsoft accepted my pitch for the Xbox One (see below), I placed this in low priority. Between the time it took me to develop the Xbox One version, OUYA had it downfall, and by that time I just cancelled it.</p>
<h1 id="201509---xbox-one">2015/09 - Xbox One</h1>
<p>In the summer of 2014, after the launch of all those versions, relatively successfully, I started talking with ID@Xbox with the possibility of bringing QoD to Xbox One. There were a couple months of paperwork and mostly the conversation about &ldquo;this is a mouse game, how will it work on consoles?&rdquo;, which was when I started seeing that all the UI needed to be remade, and even some gameplay.</p>
<p>There are several posts, <a href="/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/">here</a>, <a href="/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/">here</a>, <a href="/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/">here</a>, <a href="/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/">here</a> and <a href="/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/">here</a>  detailing what went into to that process, but after around 1 year the game was finally released, and all the work put into reworking the game to controller friendly interface and gameplay paid off, it was <a href="/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/">positively received</a>. I also took the opportunity to double the content available, and also add an <a href="/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/">extra character</a>. I&rsquo;m sure it was this combination of an almost remade version with increased content that led to it&rsquo;s positive feedback. I&rsquo;m really happy I decided to take all those months to remake it, it was daunting at first, I&rsquo;ll tell you that, but I&rsquo;m glad I did it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_xbox_one_launch.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Xbox One launch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20160929---wii-u-and-nintendo-3ds">2016/09/29 - Wii U and Nintendo 3DS</h1>
<p>Around 2015 summer, before Xbox One release, and if I recall correctly, during Gamescom in Germany, I started talking with Nintendo about bringing the game to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U.</p>
<p>This was when Nintendo was a bit more restrictive in terms of third party developers, and I was fully expecting, that me, a solo developer, would not make the cut, and it took a lot of months and patience to finally be able to show the game to someone and get accepted as an official Nintendo developer.</p>
<p>At first my goal was to make Wii U port first because it would be similar to Xbox One, with some additional features for the GamePad. Nintendo 3DS would come later, it would take more work due to it&rsquo;s specifics.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, or fortunately (depending how you see it), I bricked my Wii U devKit after a couple months of work, when the game was in a good state already but before 100% finished. During the time I waited for repairs I started the Nintendo 3DS version.</p>
<p>I knew would take a LOT more work, from performance, to completely different UI for dual screen, hybrid of touch + buttons. But when the Wii U devKit arrived, I decided to launch them side-by-side, I talked with Nintendo about a cross-buy possibility, and once they gave the ok that was the goal.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_new_inventory.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons StreetPass"  />
</p>
<p>The Nintendo 3DS version was one of the most complicated ones to pull off. This was also the first time that working on my own engine was the only thing making it possible. A lot of people were suggesting me to use Unity, and I had would have saved time in porting, which can be true, but Unity didn&rsquo;t supported 3DS, so it would never have happened if not for my custom framework.</p>
<p>This is hands down my favourite version, there is no other like it, mostly because of the nature of the device.</p>
<p>It was so fun to work with that I found myself <a href="/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/">adding features</a> just because I wanted to test them, like the StreetPass, where you can get ghosts from other players you pass on the street. Nintendo had a really neat device here.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_qod_streetpass.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons StreetPass"  />
</p>
<p>There was some trouble having both versions on the same day, it&rsquo;s a lot of coordination required between me, Nintendo America and Europe teams, 4 different SKUs (3DS NA+EU, Wii U NA+EU), but in the end we made it.</p>
<p>Like I suspected during my own tests, on the 3DS it was the ideal portable version, it&rsquo;s a game that suits shorts sessions on the go.</p>
<p>This was also the first time I worked with a publisher for this game, for Japan, the game was published by Flyhigh Works, they took it to Tokyo Game Show, localized to JP, and were crucial in shaping up the 3DS version into what it is. I do recall many sessions where my stubbornness almost caused some bad decisions in the game, but they were really cool in guiding me to make the best of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_wiiu_3ds.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Wii U and Nintendo 3DS"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20170120---playstation-4-and-the-vita-version-that-never-was">2017/01/20 - PlayStation 4 and the Vita version that never was.</h1>
<p>I love my PlayStation 4, in fact it&rsquo;s the console I have more physical games for.</p>
<p>So it was with great excitement that after a Skype call with my PlayStation rep I had the greenlight to get the game there. This started around the time of Nintendo too, but sadly, and at first I wanted PS4 + Vita combo, like Wii U + 3DS, but for a variety of reasons the PlayStation Vita never happened.</p>
<p>This was one of the reasons the PS4 versions was one of the latter ones, I kept hoping I could launch both simultaneously but never happened. Fun fact, this version almost had a physical edition that got cancelled by the publisher at last moment, eventually I even got someone, another publisher, to take care of the PS Vita version, but that also got cancelled later on. So a combination of things that happened that were no one&rsquo;s fault, but also made it a bit hard for me to explain why it wasn&rsquo;t happening. In certain moments it was almost, but it never did happened. It was a bit frustrating that I didn&rsquo;t had clear answers for the players regarding this, but I couldn&rsquo;t, and I tried but failed in the end. Well, that&rsquo;s game development.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons on PlayStation 4"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20170810---nintendo-switch">2017/08/10 - Nintendo Switch</h1>
<p>Around 1 month after I released on Wii U and 3DS, Nintendo announced their new hybrid console, the Nintendo Switch. I immediately started getting questions from players about a port. This complicated promoting the new Nintendo versions while everyone was excited about the upcoming console, saving money for it and the games. By coincidence I had launched both versions right at the end.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t recall exactly when conversations started with Nintendo about this, since it was in hot demand, both for retail and developers, but eventually Nintendo shipped me a devKit and I started porting. It was released first in the Japanese regions, again by Flyhigh Works. But a few weeks later again by me in the rest of the world. This version had the portability of 3DS, and graphics/resolution and UI of the home consoles. This was also the first time I made a demo for the game, which still exists on the eShop.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/quest_of_dungeons_switch.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Nintendo Switch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2019---dreamcast-just-having-fun">2019 - Dreamcast (just having fun)</h1>
<p>In 2019 I got my hands on a Dreamcast I decided to &ldquo;wonder if I can port it there?&rdquo;, it was never really meant for a full release, that would take months of time that I don&rsquo;t have at the moment,
I just posting it here for the record, this was under a week of work, it was fun. Maybe if I reach retirement I&rsquo;ll take some time to finish it. There&rsquo;s a lot of work left in there.</p>
<p>After a while booting the game on an emulator,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_dreamcast_2.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons running on emulator 1"  />
</p>
<p>and then later when I got it booting on a real Dreamcast</p>
 

<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_running_on_dreamcast.mp4" type="video/mp4">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>


<h1 id="20210413---switch-physical-edition">2021/04/13 - Switch Physical Edition</h1>
<p>Like I mentioned before, I tried to get the game in physical format before, and I kept trying for years but it simply wasn&rsquo;t happening. Until 2021, when by random chance, someone recommended me Leoful, and they accepted right away, in fact, from initial contact to production, it was just a couple months, I&rsquo;m really happy I was able to finally get the game on an actual box, it hits differently, as I <a href="/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/">grew playing Nintendo games</a>,  and also feels like a closure to a project that started on a smaller device and made it&rsquo;s way to a real physical game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Physical Edition for Nintendo Switch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2022---">2022 - ??</h1>
<p>Right now the game still exists in several stores (R.I.P. Nintendo 3DS and Wii U), and it&rsquo;s in maintenance mode only. The platforms patched more regularly are the mobile ones, whenever Apple or Android come up with new rules or it breaks on new devices. Windows gives nearly no problems, MacOS breaks things more often, but overall it doesn&rsquo;t give a lot of work, the last time I had to mess with it, was the Linux version to patch stuff for Steam Deck, but it was relatively easy.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_steam_deck.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Steam Deck"  />
</p>
<p>So in the end things worked out, and I want to say a big thank you to everyone who supported this project, I read all the emails, DMs, messages everyone sent over the years, even fanart, you rock.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gKx4R.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<h1 id="some-trivia">Some trivia</h1>
<ul>
<li>The game has 79k of code (all platforms)</li>
<li>The game engine has 130k of code (all platforms)</li>
<li>Over 63800 years of total play time on Steam alone</li>
<li>The game allowing the player to drop items anywhere and being persistent was a side effect of saving the whole world to save instead of recreating it by seed. I just turned it into a feature.</li>
<li>I was only able to finish the game in Hell mode AFTER releasing it, the math seemed to check out, but I wasn&rsquo;t good enough.</li>
<li>The game was called Quest of Dungeons from day 1 of development, as a generic codename, I just grew too attached to it.</li>
<li>There was a pet system that got dropped, taming enemies, but it was dropped in favour of Shaman unique skill of summons.</li>
<li>There was a way for enemies to travel between floors, like Resident Evil added that later on, going between rooms, but it was too aggressive and made the game frustratingly hard.</li>
<li>All the level and combat damage math falls apart around character level 40 or above, but the game was designed below that.</li>
<li>The initial skull sign, which only exists at the very start, was a way to teach the player that death meant restarting, in 2013-14 roguelikes weren&rsquo;t as popular and it was seen as a shock for that to happen (play-testers would email me &ldquo;my save is lost&rdquo;). My goal was that by potentially learning that early on, the player would not get surprised.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you for reading all of this.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_characters_anniversary.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a cool image made by <a href="https://twitter.com/LeonorParra08">Leonor</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons Switch Physical Release</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got several other versions and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.
One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with Leoful, it’s finally happening, and soon too, release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (begin tomorrow, March 26).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch-1024x576.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Nintendo Switch Physical"  />
</a>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got <a href="/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/">several</a> <a href="/2016/09/qod-is-now-available-on-eshop-for-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/">other</a> <a href="/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/">versions</a> and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.</p>
<p>One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with <a href="https://leoful.com/quest-of-dungeons-celebrates-7th-anniversary-with-a-nintendo-switch-physical-release/">Leoful</a>, it’s finally happening, and soon too, <strong>release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (<!-- raw HTML omitted -->begin tomorrow, March 26<!-- raw HTML omitted -->).</strong></p>
<p>This is a limited release, and for this special occasion we have a reversible cover, with the front art made by <a href="https://www.spacecoyote.com/">Nina Matsumoto</a>, and the reversible side by <a href="https://www.artstation.com/vascomarianoart">Vasco Mariano</a>, think it looks great and can’t wait for everyone to start receiving it.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Reversible and front cover<!-- raw HTML omitted --><strong><!-- raw HTML omitted -->-F.A.Q.-<!-- raw HTML omitted --></strong></p>
<p><strong>Where can I buy it?</strong><br>
[<em>PLEASE STAND BY FOR LINKS, I’LL LINK AS I HAVE THEM, UPDATE IN PROGRESS</em>]<br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Play Asia:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt">https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->NintendoSoup:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/">https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bazaar-Bazaar:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->XtraLife:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724">https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Agugames:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons</a></p>
<p><em>*Note: not in affiliation with any of the store links listed here, the order they are is random and not an indication of preference of any kind. Make sure to check where it ships from, for shipping costs &amp; possible import taxes etc.</em></p>
<p><strong>Is it region free?</strong><br>
Yes.</p>
<p><strong>Is it a cartridge or a downloadable code inside the box?</strong><br>
A cartridge, also has a reversible cover.</p>
<p><strong>How much does it cost?</strong><br>
Suggested Retail Price: USD24.99 / HKD195 / NTD710 / SGD34 (all prices exclude sales tax)</p>
<p><strong>Any differences between with the digital version?</strong><br>
Both versions contain the same content, if you already own the digital it’s the same game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/shaman_assassin_conversation_switch_cartridge.png" alt=""  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</guid>
      <description>EDIT (09/09/2017):
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.
Hey,
So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.
Super happy to say that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>EDIT (09/09/2017):<br>
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hey,</p>
<p>So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.</p>
<p>Super happy to say that <strong>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</strong>. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away. In <strong>Japan is already releasing next week, August 10</strong>, <a href="http://flyhighworks.heteml.jp/games/">Flyhigh Works</a> is handing publishing in the Japanese territory.</p>
<p>I’ll be taking care of the rest of the world, but for <strong>Europe and America I’m still working on it</strong>, but hopefully it won’t take much more time.</p>
<p>Meanwhile a sneak peek at the new logo and the new main animation made by <a href="https://twitter.com/rephildesign">@rephildesign</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pixel_logo_v1_4x.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/character_animations_1x.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>I already got a couple questions asked via twitter so I’ll try to put here the most frequent ones.</p>
<p>F.A.Q. / tl;dr</p>
<p><strong>-Release date?</strong><br>
In Japan the game will be releasing in August 10. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->NA/EU dev still under way, I’ll update this when there are changes.<!-- raw HTML omitted --> It will be released on September 14 in Europe, America and Australia.</p>
<p><strong>-How much?</strong><br>
Same as the Wii U/Nintendo 3DS, $8.99</p>
<p><strong>-New features?</strong><br>
Yes there are some new things, there’s a new Mansion, so you have a couple more different themes and sprites. Also a new Feats system to track Achievements, there are several other optimizations/tweaks/changes, but those are the main changes.</p>
<p><strong>-Who ported the game?</strong><br>
Port was made in-house. Flyhigh Works is publishing in Japan, Upfall Studios will be doing the publishing on rest of the world.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press)I want to receive news from your studio</strong><br>
You can use the form at the bottom of the website to subscribe to our newsletter, only used for announcements etc, we don’t spam much<br>
<a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact">http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact</a>. Direct email for any other questions or inquires is listed there as well.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press) Press-Kit?</strong><br>
There is one here with screenshots, videos and some info <a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons">http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 3 years old, a small message for the community</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.
Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.
A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/quest_of_dungeons_steam_page_header.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link/status/419147399375118336"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Screenshot-2022-11-01-at-19.38.50.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</p>
<p>I wanted to take this chance to say thank you to everyone who purchased the game, who helped by making Youtube videos, streaming, recommending to friends, and all the support. If I was able to convince anyone to accept the game on their console/platform it was because the players were talking about it, purchasing and saying they cared. So while I may have built the game, without the community this wouldn’t have happen, I couldn’t have done this without you.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gKx4R.gif" alt="Hugs"  />
</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
Many of you have been asking if I’m working on something new, and the answer is yes, but it’s still a bit soon to discuss what it is, I’ll share more details at a later time. But I’m excited (although a bit nervous) to start working on something new after 4 years of dev in the same project.</p>
<p><strong>What about QoD now?</strong><br>
Although I’m moving to new projects that doesn’t mean work on QoD is completely halting. I intend to keep fixing issues with new devices/OS, this is particularly true with mobile devices which rapidly evolve. I don’t have immediate plans for new content (another popular question), but again, might happen if something makes sense to add in order to improve the game.<br>
As of recently a common question is “Quest of Dungeons on Switch when?”, and while I would love to have the game there, especially with Wii U fading out, and because the game fits well on a portable mode, the ultimate decision to have the game there is up to Nintendo. All I can say about this is that I’ll talk with them and will inform you of any changes.</p>
<p>That’s it for now, thank you for reading. As always feel free reach me via twitter, email, etc. Until the next update.<br>
-David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is out now on PlayStation 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 10:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</guid>
      <description>It’s here, it finally happened! Quest of Dungeons is finally out for PlayStation 4 😀
PS4 dashboard showing Question of Dungeons
First of all, here are the links for the respective stores, you can also just search for the game and it should show on PSN Store.
US PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
EU PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
Since I did this in the past, I decided to find a review video on Youtube that goes into detail about the game running on PS4, this should cover all things, so you can decide if this is a game that you might enjoy or not.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s here, it finally happened! <strong>Quest of Dungeons is finally out for PlayStation 4</strong> 😀</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->PS4 dashboard showing Question of Dungeons<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>First of all, here are the links for the respective stores, you can also just search for the game and it should show on PSN Store.</p>
<p><strong>US PSN Store:</strong> <a href="https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001">https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001</a><br>
<strong>EU PSN Store:</strong> <a href="https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001">https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_01.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_01-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_09.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_09-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_05.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_05-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_14.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_14-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Since I did this in the past, I decided to find a review video on Youtube that goes into detail about the game running on PS4, this should cover all things, so you can decide if this is a game that you might enjoy or not.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lAqTpf9Tl5g" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I want to thank everyone for all the support while this was being made, really appreciate that.<br>
As always you can reach me anytime via twitter or email and I’ll get back asap.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about a 4 year game dev cycle</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 12:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</guid>
      <description>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.
For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was Quest of Dungeons, which started development in 2013.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.<br>
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.</p>
<p>For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was <a href="http://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a>, which started development in 2013.</p>
<p><strong>Right now</strong> I still have one more platform to release, on Playstation 4, 17 January 2017, it passed certification, ready to be released, so for the first time in years it feels that my QoD journey is finally completing. I still intend to patch the Android port with all last updates and sure, there will always be patches and things to take care of, but it will be in a whole different way now. Until now it always felt incomplete and a never ending task that extended for months, years.</p>
<p><strong>Working for so much time</strong> on the same project can be incredibly frustrating, especially if working alone, so one thing that I’m proud of myself is that I actually finished it. You wouldn’t believe the amount of times that I said “F** it, is not worth it”. Things went good with the game, in a sense that I was able to put it on a lot of platforms and it was well received for the most part.<br>
I think I was able to find a good “niche” of players that understood what QoD was all about, with all its flaws and good things.</p>
<p>The game was never meant to be released outside of PC, heck, during the first month of development it was a Tablet only game. That led to decisions that I regretted later when porting to consoles, but also allowed me to cut corners and not caring about things that weren’t meant for a PC game early on, thus speeding up development time. I spent a lot of time just rethinking the whole interface for each new platform (except PS4 which is identical to Xbox One) and that is time consuming, not to mention specific console features, on the other hand players do feel like it was hand-crafted for their device, so there’s that. Each new platform was made possible with the previous one, so it’s not something that I can say it was a total mistake.</p>
<p><strong>Technology wise</strong>, I’ve kept using my own tech for all releases, stubbornness perhaps? And that is not without it’s caveats. With engines like Unreal 4, Unity and Gamemaker these days if feels almost ridiculous to consider building your own tech for many, but not for me, not yet anyway. I used other engines in the past, I did release my first 2 games on XNA, and after that I decided that it was time to build my own tech, so I could be more flexible and not caring if an engine is discontinued or not, that was the goal. And on that part it succeeded, the same code runs on all platforms, except for specific render, input, etc. It took work, a lot, and after so many platforms I have a better idea of things that need better abstraction, in fact for the past week I’ve been just cleaning up code for future projects, feels more robust now. But I have a bit of regret of platforms that I ported the engine and possibly will never use it again, like Wii U, maybe even Nintendo 3DS. While the others, now that the work is done I can reuse for future games, it’s possible that I’ll never use for some again, so it was an effort for a one time only, and that is a problem, one that could have been prevented by using an existent engine.<br>
I tried using Unity for 3 weeks, did some tests with GameMaker, and it was a cool experience, knowledge doesn’t hurt right? But haven’t made my mind yet about switching away from my own tech, mostly because I know it well, I can quickly changes things around for each project and mostly because I love working on that part as well, it’s fun, even if it’s just for me. I’ll revisit this if/when I need to switch to a “full 3d” game.</p>
<p><strong>So many platforms!!</strong><br>
It’s a game that’s on a lot of devices now, and there are several reasons to do so, more audience, chance to make more money, get the game more known, etc, brand recognition and proving the studio is capable of delivering. I also made it because I had the chance right now, I don’t know the future, may not be able to pull that again, also it was a chance to establish a relation with Steam, Xbox, Nintendo and Sony. My idea is to keep making games for platforms that each makes sense, but trying to cut down time between each release. It was too sparse now, because of the reasons mentioned above.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing</strong> is still something I suck at, I do have a twitter account where I talk about my games, but also about tons of other stuff, mostly movies and general day things, is that even called marketing? Too late I decided to setup a newsletter list and put it on Upfall Studios website, should have done it earlier, I got 100 people to subscribe in the last year and half, I could have way more in these nearly 7 years as indie dev.<br>
I also created a twitter account for <a href="http://www.twitter.com/UpfallStudios">Upfall Studios</a>, so it’s basically a cleaned up version of my own, just news about the games and launches, a more “professional” account I call it. Taking care of so many social stuff, twitter, facebook, etc is time consuming and doesn’t come to me as naturally as using my personal account, so that is still a problem probably. For the most part I follow devs and not “companies” even when they are indies, so that’s mostly what I like to do, chances are there are more people like me.</p>
<p><strong>Community</strong> (love you guys)<br>
I like responding to people, I don’t mind getting asked questions and I’ve answered to 100% of emails I got, either about the game or gamedev in general. I’ve taken time to meet other developers in person when they wanna ask me questions. Treat others the way you wanna be treated, easy right?<br>
I’ve been extremely luck with the players and community surrounding QoD, they are nice, active in recommending the game to friends and I couldn’t have wished for a better community. Goal is to keep incrementing the amount of course =)<br>
Never lie or go on radio silence regarding customers. There are tons of Early access games that suddenly stop and not even a goodbye post, that’s the worse part, the waiting for months to see if project is alive. They won’t trust you again, even if you switch to a different studio, they won’t forget. So if project fails explain it, if you are delayed on a patch say so. Almost all the time players will understand and be supportive. When I was making the Xbox One and Nintendo ports I had to delay the PC updates for a couple months and players were really supportive, as long as they know why you are late on some promise.</p>
<p><strong>It’s never just “X more months of dev”</strong><br>
NEVER, ever, if you think it’s just 2 more months, odds are that it’s 4 more. We suck at calculating time for the most part (or at least I do), because we conceive the game in your minds and you can see it, mostly complete, but making that happen takes much more time. PC version was delayed, both Xbox and Nintendo ports took much longer than I expected, the PS4 one was shorted, because I counted with worst case scenario but things went well at first try. In my experience completing the game 1-2 months before the release can have a positive effect, especially for a 1 man team. I finished the Xbox One version 2 months before, full approved on certification, and spent that time just trying to promote it, and was able to gather some awareness for the game. I finished the Nintendo versions just 10 days before, and even had to delay the game once, I regret now that I didn’t calculated/handled things better. Lesson learned, let’s see if I don’t make that mistake again.</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong><br>
I made that mistake in the past and I still do, I can’t separate well development time and actual life time, so I end up working too many hours, and it’s addicting.<br>
QoD was made partially at night when I still had a day job, and the last 1 and a half year in full time, but that doesn’t mean I was able to do twice as much work unfortunately.<br>
When you work for someone else you have a schedule, but if you work on your own time, it’s harder. Most people tell me it’s hard to stay focused working, and I have that problem too, but not in a way that I can’t work, but mostly because I blend in leisure time with work, and working from home doesn’t help. It’s easy to get distracted, then you feel guilty and spend a couple more hours working. And while I don’t think I’m super slow, I could be using my time better. That’s something I want to change, I don’t thing strict work schedules work well, but not having clear boundaries doesn’t either. If anyone is managing this well please let me know. Open to suggestions 🙂<br>
It’s easy to find people saying this, but I’ve now experienced it myself, when you have a problem that you can’t solve don’t spend hours on the PC, take a walk, go do something else, the solution will come to mind, seriously, it works very often. You trick your mind into something else and the other problem keeps getting solved in the background.</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
In approximately 3 weeks the PS4 version will be released, I don’t any plans for more ports so I intend to move to a new game, and honestly I’m scared, I don’t have a solid idea yet, been mostly sketching ideas or trying some prototypes, and the thought of deciding “let me spend 1-2 years” in this new game is a bit scary, “can I come up with all the money?”, “will it be good?”.<br>
I wish I had a small cool idea to try for a couple months instead of a bigger one, but as I mentioned before, QoD was also supposed to be a 6 months project that turned out into 4 years so better not force anything. I’m trying not to think of “this is gonna be a cool idea that everyone will like” and instead trying to come up again with something that I would like to play, even if others don’t like it, development flows more naturally like that.<br>
Oh and I want to take 2 weeks of proper vacations after the PS4 release, haven’t had vacations in over two years, thinking of backpacking a couple countries, it’s cheaper and it’s good “mind food”-</p>
<p>Still there? thanks for reading – David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to PlayStation 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/11/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-playstation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 08:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/11/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-playstation-4/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: Release date will be January 17th 2017!
Exciting news, Quest of Dungeons is on it’s way to PlayStation 4!!
It’s actually been in development for some time, and it’s very near completion, so it’s not going to be a huge wait until release hopefully.
The official QoD page on PlayStation went live just now so I decided it was a good time to let you know that this is happening, since I’ve been getting questions about a PS4 version for some time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>EDIT: Release date will be January 17th 2017!</strong></p>
<p>Exciting news, Quest of Dungeons is on it’s way to PlayStation 4!!</p>
<p>It’s actually been in development for some time, and it’s very near completion, so it’s not going to be a huge wait until release hopefully.</p>
<p>The official QoD page on PlayStation went live just now so I decided it was a good time to let you know that this is happening, since I’ve been getting questions about a PS4 version for some time.</p>
<p>I’ll be submitting the game to PlayStation certification very soon, I’ll keep you updated so keep tuned 🙂</p>
<p>PlayStation official page: <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200809032128/https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons-ps4/">https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons-ps4/</a></p>
<p>Trailer:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xr6y6g4tE0Q" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p><em><strong>Qod Shirt</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-03-21.24.08.jpg" alt=""  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons also coming to Nintendo 3DS on September 29</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-on-september-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 09:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-on-september-29/</guid>
      <description>I have great news.
Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo 3DS on September 29.
A couple weeks ago I announced that QoD was being released for Wii U on September 29 but I didn’t had a specific release date for the Nintendo 3DS version.
I spent the last few weeks trying to sort all know issues on the Nintendo 3DS version and I’ve been working with Nintendo to see if it can be released at the same time as the Wii U version.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have great news.</p>
<p>Quest of Dungeons is coming to <strong>Nintendo 3DS</strong> on <strong>September 29</strong>.</p>
<p>A couple weeks ago I announced that QoD was being released for <a href="/2016/08/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-wii-u-on-september-29/">Wii U on September 29</a> but I didn’t had a specific release date for the Nintendo 3DS version.</p>
<p>I spent the last few weeks trying to sort all know issues on the Nintendo 3DS version and I’ve been working with Nintendo to see if it can be released at the same time as the Wii U version. So everyone gets it on the same day \o/</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_03.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>Here are some screenshots</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_07.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_07.png" alt=""  />
</a>  <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_06.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_06.png" alt=""  />
</a>  <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_05.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_05.png" alt=""  />
</a>  <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_04.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_04.png" alt=""  />
</a>  <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_03.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_03.png" alt=""  />
</a>  <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_02.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_02.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>And a trailer:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZjCf5Qsvh1c" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="faq">F.A.Q.</h2>
<p><em><strong>-Does it support the “older” Nintendo 3DS model?</strong></em><br>
Yes, game will run on all Nintendo 3DS models.</p>
<p><em><strong>-Does it support StreetPass?</strong></em><br>
Yes, see this <a href="/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/">post (link)</a> for more information about how it works.</p>
<p><em><strong>-How much?</strong></em><br>
Game will be sold at $8.99/€8.99/£7.99. I made the game cross-buy so you get the Wii U version for free if you have the same NNID on both systems.</p>
<p><em><strong>-Does it have stereoscopic 3D?</strong></em><br>
No.</p>
<p><em><strong>-How many blocks does it require on SD Card?</strong></em><br>
Approximately 306 blocks (~39MB). <a href="https://twitter.com/UpfallStudios/status/780795144224305152">(link)</a></p>
<p>That’s all for now. Looking forward to see the game reaching your hands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons coming to Wii U on September 29</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/08/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-wii-u-on-september-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 08:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/08/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-wii-u-on-september-29/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I have some good news,
I just got confirmation of the final release date for Quest of Dungeons on Wii U, it’s coming on September 29, both Europe and America. So we are nearly there, “hype.jpg”.
Quest of Dungeons Wii U
F.A.Q. -Does it have off-TV support?
Yes, you can play with the GamePad only.
-Does it support Wii U Pro Controller?
Yes.
-What does the GamePad screen shows?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey, I have some good news,</p>
<p>I just got confirmation of the final release date for <strong>Quest of Dungeons</strong> on <strong>Wii U</strong>, it’s coming on <strong>September 29</strong>, both Europe and America. So we are nearly there, “hype.jpg”.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/quest_of_dungeons_wiiu.png" alt=""  />
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Quest of Dungeons Wii U<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<h2 id="faq"><strong>F.A.Q.</strong></h2>
<p><em><strong>-Does it have off-TV support?</strong></em><br>
Yes, you can play with the GamePad only.</p>
<p><em><strong>-Does it support Wii U Pro Controller?</strong></em><br>
Yes.</p>
<p><em><strong>-What does the GamePad screen shows?</strong></em><br>
There are 3 different ways you can play the game</p>
<ul>
<li>Off-TV mode: You can play the game just on the GamePad.</li>
<li>TV-Only: In this mode everything is on the TV, just like the PC version, and you can play with either Wii U Pro Controller or GamePad</li>
<li>Mixed: GamePad shows a Minimap and touch Inventory (video below)</li>
</ul>
<p>I think this covers most ways people enjoy using when playing on their Wii U.</p>
<p><em><strong>-How much?</strong></em><br>
Game will be sold at $8.99/€8.99/£7.99. I made the game cross-buy so you get the Nintendo 3DS version for free if you have the same NNID on both systems. See below for Nintendo 3DS version release.</p>
<p>Here are some screenshots</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_01.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_01-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_03.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_03-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_04.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_04-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_05.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_05-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_06.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_06-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_07.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_07-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_08.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_08-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_09.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_09-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_10.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_10-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_11.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_11-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_12.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_12-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_13.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_13-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_14.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/WiiU_Image_14-672x372.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>And a trailer</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l0HGrk1b_UE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="so-what-about-the-nintendo-3ds-version"><strong>So what about the Nintendo 3DS version?</strong></h2>
<p><a href="/2016/09/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-on-september-29/">Nintendo 3DS version will be released on September 29 as well.</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->I still don’t have a locked release date, next time I talk about it, it will be to announce when. Coordinating both versions of the game (on both regions) for a simultaneous release turned out to be a bit trickier than anticipated to the small team (1 person), I’m working on some last minute issues, and I’ll try to release it close as possible to the Wii U version. When I have the final release date I’ll let you know. It will be launched simultaneously on both regions as well.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<h2 id="cross-buy"><strong>Cross-buy</strong></h2>
<p>As I mentioned before, the game will have cross-buy, so if you buy the Wii U version on September 29, when the Nintendo 3DS version gets released you will get it for free if you use the same NNID. So don’t feel shy to buy it, because you won’t have to choose one or another version.</p>
<p>Let me know if you have any questions and spread the word.</p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/UpfallStudios">twitter.com/UpfallStudios</a><br>
<a href="http://twitter.com/DJ_Link">twitter.com/DJ_Link</a><br>
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/UpfallStudios">facebook.com/UpfallStudios</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons for Nintendo 3DS screenshots</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/07/quest-of-dungeons-for-nintendo-3ds-screenshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/07/quest-of-dungeons-for-nintendo-3ds-screenshots/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys, here are some screenshots of Quests of Dungeons for Nintendo 3DS. Hope you like it. Stay tuned for some news soon.
Nintendo 3DS is a trademark of Nintendo. © 2011 Nintendo.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys, here are some screenshots of Quests of Dungeons for Nintendo 3DS. Hope you like it. Stay tuned for some news soon.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_01.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_01.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_02.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_02.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_03.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_03.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_04.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_04.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_05.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_05.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_06.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_06.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_07.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/screen_07.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Nintendo 3DS is a trademark of Nintendo. © 2011 Nintendo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD 3DS/Wii U port devlog 1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 08:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>So how are the Nintendo ports coming along?
It’s been sometime since I announced Quest of Dungeons for 3DS and Wii U, so it’s time to talk about what’s been happening in the “backstage”.
I’m working on both versions at the same time, potentially for a simultaneous release. But this adds some extra challenges since both are very different and well, I’m juggling between two ports on my own.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>So how are the Nintendo ports coming along?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s been sometime since I announced Quest of Dungeons <a href="/2016/02/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/"> for 3DS and Wii U</a>, so it’s time to talk about what’s been happening in the “backstage”.</p>
<p>I’m working on both versions at the same time, potentially for a simultaneous release. But this adds some extra challenges since both are very different and well, I’m juggling between two ports on my own.</p>
<p>From a technical point of view, both are already up and running, graphics, sound, input, all of that is working (as far as I tested anyway. bugs yikes).</p>
<p>I had to greatly optimize some portions of the code for the 3DS version, because I want to try to target 60FPS, let’s see if I can accomplish that.</p>
<p>Wii U is obviously a more powerful machine so the pre-existing game code from the Xbox version, after I ported it to the Wii U, just ran.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So if the game is running, what is left?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’m doing specific features for both versions, and that takes time. Both consoles have a second touch screen for example, so I had to come up with a feasible way to use them.</p>
<p><strong>Wii U</strong></p>
<p>On Wii U you can play the traditional way, TV, but I also added off-tv support, so you can play just on the GamePad screen. I have Pro Controller support and another way you can play is a mix between TV and gamepad screen, where you can use a touch based inventory, map, etc to manage things.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>You can even play with the Pro Controller, and watch the game on the gamepad screen, as a tiny TV. I spent the last few weeks adding these changes which I hope will prove useful for players.</p>
<p><strong>Bottom line is:</strong> Yes, you can play only with buttons, like a “regular” game, but if you want, there is some gamepad use, but it’s optional.</p>
<p><strong>Nintendo 3DS</strong></p>
<p>The 3DS version is proving to be the most challenging one, first there were some technical issues I had to overcome, now is trying to fit all content in both those screens in a coherent way. If you played the other versions you know there is a fair amount of menus/UI at the user disposal, either to check inventory, character equipment, skills, buffs, quests, stats, etc.</p>
<p><em>UI/Dual Screen</em></p>
<p>I started by doing a 2 screen split-inventory, imagine the Xbox One but kind of split between 2 screens. So the list was on the top screen, and the item description on the bottom one. And that worked.</p>
<p><em>OLD</em></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_old_inventory.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_old_inventory.png" alt="qod_3ds_old_inventory"  />
</a></p>
<p>However I was never 100% happy with it, and I was barely using touch, which despite not being a personal favorite, I know I lot of people like, so I decided to throw all away and redo it differently. In a way that players could either touch items to open description (the second screen on the previous version) and then Eat/Equip/etc, but also that with a button press you can use it too, via dpad and a/b/x/y.</p>
<p>This is posing some challenges since I’m now trying to put everything that was on 2 screens into a single one, but I’ll get there.<br>
This is still WIP but I feel I’m getting near something a bit better.</p>
<p><em>NEW (WIP)</em></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_new_inventory.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_new_inventory.png" alt="qod_3ds_new_inventory"  />
</a></p>
<p><em>StreetPass</em></p>
<p>I never considered using StreetPass, but the other day I woke up with a cool idea. When you StreetPass someone you send and receive ghosts from previous runs to the other user. Here’s how it works, when you die, the game saves your character as it is, stats, equipment, etc. There is later a chance, that in a new game you might encounter yourself, but now you will also send those ghosts to the other players. So when you find ghosts from other users (they will have a icon in-game to make it different) if you defeat them, you’ll get all the loot. Cool right?</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_qod_streetpass.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_qod_streetpass.png" alt="3ds_qod_streetpass"  />
</a></p>
<p>Final reminder, everything discussed here is WIP so it can change.<br>
So still no ETA, but I’m getting closer. And that is it for now. I’ll let you guys know when I have more news.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/02/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 17:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/02/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</guid>
      <description>Nintendo fans rejoice!!!
It’s time to reveal what I’ve been up to lately, I’ve been very cryptic on Twitter about what I was actually doing but it was for a good cause, because Quest of Dungeons is making it’s way on to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U.
Development started a couple months ago, so I still don’t have an ETA, but from now on I can be less vague to what I’m really doing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nintendo fans rejoice!!!</p>
<p>It’s time to reveal what I’ve been up to lately, I’ve been very cryptic on Twitter about what I was actually doing but it was for a good cause, because Quest of Dungeons is making it’s way on to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U.<br>
Development started a couple months ago, so I still don’t have an ETA, but from now on I can be less vague to what I’m really doing.</p>
<p>I’ll leave you with 2 images of the game/devices. Take all of that as W.I.P. There is much to be done so everything is still subject to change.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/quest_of_dungeons_3ds-1.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/quest_of_dungeons_3ds.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Quest of Dungeons Nintendo 3DS<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/quest_of_dungeons_wiiu.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/quest_of_dungeons_wiiu.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Quest of Dungeons Wii U<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>Don’t forget to share the news with your frinds, and for more up-to date info twitter is the place to <a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link">follow me</a>.</p>
<p>Nintendo 3DS and Wii U are trademarks of Nintendo. © 2012 Nintendo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>year review log 2015</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/12/year-review-log-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/12/year-review-log-2015/</guid>
      <description>Can’t believe it’s almost new year again.
It became a habit of mine to to hit pause for a couple minutes, look back, write about it and think about what’s next, this helps me to sort things out.
Thank you
I have to start with something, a big Thank You for all the people who purchased QoD, everyone who helped spreading the word, the ones who wrote emails, tweeted and help my solo developer work became an even better thing to do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can’t believe it’s almost new year again.<br>
It became a habit of mine to to hit pause for a couple minutes, look back, write about it and think about what’s next, this helps me to sort things out.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you</strong><br>
I have to start with something, a big Thank You for all the people who purchased QoD, everyone who helped spreading the word, the ones who wrote emails, tweeted and help my solo developer work became an even better thing to do. This wouldn’t be possible without everyone who supported me, in one way or another, so even if I do work a lot to make the best possible I can, if no one cared, it wouldn’t be possible, so thank you.</p>
<p><strong>Indie life</strong><br>
I took the jump to full time indie developer this year again, back in March, it wasn’t something I was planning, but was semi forced to do because of some internal restructuring the company was having, so I left. With the <a href="/2014/12/im-a-xbox-one-developer-now-qod-getting-a-port/">Xbox One port of Quest of Dungeons</a> in hands, and falling behind on my personal deadlines, I decided to risk take a couple months and finish it. One one hand I have more freedom, and can work on games, on the other hand there’s the constant fear of “this is the last month” if everything fails and games stop selling. I also decided to start taking care of myself health-wise, by exercising more regularly, and for the most part of the year I did almost everyday a 6-8 KM fast-paced walk right after waking up, overall I fell much better, which helps with the mood and work altogether. The weird thing is that I had to get a gadget in order to feel more motivated, got a fitbit that tracks daily activity, been wearing it for 10 months now, so gamificating health ftw. Personal note, take some proper vacations next year, and by proper I mean, in any place, but disconnected from emails/work and whatever.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/944873_10156260342525364_3728126092064434364_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/944873_10156260342525364_3728126092064434364_n-150x150.jpg" alt="i find your lack of faith distrurbing"  />
</a></p>
<p><strong>QoD on Xbox One</strong><br>
When I left in March, I was already way behind on my original launch plans, because developing for a console is a whole different thing and doing it during nights only was quickly draining my energies.<br>
The following months were mainly devoted to finishing the game, I had to redo a lot of the UI and gameplay to <a href="/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/">accommodate a game controller and other stuff</a>, but eventually on September 4 I <a href="/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/">finally released it</a> and I was genuinely surprised by the overwhelming <a href="/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/">positive feedback</a>, since, at that point the game was out for some time in its PC and Mobile form, but the new additions/changes and the fact that you could play it with a controller for the first time made it more appealing for many people.</p>
<p>Looking back, it took me a full year, from getting the game approved to the actual release. While it’s a lot of time, I also think it was worth it, a lot of the game was tweaked, also for some part I still had my day job, certifications take some time also. In fact the final build was finished around June, I just took those “extra” months to finding bugs/polishing and start to approach journalists/websites.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/branded_key_art_584x800_alt_version.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/branded_key_art_584x800_alt_version.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Xbox One box art"  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11942205_310047909119021_6766836944566229236_o.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11942205_310047909119021_6766836944566229236_o-150x150.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Xbox One"  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/XboxOne_Image_01.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/XboxOne_Image_01.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Xbox One screenshot warrior"  />
</a></p>
<p><strong>GDC/Gamescom</strong></p>
<p>One of the things I’ve always wanted to attend, at least once, was GDC (Game Developers Conference), and this year I was finally able to, to the European one, which despite being expensive, is still less expensive then traveling to the US. And of course since it’s on the same week, I also went to Gamescom, and it was amazing, it’s much bigger then <a href="/2014/10/egx-2014/">EGX</a>, I had no idea. During GDC I was able to meet tons of cool developers, attend some parties (which is usually not my thing) and learn a lot overall.<br>
I was also able to watch a Video Games Live concert for the first time, and I loved it, even got a photo with Tommy Tallarico.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11800512_10155811214270364_267427683833702867_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11800512_10155811214270364_267427683833702867_n-150x150.jpg" alt="Gamescom 2015"  />
</a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11866409_10155826026945364_3741151929249482381_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11866409_10155826026945364_3741151929249482381_n-150x150.jpg" alt="Video Games Live 2015 Koln"  />
</a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11866259_10155826026335364_4527137215117046469_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11866259_10155826026335364_4527137215117046469_n-150x150.jpg" alt="Video Games Live 2015 Koln"  />
</a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11828828_10155803526680364_299957432295330404_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/11828828_10155803526680364_299957432295330404_n-150x150.jpg" alt="GDC Europe 2015"  />
</a></p>
<p><strong>Now &amp; Future(?)</strong></p>
<p>With the release of the XO version, a lot of people are asking what am I doing right now, “Are you on vacation?”, “New game?”. I can definitely say that I’m not on vacation mode right now, I’m already working on something for next year, which is kind of a semi-secret right now, mostly because I’m still unsure if I can pull it off. I started working on a concept for a new game, but something unexpected came up and it’s possible that Quest of Dungeons will get a new port, but now is not the time to talk about it, because at this point is not 100% sure it will, but that’s what I’m working on now.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Back_to_the_Future_time_travel_test_with_Michael_J._Fox_as_Marty_McFly.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Back_to_the_Future_time_travel_test_with_Michael_J._Fox_as_Marty_McFly-150x150.jpg" alt="Back to the Future (1985) Directed by Robert Zemeckis Shown from left: Christopher Lloyd (as Dr. Emmett Brown), Michael J. Fox (as Marty McFly)"  />
</a></p>
<p>On a final note, another thing that comes to mind is that I’ve been blogging way less, I used to post a lot more stuff, especially tutorials of some kind, and I haven’t, so one of the things I wanna change is to write at least one post a month next year. It happened very little this year because I’ve been mostly working with NDA stuff and it’s hard to “Here’s how I fixed this”.</p>
<p>Happy New year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons reviews roundup</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone,
Quest of Dungeons was released on Xbox One exactly a month ago, and the response has been very positive from both players and reviewers, so I decided to list a couple review links here. There are several more, and tons of Youtube videos, so thank you all for helping spreading the word.
9/10 – Xbox Tavern
8.1/10 – Sticky Trigger
8/10 – What’s Your Tag
8/10 – ICMX</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>Quest of Dungeons was <a href="/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/">released on Xbox One</a> exactly a month ago, and the response has been very positive from both players and reviewers, so I decided to list a couple review links here. There are several more, and tons of Youtube videos, so thank you all for helping spreading the word.</p>
<p><strong>9/10</strong> – <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230206192641/http://xboxtavern.com/all-review-list/quest-of-dungeons/">Xbox Tavern</a><br>
<strong>8.1/10</strong> – <a href="http://www.stickytrigger.com/games/quest-of-dungeons-review/">Sticky Trigger</a><br>
<strong>8/10</strong> – <a href="http://whatsyourtagblog.com/2015/09/14/quest-of-dungeons-review/">What’s Your Tag</a><br>
<strong>8/10</strong> – <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20170611171806/http://www.icxm.net/x/quest-of-dungeon-review.html">ICMX</a><br>
<strong>8.5/10</strong> – <a href="http://www.ztgd.com/quest-of-dungeons/review/">ZTGD</a><br>
<strong>4/5</strong> – <a href="http://wegotthiscovered.com/gaming/quest-dungeons-review/">We Got this Covered</a><br>
<strong>9/10</strong> – <a href="http://dkplaysgames.blogspot.co.uk/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-xbox-one-review.html">We Play Games</a><br>
<strong>8/10</strong> – <a href="http://www.entertainment-focus.com/game-review/quest-of-dungeons-review/">Entertainment Focus</a><br>
<strong>Try it</strong> – <a href="http://www.xblafans.com/quest-of-dungeons-review-run-the-procedural-gauntlet-83336.html">XBLA Fans</a><br>
<strong>8.5/10</strong> – <a href="http://thisgengaming.com/2015/09/14/quest-of-dungeons-xbox-one-review/">ThisGenGaming</a><br>
<strong>8.4/10</strong> – <a href="http://moargeek.com/2015/09/07/quest-of-dungeons-review-perfectly-catching-the-roguelike-spirit/">MoarGeek</a><br>
<strong>9/10</strong> – <a href="http://www.readersgambit.com/quest-of-dungeons-review/">Readers Gambit</a></p>
<p>As always, for more news feel free to poke me on <a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link">Twitter</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first ever console game is out</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Hey, it’s been a while.
For the past few months I’ve been working on porting Quest of Dungeons to Xbox One, and I’m super happy that it’s finally out. It was released around a week ago, on September 4.
This took some time but I’m happy of the way the game is played with a gamepad, after a lot of changes to the UI I really feel like it was worth all the effort I put into it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey, it’s been a while.</p>
<p>For the past few months I’ve been working on porting Quest of Dungeons to Xbox One, and I’m super happy that it’s finally out. It was released around a week ago, on <a href="/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/">September 4</a>.</p>
<p>This took some time but I’m happy of the way the game is played with a gamepad, after a lot of changes to the UI I really feel like it was worth all the effort I put into it. If you wanna read more about the new stuff on the XO version you can find the article <a href="/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The players feedback and reviews were very positive as well. Here are some examples:</p>
<p>8/10 – <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20170611171806/http://www.icxm.net/x/quest-of-dungeon-review.html">http://www.icxm.net/x/quest-of-dungeon-review.html</a><br>
8/10 – <a href="http://www.entertainment-focus.com/game-review/quest-of-dungeons-review/">http://www.entertainment-focus.com/game-review/quest-of-dungeons-review/</a><br>
4/5 – <a href="http://wegotthiscovered.com/gaming/quest-dungeons-review/">http://wegotthiscovered.com/gaming/quest-dungeons-review/</a><br>
9/10 – <a href="http://dkplaysgames.blogspot.co.uk/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-xbox-one-review.html">http://dkplaysgames.blogspot.co.uk/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-xbox-one-review.html</a></p>
<p>I also want to thank everyone who emailed and tweeted me, watching everyone having fun with the game warms the hearth 🙂</p>
<p><strong>So what is next?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve been getting that question a lot. “Are you making more games?” “Are you working on something new already?”<br>
QoD has kept me pretty busy until now, so while I have some ideas in my mind I haven’t really started anything new, my ideas may very well not be even good at all, I need to test and prototype to see what I wanna do next. I still need to do a patch to QoD to fix some stuff, that is the priority now, but that should only keep me busy until the end of the month. After that it’s time to jump into something new, which is kind of scary, but exciting at the same time. I have no idea if I can ever make a game that people will like, like they did with QoD, but I’ll do my best.</p>
<p>As always, you can find me on <a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link">twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
