<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in video on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 22:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updates about Different Pixel and Sapphire</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/</guid>
      <description>Like some of you already know I’m currently out of job, the company where I worked like many out there closed due to, I don’t know, financial issues, bad management, who knows. Even worse the news got out just before Christmas and it was not the holidays I intended to have. Times have been hard, since the last pay check I got was in November.
I worked there since 2006, almost 4 years, I joined the team back then in the hopes of joining something in the games industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt and Sapphire Updates</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</guid>
      <description>Lately all my free time has been spent adding new features to Basalt and developing Sapphire.
Some months ago, I started building Sapphire, a 2D editor for helping me creating to create my maps. Unfortunately I made a bad choice and decided to integrate XNA with Windows Forms, although I managed to do it it was a real pain to add something simple and eventually I dropped it.
Here’s a screenshot of the previous alpha version:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an 2D Game Engine in XNA &amp;#8211; Part 1</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/building-an-2d-game-engine-in-xna-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/building-an-2d-game-engine-in-xna-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I decided to starting writing a series of tutorials for building an 2d XNA game engine.
Keep in mind that while the main focus is 2d nothing prevents us from adding the 3d stuff later but for now we will stick to 2D.
It’s not very original but I’ll call this the Bay Engine. If anyone else has a better idea let me know.
Requirements:
You must have some Object Oriented Programming background to full understand what we will do here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA Camera 2d with zoom and rotation</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/xna-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/xna-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</guid>
      <description>07/01/2011 – By popular request updated to XNA 4.0, xna 3.1 code is still there too
One of the things I keep finding is people asking how to do a simple camera 2d in XNA. Today I decided to contribute with my own solution.
Most of the time the solution given is to have a class camera with a Vector2 position and when drawing the sprite batch to subtract the camera position to the sprite position itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt gains a media player</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/basalt-gains-a-media-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 18:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/10/basalt-gains-a-media-player/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve been working on a sort of media player in order to play movies on my 2d engine Basalt made on top of XNA.
By extending my class Object2d I manage to get this pretty cool result. You can even apply shaders to it. Since I extended the class from Object2d I can rotate, scale and set a position to the video besides regular options like play/pause, fullscreen etc. For those who don’t know the video playing is a chunk of the series Naruto Shippuuden</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA Sprite Sheet</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-sprite-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 10:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-sprite-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I decided to take the morning to make a small sprite sheet editor for our Xna engine. This way the artist can easily define the sprite areas and their origin saving in a file that can later on be loaded on the engine.
Not very fancy yet but it gets the job done.
Next step will be making an animator editor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pugna prototype</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/08/pugna-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/08/pugna-prototype/</guid>
      <description>Hello there.
Yes i know I haven’t updated in awhile, I’ve been really busy. So the deadline for Dream Build Play is 5 days from now and up till yesterday I haven’t made anything.
My goal was to have a prototype by now to submit to DBP, but I ain’t got anything. So today I decided to see what I could do from scratch, and not related to the main idea that Rita and I have for the game we should have submitted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Talk: Linus Torvalds On Git</title>
      <link>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/02/tech-talk-linus-torvalds-on-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 16:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://djlink.github.io/web_david-amador.com/2009/02/tech-talk-linus-torvalds-on-git/</guid>
      <description>I recently found that there is a subversion alternative surfacing that is in many ways much better that subversion, it name is Git and it’s a creation of Linus Torvalds.
Here’s a video of him talking about it
https://www.youtube.com/v/4XpnKHJAok8</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
