<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 11:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switching to a new Keyboard, the Glove80</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/03/new-keyboard-glove80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 11:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/03/new-keyboard-glove80/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 8-9 year old Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic keyboard died 🪦 (actually it&amp;rsquo;s been showing signs for a while), so I decided to search the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I just wanted &amp;ldquo;the same one&amp;rdquo;, but they are discontinued, even used ones are expensive, and many didn&amp;rsquo;t had the dongle anymore (btw don&amp;rsquo;t buy this KB without the bundled dongle, comes locked from factory, you can&amp;rsquo;t use a different one, shame on you MS).
I found that some brands will eventually have similar models later this year (but no release date yet) but I needed to start changing now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="why">Why?</h3>
<p>My 8-9 year old Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic keyboard died 🪦 (actually it&rsquo;s been showing signs for a while), so I decided to search the market.</p>
<p>At first I just wanted &ldquo;the same one&rdquo;, but they are discontinued, even used ones are expensive, and many didn&rsquo;t had the dongle anymore (btw don&rsquo;t buy this KB without the bundled dongle, comes locked from factory, you can&rsquo;t use a different one, shame on you MS).
I found that some brands will eventually have similar models later this year (but no release date yet) but I needed to start changing now.</p>
<p>A friend recommended me a Kinesis or the ErgoDox, but for a variety of reasons I ended up going with a Glove80 which I found during my searches, it&rsquo;s an expensive one, but it&rsquo;s split, ortholinear and it has the F1-F10 keys which I think are a nice to have separate.</p>
<p>I anticipate a big learning curve, and there&rsquo;s a possibility I might not even get used to it. I found a bunch of posts of people who gave up and returned them (any of the KBs I mentioned really), so I anticipate friction. I&rsquo;m going to write a log on how things will progress and eventually post it. Regardless of failure or success.</p>
<h3 id="unboxing">Unboxing</h3>
<p>After much debating I decided to order it on February 6th, received it on February 14th, so overall pretty fast shipping + delivery.</p>
<p>I got the Rev2, which now always comes with a carrying case, and this is how it was packed.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 Rev 2 unboxing" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_rev2_unboxing.jpg"></p>
<p>The box is indeed sturdy, and as the welcome note claims, good enough to travel, although it&rsquo;s on the big side so I don&rsquo;t see it as something to be carried around everyday, but for a trip or working elsewhere for a couple days it&rsquo;s very good.</p>
<p>It also came with some spare keycaps on a cloth bag, some tools and rubbers for tenting, and a USB-C (KB side) to USB-A (PC side) cable.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 extras in the case" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_unboxing_extras.jpg"></p>
<h3 id="setup">Setup</h3>
<p>You can setup the keyboard by bluetooth (no dongle) or via USB cable. You only need to connect the left part, and the right side always communicates with the left one wirelessly. However, to charge you need to connect a cable on both, not at the same time but if you want to never care about battery you&rsquo;ll need a USB split cable or 2 of them always plugged in. The left side runs out of battery faster than the right one so that&rsquo;s probably not an issue.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 tenting" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_tenting.jpg"></p>
<p>In terms of tenting there&rsquo;s several feet with some screws you can lower and put higher as needed, but I&rsquo;ve been using it flat. As I mentioned they ship it with some extra rubbers, for stability if needed to raise a lot, I have it on a deskmat and it&rsquo;s super stable, I guess on a desk directly, if you run into issues that could be useful.</p>
<p>Note for Mac users, the best way to just use it out of the box and having all keys work as they are on each key Label is U.S. International - PC as the keyboard layout.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 mac keyboard setting" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_mac_keyboard_setting.png"></p>
<h3 id="day-1">Day 1</h3>
<p>The first thing I noticed it how low profile it is, I love it, so close to the desk, here&rsquo;s the left side near a Nintendo Switch (left).</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 low profile" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_side_profile_vs_nintendo_switch.jpg"></p>
<p>Ok just to be honest here, I just tried it but right now but I&rsquo;m still typing this on my temporary keyboard, I tried the Glove80 a bit and I&rsquo;m now on that &ldquo;OMG I regret this already!&rdquo; stage. The packing is very nice, the keyboard looks great and seems comfortable, but I&rsquo;m switching from ISO to ANSI, algo to split and ortholinear, everything is in a completely different place, I can barely find anything. Out of curiosity I did a <a href="https://monkeytype.com/">https://monkeytype.com/</a>  test and yeah this will take some getting use to, but I&rsquo;m excited for this.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 day one test typing" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_day_one_test_typing.jpg"></p>
<h3 id="day-2">Day 2</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m typing this on the Glove80 now so it might take forever. I&rsquo;ve been practicing a little bit more and I started to average 20 words per minute (with a lot of errors and corrections). So it&rsquo;s still terrible but not as bad as yesterday, that&rsquo;s what I got to focus on.</p>
<p>Some observations already, most of my tests are still just words as I noticed that I need to get used to the ortholinear layout, I have a lot of fails that come from the muscle memory of fingers moving around, which is not as needed here. Also I&rsquo;m messing up all the time the usual shortcuts, CTRL, SHIFT, ALT, they are all now in different places so there&rsquo;s a lot to get used to.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t like much that the &ldquo;WIN&rdquo; key is on the right thumb cluster, so I&rsquo;m taking a note to maybe switch it with the layer key which I guess I&rsquo;ll use way less.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 left and right thumbcluster" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_change_thumbcluster.jpg"></p>
<h3 id="day-4">Day 4</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m only using the keyboard at night but I&rsquo;ve been making progress, do a couple rounds of tests after work, I&rsquo;m more comfortable typing with it, doesn&rsquo;t feel as strange anymore, at least words.</p>
<p>The keyboard is indeed comfortable, not having to move my hands so much, really starting to grow on me. During the day I&rsquo;m using a regular KB and I can feel the wrists pressure. If I fully turn into this keyboard I can see myself not wanting to go back.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s funny that I now know exactly which characters I have more trouble typing, it&rsquo;s especially right hand pinky row (OPL) and left hand CDFV &ldquo;square&rdquo;. But mentally that has helped as I pause a bit, remember myself and do a bit less errors even if I&rsquo;m slower. I&rsquo;ve been trying to force myself not to look to the keyboard but once in a while I&rsquo;ll do a couple tests looking to get my bearings.</p>
<h3 id="day-5">Day 5</h3>
<p>Today I&rsquo;ve reached a 50 WPM speed test with 100%, that was an outliner but I&rsquo;m happy about it.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 5th day speed test" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_type_speed_day_5.png"></p>
<h3 id="day-7">Day 7</h3>
<p>Slowly but steady I&rsquo;m getting better. I found out that I tend to have the right side with a worse angle then the left side, probably bad posture from older keyboards, I guess I probably had the 1-piece keyboard always slightly more to the left, due to the mouse, so I tend to have my left wrist not as relaxed. This might be because of mouse use as well.</p>
<p>Yikes coding just kills your body slowly.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 5th day speed test" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_type_speed_day_7.png"></p>
<h3 id="day-8">Day 8</h3>
<p>The start of a new week, I decided I&rsquo;ll now introduce numbers and special keys like ( ) ; , . etc to my typing practice, it&rsquo;s time to start dealing with that.</p>
<h3 id="day-17">Day 17</h3>
<p>Most of the biggest &ldquo;speed&rdquo; progress was made in the first 2 weeks, now it&rsquo;s mostly being a bit more confident with the fingers, not as many mistakes, not necessarily being faster.
I found out that I can have shortcuts to use the keyboard as a mouse, like having 4 keys to move mouse UP/DOWN/LEFT/RIGHT, this is a godsend, sometimes I just want to move the mouse a little bit and switch back to keyboard, this speeds up things by a lot. I mapped it to holding LAYER key and IJKL for movement.</p>
<h3 id="day-18-to-29">Day 18 to 29</h3>
<p>Slow but steady&hellip;</p>
<p><img alt="progress" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_typing_progress.jpg"></p>
<p>I keep bouncing between using the Glove80 and going back to my keyboard depending on what I need, if I need faster coding sessions or if something that I&rsquo;m more comfortable with going slower.</p>
<h3 id="day-30">Day 30</h3>
<p>I just realized I&rsquo;ve been using it as my main keyboard for the past week or so of work, I&rsquo;m still not as fast, and many of the shortcuts still ilude me a bit, but for the most part I can work ok, it&rsquo;s rare that I have to speed type this past week, so it was the perfect time. Most work has been evaluation, debug and searching/fixing stuff, so I think I&rsquo;ll get there as fast as my old KB eventually.</p>
<p>This change was mostly due to a friend asking me last week how the change was going (he has a Kinesis so was curious), and I said I was feeling bad on doing the full change while I was not as good, due to contract work. And his comment about my speed probably already being good enough and that I should switch made me do it. Thing is, that final stretch can&rsquo;t be done in small bursts.</p>
<h3 id="mapping-tool">Mapping tool</h3>
<p>Glove80 provides a web interface where we can remap every key and layer. It&rsquo;s very intuitive, and how I remapped some of the keys in a layer for using mouse. Once you wrap it up, it exports a file, you just plug in the keyboard left part via USB mode, just drag a file to a storage disk that shows up on the computer, once it&rsquo;s there it ejects automatically, then repeat it for the right side. It&rsquo;s fast and just works. I haven&rsquo;t used this much but I can see myself in the long run wanting to do tweaks as I even talked a bit before.</p>
<p>Most of the keyboard keys are in a good position, even if it feels odd at first, but you can remap everything.</p>
<h3 id="thoughts">Thoughts</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;ll admit that once in a while when I&rsquo;m in a rush I still go back to a regular keyboard, I&rsquo;ve made good progress and I can see the advantages but I have nearly 2 decades of muscle memory on regular keyboards, so it will take some extra time to never have the feeling of requiring to switch back when I need to code faster or in a rush. Shortcuts especially are harder.
But if I keep this up I&rsquo;ll eventually only need it rarely or not at all.</p>
<p>The good things is that when I use it my posture is better.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 on a desk" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_photo_desk_showing_halve_distanced_desk.jpg"></p>
<p>I can have my shoulder blades in a more comfortable position, I feel myself less hunched and curled, my shoulders and wrists appreciate it. It&rsquo;s definitely worth learning how to use one and the cost. Again, coding slowly kills your body, gotta try to delay it as much as possible.</p>
<p>On the bad side I found out Windows bluetooth is so unreliable I had to force my device not to allow power management. Luckily that fixed disconnections with the Glove80 right away. It&rsquo;s possible I would have issues with other stuff (usually I have with bluetooth headphones issues once in a while), but a keyboard failing wasn&rsquo;t something that I could have happening.</p>
<p><img alt="Glove80 Rev 2 unboxing" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/glove80_cherry_blossom.jpg"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m still on the fence on the best place to keep my trackball mouse. Because the keyboard can be much farther apart, if you put the mouse on the right side, it becomes too uncomfortable, which defeats the purpose.
So sometime if I need to use it for longer sessions (like painting software etc) I just put the right part of the keyboard to the middle.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t regret buying this, even if it was the most expensive keyboard I ever got.</p>
<p><img alt="Most expensive keyboard so far" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/the_most_expensive_kb_so_far.jpg"></p>
<p>I would recommend this keyboard as a good one, for sure. However, having never tried any of the other popular ones (Kinesis, Ergodox, etc), I can&rsquo;t know for sure if this one is better or worse, all I can say is that I&rsquo;m happy with it so far.</p>
<p>Let me know if you have any particular questions, be glad to answer, I know this isn&rsquo;t exactly a &ldquo;good review post&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s just a dump of my process to get here.</p>
<hr>
<p>See you in the next post!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cozy Game Moments in Unexpected Places</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/01/cozy-game-moments-in-unexpected-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/01/cozy-game-moments-in-unexpected-places/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a rise in the popularity of cozy games, the ones that are not about just hard challenges, combat or adrenaline, but about comfort and attempt of well-being. Those are great, and it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to see the indie scene doing many interesting things in that department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I always have this on the back on my mind as one of my favourite things, one thing I&amp;rsquo;m usually very interested in, cozy feelings/atmosphere that can be found in unexpected places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a rise in the popularity of cozy games, the ones that are not about just hard challenges, combat or adrenaline, but about comfort and attempt of well-being. Those are great, and it&rsquo;s incredible to see the indie scene doing many interesting things in that department.</p>
<p>But I always have this on the back on my mind as one of my favourite things, one thing I&rsquo;m usually very interested in, cozy feelings/atmosphere that can be found in unexpected places.</p>
<p>They can come in a variety of genres or situations, even if the overall game is not about that. What fascinates me about this is my own taste for &ldquo;comfort movies&rdquo;, when you ask someone what their comfort movie is, it&rsquo;s a wide range of action, horror, comedy, drama, sci-fi and more, it&rsquo;s not always obvious.</p>
<p>So in this post, I just to dump a bit of my thoughts on some of the games that I found interesting.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start by an obvious to understand, and possibly one of my all time favourite ones &hellip;</p>
<h2 id="sanctuaries-of-survival">Sanctuaries of survival</h2>
<p>Resident Evil - Ok read it again but with the title voice, RESIDENT EVIL. Thanks :)</p>
<p>RE games, for those who never played, might seem like a weird pick for &ldquo;cozy&rdquo;, and it is, but let&rsquo;s focus on the first few games here, they are pure suspense and horror games, gore, scares, you die a lot, however, they pull off one of the most relaxing game rooms maps ever made, the Save Rooms. That&rsquo;s why I was mentioning the originals mostly, from Zero, 1, 2 and 3 the save rooms are so damn good.</p>
<p><img alt="Resident Evil 1 Remake Save Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/resident_evil_remake_gamecube_save_room.webp"></p>
<p>These locations as the name implies is where the player can save, but also, they allow you to breathe a little, small pockets of safety, where there are no dangers, you are locked from the monsters and you can manage your inventory.</p>
<p><img alt="Resident Evil 0 Save Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/resident_evil_0_save_room.webp"></p>
<p>On top of that, soothing music plays in the background, seriously, it&rsquo;s near perfect. The feeling is so strong, that the first few times, after you reach them, you don&rsquo;t want to leave, you are immediately attached to them. You can control when you leave, and leave you will, but at your pace, eagerly waiting for the next one. Unless you&rsquo;re out of Ink Ribbons!</p>
<p>Here, I&rsquo;ll save you the trouble of searching the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pZV3UPmXI4">RE Save Room music</a> :)</p>
<h2 id="a-home-away-from-home">A Home Away From Home</h2>
<p>Final Fantasy VII, despite its epic scale and combats, dozens of hours of gameplay and storyline, joy and sadness, offers moments of quiet coziness during the difficult journey around the world.</p>
<p><img alt="Final Fantasy 7 PS1 Cozy Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/final_fantasy_7_cozy_room_3.jpg"></p>
<p>Whenever we are exploring a town, entering other people&rsquo;s houses (classic RPG!), everything has an inviting atmosphere. These spaces, though simple, feel familiar and offer a sense of relaxation.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th><img alt="Final Fantasy 7 PS1 Cozy Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/final_fantasy_7_cozy_room_1.jpg"></th>
          <th><img alt="Final Fantasy 7 PS1 Cozy Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/final_fantasy_7_cozy_room_4.jpg"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>It&rsquo;s the small details, like a carefully placed painting or a comfy-looking bed, that contributes to this feeling of comfort. These moments actually do a lot for the game&rsquo;s personality, especially because a lot of long dialogues take place in these environments, so you don&rsquo;t feel out of place, or with the urge to leave right away. Maybe it&rsquo;s it&rsquo;s painted nature, maybe it&rsquo;s the camera angle, but the Remake couldn&rsquo;t replicate this feeling.</p>
<p><img alt="Final Fantasy 7 PS1 Cozy Room" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/final_fantasy_7_cozy_room_2.jpg"></p>
<h2 id="journeys-into-the-unknown">Journeys into the Unknown</h2>
<p>I only recently played Syberia, all because of Nintendo Switch, I saw the game and felt like it was a good fit. The game has a somewhat slow pace which helps with giving us change to visually absorb the world. I couldn&rsquo;t quite put my finger in it but I was immediately drawn to it, the game can be defined mostly by it&rsquo;s sense of of melancholic beauty and isolation at first. The mechanical town, some of the most eerie scenarios. And yet, the total feeling of comfort really comes after we get to use the train.</p>
<p><img alt="Syberia 1 train" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Syberia-train-winder.jpg"></p>
<p>By becoming Kate Walker primary mode of transport, after many many puzzles, it soon turns not only into a transport but also a home, becoming surprisingly cozy, and the only way to move forward.  The rhythmic melody of the engine, the passing landscapes, and the quiet solitude of the train compartment create a sense of journey and reflection.  These moments allow Kate and the player to process the events, adding warmth to the game&rsquo;s overall atmosphere.</p>
<p><img alt="Syberia 1 train pedestral" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Syberia-train-pedestal.jpg"></p>
<h2 id="a-different-kind-of-cozy">A Different Kind of Cozy</h2>
<p><img alt="Little Nightmares" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/little_nightmares_01.jpg"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a big fan of Little Nightmares (I and II), to me very special games, it ranges from cute to horrific, majority of it&rsquo;s vibes are Ghibli-meets-Nightmare-Before-Christmas aesthetic esque scenarios, giving it a cartoony look that looks secure but it just happens to take place at &ldquo;Silent Hill levels of horror&rdquo;.</p>
<p><img alt="Little Nightmares" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/little_nightmares_02.jpg"></p>
<p>There are elements of coziness, just not in the traditional kind, not even the one that I might say there will be moments where you&rsquo;ll feel relaxed. You&rsquo;re never quite there, but feels like it could.</p>
<p><img alt="Little Nightmares" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/little_nightmares_03.jpg"></p>
<p>Instead, it&rsquo;s tied to the feeling of being small and vulnerable in a large and dangerous world, it&rsquo;s an odd one, the feeling of crawling through vents, hiding under furniture, and finding small pockets of safety create a sense of childlike vulnerability, which can be surprisingly comforting in its own way.</p>
<p><img alt="Little Nightmares" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/little_nightmares_04.webp"></p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a dangerous world that wants to kill you, but empty it has it&rsquo;s charm and calmness.</p>
<hr>
<p>Ok thanks for sticking around, I hope you enjoyed, let me know other games you felt they had cozy moments, atmosphere or other in unexpected places.</p>
<hr>
<p>See you in the next post!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about a 4 year game dev cycle</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 12:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.&lt;br&gt;
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questofdungeons.com&#34;&gt;Quest of Dungeons&lt;/a&gt;, which started development in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.<br>
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.</p>
<p>For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was <a href="http://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a>, which started development in 2013.</p>
<p><strong>Right now</strong> I still have one more platform to release, on Playstation 4, 17 January 2017, it passed certification, ready to be released, so for the first time in years it feels that my QoD journey is finally completing. I still intend to patch the Android port with all last updates and sure, there will always be patches and things to take care of, but it will be in a whole different way now. Until now it always felt incomplete and a never ending task that extended for months, years.</p>
<p><strong>Working for so much time</strong> on the same project can be incredibly frustrating, especially if working alone, so one thing that I’m proud of myself is that I actually finished it. You wouldn’t believe the amount of times that I said “F** it, is not worth it”. Things went good with the game, in a sense that I was able to put it on a lot of platforms and it was well received for the most part.<br>
I think I was able to find a good “niche” of players that understood what QoD was all about, with all its flaws and good things.</p>
<p>The game was never meant to be released outside of PC, heck, during the first month of development it was a Tablet only game. That led to decisions that I regretted later when porting to consoles, but also allowed me to cut corners and not caring about things that weren’t meant for a PC game early on, thus speeding up development time. I spent a lot of time just rethinking the whole interface for each new platform (except PS4 which is identical to Xbox One) and that is time consuming, not to mention specific console features, on the other hand players do feel like it was hand-crafted for their device, so there’s that. Each new platform was made possible with the previous one, so it’s not something that I can say it was a total mistake.</p>
<p><strong>Technology wise</strong>, I’ve kept using my own tech for all releases, stubbornness perhaps? And that is not without it’s caveats. With engines like Unreal 4, Unity and Gamemaker these days if feels almost ridiculous to consider building your own tech for many, but not for me, not yet anyway. I used other engines in the past, I did release my first 2 games on XNA, and after that I decided that it was time to build my own tech, so I could be more flexible and not caring if an engine is discontinued or not, that was the goal. And on that part it succeeded, the same code runs on all platforms, except for specific render, input, etc. It took work, a lot, and after so many platforms I have a better idea of things that need better abstraction, in fact for the past week I’ve been just cleaning up code for future projects, feels more robust now. But I have a bit of regret of platforms that I ported the engine and possibly will never use it again, like Wii U, maybe even Nintendo 3DS. While the others, now that the work is done I can reuse for future games, it’s possible that I’ll never use for some again, so it was an effort for a one time only, and that is a problem, one that could have been prevented by using an existent engine.<br>
I tried using Unity for 3 weeks, did some tests with GameMaker, and it was a cool experience, knowledge doesn’t hurt right? But haven’t made my mind yet about switching away from my own tech, mostly because I know it well, I can quickly changes things around for each project and mostly because I love working on that part as well, it’s fun, even if it’s just for me. I’ll revisit this if/when I need to switch to a “full 3d” game.</p>
<p><strong>So many platforms!!</strong><br>
It’s a game that’s on a lot of devices now, and there are several reasons to do so, more audience, chance to make more money, get the game more known, etc, brand recognition and proving the studio is capable of delivering. I also made it because I had the chance right now, I don’t know the future, may not be able to pull that again, also it was a chance to establish a relation with Steam, Xbox, Nintendo and Sony. My idea is to keep making games for platforms that each makes sense, but trying to cut down time between each release. It was too sparse now, because of the reasons mentioned above.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing</strong> is still something I suck at, I do have a twitter account where I talk about my games, but also about tons of other stuff, mostly movies and general day things, is that even called marketing? Too late I decided to setup a newsletter list and put it on Upfall Studios website, should have done it earlier, I got 100 people to subscribe in the last year and half, I could have way more in these nearly 7 years as indie dev.<br>
I also created a twitter account for <a href="http://www.twitter.com/UpfallStudios">Upfall Studios</a>, so it’s basically a cleaned up version of my own, just news about the games and launches, a more “professional” account I call it. Taking care of so many social stuff, twitter, facebook, etc is time consuming and doesn’t come to me as naturally as using my personal account, so that is still a problem probably. For the most part I follow devs and not “companies” even when they are indies, so that’s mostly what I like to do, chances are there are more people like me.</p>
<p><strong>Community</strong> (love you guys)<br>
I like responding to people, I don’t mind getting asked questions and I’ve answered to 100% of emails I got, either about the game or gamedev in general. I’ve taken time to meet other developers in person when they wanna ask me questions. Treat others the way you wanna be treated, easy right?<br>
I’ve been extremely luck with the players and community surrounding QoD, they are nice, active in recommending the game to friends and I couldn’t have wished for a better community. Goal is to keep incrementing the amount of course =)<br>
Never lie or go on radio silence regarding customers. There are tons of Early access games that suddenly stop and not even a goodbye post, that’s the worse part, the waiting for months to see if project is alive. They won’t trust you again, even if you switch to a different studio, they won’t forget. So if project fails explain it, if you are delayed on a patch say so. Almost all the time players will understand and be supportive. When I was making the Xbox One and Nintendo ports I had to delay the PC updates for a couple months and players were really supportive, as long as they know why you are late on some promise.</p>
<p><strong>It’s never just “X more months of dev”</strong><br>
NEVER, ever, if you think it’s just 2 more months, odds are that it’s 4 more. We suck at calculating time for the most part (or at least I do), because we conceive the game in your minds and you can see it, mostly complete, but making that happen takes much more time. PC version was delayed, both Xbox and Nintendo ports took much longer than I expected, the PS4 one was shorted, because I counted with worst case scenario but things went well at first try. In my experience completing the game 1-2 months before the release can have a positive effect, especially for a 1 man team. I finished the Xbox One version 2 months before, full approved on certification, and spent that time just trying to promote it, and was able to gather some awareness for the game. I finished the Nintendo versions just 10 days before, and even had to delay the game once, I regret now that I didn’t calculated/handled things better. Lesson learned, let’s see if I don’t make that mistake again.</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong><br>
I made that mistake in the past and I still do, I can’t separate well development time and actual life time, so I end up working too many hours, and it’s addicting.<br>
QoD was made partially at night when I still had a day job, and the last 1 and a half year in full time, but that doesn’t mean I was able to do twice as much work unfortunately.<br>
When you work for someone else you have a schedule, but if you work on your own time, it’s harder. Most people tell me it’s hard to stay focused working, and I have that problem too, but not in a way that I can’t work, but mostly because I blend in leisure time with work, and working from home doesn’t help. It’s easy to get distracted, then you feel guilty and spend a couple more hours working. And while I don’t think I’m super slow, I could be using my time better. That’s something I want to change, I don’t thing strict work schedules work well, but not having clear boundaries doesn’t either. If anyone is managing this well please let me know. Open to suggestions 🙂<br>
It’s easy to find people saying this, but I’ve now experienced it myself, when you have a problem that you can’t solve don’t spend hours on the PC, take a walk, go do something else, the solution will come to mind, seriously, it works very often. You trick your mind into something else and the other problem keeps getting solved in the background.</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
In approximately 3 weeks the PS4 version will be released, I don’t any plans for more ports so I intend to move to a new game, and honestly I’m scared, I don’t have a solid idea yet, been mostly sketching ideas or trying some prototypes, and the thought of deciding “let me spend 1-2 years” in this new game is a bit scary, “can I come up with all the money?”, “will it be good?”.<br>
I wish I had a small cool idea to try for a couple months instead of a bigger one, but as I mentioned before, QoD was also supposed to be a 6 months project that turned out into 4 years so better not force anything. I’m trying not to think of “this is gonna be a cool idea that everyone will like” and instead trying to come up again with something that I would like to play, even if others don’t like it, development flows more naturally like that.<br>
Oh and I want to take 2 weeks of proper vacations after the PS4 release, haven’t had vacations in over two years, thinking of backpacking a couple countries, it’s cheaper and it’s good “mind food”-</p>
<p>Still there? thanks for reading – David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 11:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questofdungeons.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Quest of Dungeons&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.questofdungeons.com/imgs/icon.png&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is finally out.&lt;br&gt;
I didn’t get to make a post on day one, and it’s been nearly two weeks since launch but these past 2 weeks have been one crazy roller coaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was released on March 25th, for PC, Mac and iOS. You can get it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/270050&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id698726956/&#34;&gt;iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt; or directly from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.questofdungeons.com/&#34;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; via Humble Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I released all platforms on the same day, which was something I always wanted to try, and I have to say that it didn’t went as bad as I thought. As some of you know I have a day job so I had to take 2 vacation days to simple answer emails and do quick fixes, especially to the PC/Mac version. With each new software is natural to have problems at launch and Quest of Dungeons was no exception, and right now I’m still working on a daily basis in fixing some stuff and attending to some popular requests/changes from players to the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.questofdungeons.com"><img alt="Quest of Dungeons" loading="lazy" src="https://www.questofdungeons.com/imgs/icon.png">  </a></p>
<p>I’m pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is finally out.<br>
I didn’t get to make a post on day one, and it’s been nearly two weeks since launch but these past 2 weeks have been one crazy roller coaster.</p>
<p>It was released on March 25th, for PC, Mac and iOS. You can get it on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/270050">Steam</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/id698726956/">iOS App Store</a> or directly from the <a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com/">site</a> via Humble Store.</p>
<p>I released all platforms on the same day, which was something I always wanted to try, and I have to say that it didn’t went as bad as I thought. As some of you know I have a day job so I had to take 2 vacation days to simple answer emails and do quick fixes, especially to the PC/Mac version. With each new software is natural to have problems at launch and Quest of Dungeons was no exception, and right now I’m still working on a daily basis in fixing some stuff and attending to some popular requests/changes from players to the game.</p>
<p>It was an extremely complicated task to do on my own, managing marketing, answering emails and tweets, scouting Steam forums to see if players are reporting problems, oh and do some actual coding, because you know, bugs don’t fix themselves. But overall I’m happy with the results so far.</p>
<p>The response to the game has been overall positive, and despite a few problems the game has gathered some good reviews.</p>
<p>TouchArcade – 4/5 – <a href="https://toucharcade.com/2014/04/03/quest-of-dungeons-review/">Review</a><br>
CriticalIndieGamer – 9/10 – <a href="https://criticalindiegamer.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-review-pc/">Review</a><br>
SoftPedia – 7/10 – <a href="www.softpedia.com/reviews/games/pc/Quest-of-Dungeons-Review-435164.shtml">Review</a><br>
148Apps – 4/5 – <a href="https://www.148apps.com/reviews/quest-of-dungeons-review/">Review</a><br>
PocketGamer – 6/10 – <a href="https://www.pocketgamer.co.uk/r/iPad/Quest+of+Dungeons/review.asp?c=58622&amp;srch=quest+of+dungeons">Review</a></p>
<p>There are several <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%22quest+of+dungeons%22">youtube videos</a>, and I even caught a few people live streaming it on Twitch, it’s always awesome to see people playing your game, and having genuine reactions.</p>
<p>This is one of my favourite moments (#spoilers)</p>
<p>{&laquo; youtube ef9Z-Zs23GQ &gt;}}</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons development update</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on Quest of Dungeons and I’m nearing Gold. I’m attempting to release every version on the same day, which I never managed to do before but would like to do this time.&lt;br&gt;
I have both the iOS, Mac and Windows version very stable, the Mac and iOS apps were already accepted by the App Store, for Windows I’m still trying to wrap up the process of getting it on a digital store too. I’m just polishing the game and finishing some bugs, but I’m close, I can feel it =)&lt;br&gt;
Right now I’m targeting for a late January release, but I’ll have a more precise date in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been working on Quest of Dungeons and I’m nearing Gold. I’m attempting to release every version on the same day, which I never managed to do before but would like to do this time.<br>
I have both the iOS, Mac and Windows version very stable, the Mac and iOS apps were already accepted by the App Store, for Windows I’m still trying to wrap up the process of getting it on a digital store too. I’m just polishing the game and finishing some bugs, but I’m close, I can feel it =)<br>
Right now I’m targeting for a late January release, but I’ll have a more precise date in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>Meanwhile here are a couple of screenshots.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_01.png"><img alt="quest_of_dungeons_mac_01" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_01-300x187.png"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_02.png"><img alt="quest_of_dungeons_mac_02" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_02-300x187.png"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_03.png"><img alt="quest_of_dungeons_mac_03" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_03-300x187.png"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_04.png"><img alt="quest_of_dungeons_mac_04" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_04-300x187.png"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_05.png"><img alt="quest_of_dungeons_mac_05" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/quest_of_dungeons_mac_05-300x187.png"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puwang is running on PC, releasing it for free</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/puwang-is-running-on-pc-releasing-it-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 23:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/puwang-is-running-on-pc-releasing-it-for-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey guys,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided to spend the afternoon making Puwang run on Windows, really don’t know why but I did it.&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/puwang.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;puwang&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/puwang.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Took me around 3 hours, mostly because I had to add Mouse and Keyboard controls. I also added support for an Xbox360 controller to control the game, it’s very cool. You can’t use the gamepad to control menus though, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to release it for Windows for free, because the game isn’t exactly designed for PC’s, has a smaller resolution, runs on window mode only and doesn’t have Leaderboards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys,</p>
<p>Decided to spend the afternoon making Puwang run on Windows, really don’t know why but I did it.<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/puwang.jpg"><img alt="puwang" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/puwang.jpg"></a><br>
Took me around 3 hours, mostly because I had to add Mouse and Keyboard controls. I also added support for an Xbox360 controller to control the game, it’s very cool. You can’t use the gamepad to control menus though, sorry.</p>
<p>I decided to release it for Windows for free, because the game isn’t exactly designed for PC’s, has a smaller resolution, runs on window mode only and doesn’t have Leaderboards.</p>
<p>Here’s a video I just made of the PC version</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1UkJHDLfI-A?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<blockquote>
<p>The Game requires some external frameworks to be installed, so in event it crashes at start please make sure all dependencies are correctly installed.<br>
–<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=5555">Microsoft Visual C++ 2010 Redistributable Package (x86) </a><br>
–<a href="http://connect.creativelabs.com/openal/Downloads/Forms/AllItems.aspx">OpenAL</a><br>
–<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=35">DirectX9</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>So I hope you have fun, let me know what you think.</p>
<p>Don’t forget that you can still grab the original iOS (Universal) game <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20151117181201/https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?mt=8">here</a>.</p>
<p>Download:<br>
<a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/puwang-notepad-shump">Puwang – (Windows) – 16.1MB</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rage</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 16:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/rage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So being a big fan of Quake, Quake 3 Arena and Doom I was eager to get my hands on id Software latest game, Rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most developers out there I’ve been impressed by John Carmack’s work and breakthroughs in gaming and computer graphics for years. When I first heard Rage was targeting 60FPS I got intrigued.&lt;br&gt;
Almost every game targets 30FPS and targeting twice as that leaves &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/2011/08/hurry-you-only-have-16-ms-to-render-everything/&#34; title=&#34;Hurry you only have 16 ms to render everything&#34;&gt;less time to render each frame&lt;/a&gt;, even more since they were promising vast wastelands, detailed characters, top notch animations and AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So being a big fan of Quake, Quake 3 Arena and Doom I was eager to get my hands on id Software latest game, Rage.</p>
<p>Like most developers out there I’ve been impressed by John Carmack’s work and breakthroughs in gaming and computer graphics for years. When I first heard Rage was targeting 60FPS I got intrigued.<br>
Almost every game targets 30FPS and targeting twice as that leaves <a href="/2011/08/hurry-you-only-have-16-ms-to-render-everything/" title="Hurry you only have 16 ms to render everything">less time to render each frame</a>, even more since they were promising vast wastelands, detailed characters, top notch animations and AI.</p>
<p>But enough of that. I got the PC version since I’m old fashioned and I think shooters are best played with Mouse/Kb. Besides that shooters are always a tad slower on consoles to compensate the lack of Mouse for aiming.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg" title="WP_000105"></a></p>
<p>The game comes packed on 3 DVD summing a 23GB install.</p>
<p>The story takes place after a meteor crashing into the earth, several arks where placed underground with people in order for mankind to survive. You are one of those survivors.<br>
There isn’t much more into, after you wake up you discovered most of the planet is a wasteland ruled by bandits, mutants and others.</p>
<p>From there you jump from mission to mission against the several factions.</p>
<p>Apart from some technical issues I first encountered, after updating the drivers I managed to play it smoothly on my laptop, my desktop rig is quite old now (6+ years) so it doesn’t quite handle it at 1080p.</p>
<p>I’m very impressed with the game’s smooth animations and enemy AI. The story itself is crap but the whole fun in this game is just playing it, the battles always feel fresh, holding the shotgun feels like an id gun indeed. You keep encountering new enemies with new tricks, near the end you are still trying to get the hang of that new enemy tactics.</p>
<p>If you have the chance try it.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00001.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00001-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00007.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00007-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00010.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00010-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00012.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00012-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00005.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00005-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00008.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00008-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00009.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00009-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00010.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00010-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00015.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00015-300x168.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Meat Boy, meat dissection</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/super-meat-boy-meat-dissection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 20:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/super-meat-boy-meat-dissection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually write reviews about games, maybe mostly because I don’t play as often as I used to. Most games today are just graphics graphics, I use super shader ray-traced lights but I forgot gameplay because I’m a tech demo.&lt;br&gt;
I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/&#34;&gt;grew up with a Super Nintendo&lt;/a&gt; playing Super Mario World and Zelda A Link to the Past, yeah shocker, no Spectrum to me :P, so I’m 2D gameplay type lover.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don’t usually write reviews about games, maybe mostly because I don’t play as often as I used to. Most games today are just graphics graphics, I use super shader ray-traced lights but I forgot gameplay because I’m a tech demo.<br>
I <a href="/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/">grew up with a Super Nintendo</a> playing Super Mario World and Zelda A Link to the Past, yeah shocker, no Spectrum to me :P, so I’m 2D gameplay type lover.</p>
<p>I always loved Mario games, the precision and the rush of making a level without stopping or speeding down was as good as it gets for platform games in my opinion. This is the key point in Mario games, not the story, why else would people still be playing those games? The princess keeps being kidnapped by the same dude, there’s basically no story so what keeps gamers coming around is gameplay and fun.</p>
<p>This is what Super Meat Boy brings us, excellent gameplay with all the frustration and deaths that actually brings meaning to reaching the end of a level. I’ve been following Meat Boy development ever since it was announced, well in fact I’m an avid Edmund Mcmillen fan even since <a href="http://www.chroniclogic.com/gish.htm">Gish</a>, I even bought his “This is a cry for help” cd, comes packed with 18 games and great comics, you should get it if we is still selling them.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/edmund_mcmillen_this_is_a_cry_for_help_cd.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/edmund_mcmillen_this_is_a_cry_for_help_cd.jpg" title="This is a cry for Help Edmund Mcmillen CD proof :P"></a></p>
<p>Sorry Tommy Refenes but I don’t know any of your past works. Anyway, back on track…</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/1269147417.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/1269147417.jpg" title="1269147417"></a></p>
<p>The game is a fast paced platform game with a block of meat which mission is to reach Bandage Girl (it’s Super Meat Boy “princess peach”) on every level, for that we must jump, jump, jump, avoid traps, jump, did I mention we has to jump?</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/snessmb.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/snessmb.jpg" title="snessmb"></a></p>
<p>The entire game is about precision and button timing, you fail you die, too slow? goodbye.<br>
This will put you swearing at the TV like you never did, believe me, and not because the buttons feel dumb or the game didn’t respond but because you sucked and died. The controls are so well responsive that it feels like they grabbed Super Mario controls code and improved it.<br>
Plus the Xbox360 controller buttons colors are almost the same as the SNES controller, I felt like going back in time.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/xbox360controller1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/xbox360controller1.jpg" title="xbox360controller"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/Snes_control.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/Snes_control.jpg" title="Snes_control"></a></p>
<p>A curious thing is, there’s a run button, the X and another for jump, the A button. Most of the time you will be running so the run button feels almost useless. Well the obvious thing is, on tight platforms you won’t be running, the other thing is this was the first time since those early hardcore platform games which I felt that pressing that button all the time helped me grasping the controller better, and jump seem more timed because you are using the same finger to press them both. Just try it, you’ll see what I mean.</p>
<p>Graphically the game is simple but pretty with small details that you’ll probably miss the first time you play each level. My only complaint is that the cutscenes don’t feel like they belong in the game, because the lack of detail in scenarios and characters, luckily most will put a smile on your face so no harm done.</p>
<p>The game is packed with unlockable characters from other indie games like Beat Trip, Braid, Gish, you name it. For that you need to collect bandages all across the levels. The other things is that each level has a Light and Dark World, (Zelda Link to the Past memories for me) and you unlock the Dark World, which is even harder when you score an A in the Light World.</p>
<p>So the game is a blast and I highly recommend it, even more because right now is at 800 MS Points.</p>
<p>Here’s a video of me playing, be warned I’m not a very good player 😛</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8gwh1O1OpyQ?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games and systems from childhood</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 12:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think the first game I ever played was &lt;strong&gt;Tetris&lt;/strong&gt; on a 286 if my memory isn’t failing me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tetris_DOS_1986.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tetris_DOS_1986.png&#34; title=&#34;Tetris_DOS_1986&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My father worked at restaurant nearby a small apartment rental office, one of the dudes that worked there occasionally would let me play. I remember one day he had this new game, &lt;strong&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/strong&gt;, my chin just fell, awesome,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/prince-of-persia.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/prince-of-persia.gif&#34; title=&#34;prince-of-persia&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought games couldn’t get any better. I remember always asking him to “type the code to play” as I called it, since it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DOS&#34;&gt;DOS&lt;/a&gt; based. Probably something like “cd /games/prince~” =P&lt;br&gt;
I spent hours playing that game, I do know I never managed to see the end thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think the first game I ever played was <strong>Tetris</strong> on a 286 if my memory isn’t failing me.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tetris_DOS_1986.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tetris_DOS_1986.png" title="Tetris_DOS_1986"></a><br>
My father worked at restaurant nearby a small apartment rental office, one of the dudes that worked there occasionally would let me play. I remember one day he had this new game, <strong>Prince of Persia</strong>, my chin just fell, awesome,</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/prince-of-persia.gif"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/prince-of-persia.gif" title="prince-of-persia"></a></p>
<p>I thought games couldn’t get any better. I remember always asking him to “type the code to play” as I called it, since it was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DOS">DOS</a> based. Probably something like “cd /games/prince~” =P<br>
I spent hours playing that game, I do know I never managed to see the end thought.</p>
<p>Next in line were <strong>Super Mario Bros</strong>. games. Some neighbors had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NES"><strong>NES</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/nes-console.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/nes-console.jpg" title="nes-console"></a></p>
<p>and when my parents were there that was to entertain the visitors kids, I didn’t even know there were any home consoles before seeing a NES before, I later discovered the Spectrum which was older but my first contact with a home console was with the NES and it’s gigantic cartridges.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/mario_bros_nes_cartridge.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/mario_bros_nes_cartridge.jpg" title="mario_bros_nes_cartridge"></a></p>
<p>I never got at PC or console until I turn 12 I think, when my mother brought back from one of her trips a what she called “expensive toy on promotion” which was basically a Super Nintendo Street Fighter 2 Turbo Edition, a Super Scope and another game <strong>Battletoads in BattleManiacs</strong></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/snes.jpg" title="snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/SNES_Controller.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/SNES_Controller.jpg" title="SNES_Controller"></a></p>
<p>This is a picture of the box, containing the Super Nintendo and <strong>Street Fighter 2 Turbo</strong></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/snes-street-fighter-2-turbo-edition.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/snes-street-fighter-2-turbo-edition.jpg" title="snes street fighter 2 turbo edition"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/street_fighter_ii_snes_hadoken.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/street_fighter_ii_snes_hadoken.jpg" title="street_fighter_ii_snes_hadoken"></a><br>
Sure was a sweet game, probably one of the best fight games I ever played. Since most of my friends at the time didn’t had this game I had quite the advantage when borrowing games.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Battletoads_in_battlemaniacs-snes-box.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Battletoads_in_battlemaniacs-snes-box.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Battletoads_in_battlemaniacs-snes-box.jpg" title="Battletoads_in_battlemaniacs snes box"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Battletoads-in-Battlemaniacs-cartridge.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Battletoads-in-Battlemaniacs-cartridge.jpg" title="Battletoads in Battlemaniacs cartridge"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/BattletoadsInBattlemaniacs3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/BattletoadsInBattlemaniacs3.jpg" title="BattletoadsInBattlemaniacs3"></a></p>
<p><strong>Battletoads in Battlemaniacs</strong> was a Beat ’em up game much like <strong>Street of Rage</strong> on the <strong>Mega Drive</strong> ( <strong>Genesis</strong> in US). This game had one of the hardest levels I ever played on a game, the “brain track race thingy”</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IbMLdDDGmyc?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>If people are complaining about <a href="http://www.limbogame.org/"><strong>Limbo</strong>‘</a>s deaths I imagine with this game. It took me ages to beat that level.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_scope.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_scope" title="super_scope"></a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/nintendo-snes-scope.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/nintendo-snes-scope.jpg" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA"></a><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Super-NES-Super-Scope-6-2.gif"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Super-NES-Super-Scope-6.gif" title="Super NES Super Scope 6 (2)"></a></p>
<p>The <strong>Super Scope</strong> was this huge bazooka, had 6 games in it but they all sucked. I don’t think Nintendo released much more games for this.</p>
<p>Since most of my friends had the SNES + <strong>Super Mario World</strong> bundle I pretty much always had a copy at home. It is one of my favorite games ever. Even my sister loved to play it. Along side Battletoads this was another game that made me had rage attacks one a particular level, <a href="http://www.mariowiki.com/Tubular">Tubular</a>, it’s considered the hardest levels in the game because of the lack of ground to stand on and the large amount of enemies.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_mario_world_box.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_mario_world_box.jpg" title="super_mario_world_box"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tubular_SMW.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Tubular_SMW.png" title="Tubular_SMW"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-world-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-world-2.jpg" title="super-mario-world-2"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-world.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-world.jpg" title="super mario world"></a></p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hSXSWqUirGA?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/ZelaALttP.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/ZelaALttP.jpg" title="ZelaALttP"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/a-link-to-the-past-cardridge.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/a-link-to-the-past-cardridge.jpg" title="a link to the past cardridge"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/zelda-a-link-to-the-past.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/zelda-a-link-to-the-past.jpg" title="zelda-a-link-to-the-past"></a></p>
<p>Another one of my favorite SNES games is <strong>The Legend of Zelda A Link to the Past</strong>, for me it’s the best Zelda game. Sure <strong>Zelda Ocarina of Time</strong> was awesome but it didn’t brought anything new to the series, even more the removed what made Link to the Past so great, the Light and the Dark world. After exploring the all Light World and defeating Ganondorf you are transported to the Dark World</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/LegendOfZelda_2D00_ALinkToThePast_2D00_LightWorld.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/LegendOfZelda_2D00_ALinkToThePast_2D00_LightWorld.png" title="LegendOfZelda_2D00_ALinkToThePast_2D00_LightWorld"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/LegendOfZelda-ALinkToThePast-DarkWorld.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/LegendOfZelda-ALinkToThePast-DarkWorld.png" title="LegendOfZelda-ALinkToThePast-DarkWorld"></a></p>
<p>Wait wait… but you could also go back in forward from one world to another, most of the castle and secrets implied that you had to activate or move something in a world to affect the other one. How cool is that?</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/240px-Light_World_-_Dark_World.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/240px-Light_World_-_Dark_World.png" title="240px-Light_World_-_Dark_World"></a></p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GqZg1ikmKFw?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>I don’t remember all the other games that I’ve played on the SNES but here are some box arts from some I do remember:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/axelay_box.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/axelay_box.jpg" title="axelay_box"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/supermariokart_box.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/supermariokart_box.jpg" title="supermariokart_box"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_nes-super_mario_world_2_yoshis_island.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super_nes-super_mario_world_2_yoshis_island.jpg" title="super_nes-super_mario_world_2_yoshis_island"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-rpg-box_front.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-rpg-box_front.jpg" title="super mario rpg box_front"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-all-stars-snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-mario-all-stars-snes.jpg" title="super mario all stars snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-castlevania-iv-snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/super-castlevania-iv-snes.jpg" title="super castlevania iv snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/starfox-super-nintendo-box-art.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/starfox-super-nintendo-box-art.jpg" title="starfox-super-nintendo-box-art"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/simcity_snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/simcity_snes.jpg" title="simcity_snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/F-Zero_snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/F-Zero_snes.jpg" title="F-Zero_snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/donkey-kong-country-snes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/donkey-kong-country-snes.jpg" title="donkey-kong-country snes"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/chrono_trigger_snes_box1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/chrono_trigger_snes_box1.jpg" title="chrono_trigger_snes_box1"></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/FFviBoxArt.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/FFviBoxArt.jpg" title="FFviBoxArt"></a></p>
<p>Damn this post is getting way big, I think I’m going to split this into several parts, I’ll cover Mega Drive on the next run. What about you, what are your favorite SNES games?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make a Game Week</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/03/make-a-game-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/03/make-a-game-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work on a game creation company and this week the administration decided to give us a challenge, to make a game. Using whatever tools we want to whatever platform we like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we got divided between 4 teams the challenge was to make every minute count. My team got composed by me (programmer), a designer and a person from man resources. Of course I was going to handle every bit of code, the designer the art and the third person the level design and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I work on a game creation company and this week the administration decided to give us a challenge, to make a game. Using whatever tools we want to whatever platform we like.</p>
<p>After we got divided between 4 teams the challenge was to make every minute count. My team got composed by me (programmer), a designer and a person from man resources. Of course I was going to handle every bit of code, the designer the art and the third person the level design and documentation.</p>
<p>We came up with a platform game called Cloud9 in which you have to return a star to the moon. The star has magical properties and can use the 4 basic elements. <img alt="cloud9" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2009/03/cloud9.jpg" title="cloud9"></p>
<p>Meanwhile the week went by and this is the last day. I spent most of the day building the level editor.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
