<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 10 years old!</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-10-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-10-years-old/</guid>
      <description>📝 It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years It&amp;rsquo;s around 11 a.m. as start to type this. 10 years ago at this hour, I was at my day job, trying to focus and not be distracted by the fact that later that day, at around 18h, Quest of Dungeons was being released on Steam and iOS. For the first time, players around the world could try it. I was quite anxious about this; it had been a few years in the making, mostly nights and weekends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="-its-been-10-years">📝 It&rsquo;s been 10 years</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s around 11 a.m. as start to type this. 10 years ago at this hour, I was at my day job, trying to focus and not be distracted by the fact that later that day, at around 18h, <a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a> was being released on Steam and iOS. For the first time, players around the world could try it. I was quite anxious about this; it had been a few years in the making, <a href="/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/">mostly nights and weekends</a>. I had little idea of what to expect, but being on Steam was simultaneously exciting and terrifying. What if people hated it?</p>
<p>What follows for the rest of the post, is a brain dump of the timeline of some of the most crucial events of this silly little project for anyone who is curious.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/pixel_logo_v1_4x.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons characters"  />
</p>
<h1 id="-2011-2013">🤯 2011-2013</h1>
<p>✔️ Failing can help</p>
<p>Before the game launched, I had a few years of terrible prototypes, cancelled projects, and other unexpected life events. One day, though, all those mistakes fell into place, and QoD was born—a flow of ideas came to my mind, after seeing a bunch of stuff failed in front of me, but that maybe I could make them work. I knew what I wanted to avoid now and what I things I would like to experiment with. Within this time I also made a simple iOS game called <a href="/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/">Puwang</a>, a gamejam compo, where most of the goal was to make a quick game and hopefully make $100 that year to cover the iOS developer account expenses. For QoD I wanted to make a small game that I could play on my phone during commute, and that&rsquo;s why it started as a mobile-only game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_characters.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons characters"  />
</p>
<p>⌨️ Expanding</p>
<p>During the time I was the only person to ever played it, I found myself enjoying it on a bigger screen/tablet, and after giving it a 2-3 friends to test and having confirmation, I thought it would be good to launch a desktop version along the iPhone/iPad versions, Windows and Mac.
This added some development time, but also allowed me to expand the game a bit more, the mobile version was virtually identical to desktop/tabled, but they shared a bigger UI, more suited for Mouse and the higher resolutions.
This turned out to be one of the best decisions, as the desktop version is foundation for everything after. At this point I was already <a href="/tags/basalt/">rolling my own engine</a> for prior games on mobile and desktop, so most of the development was indeed for game stuff, and not engine. While I&rsquo;ve made the mistake often of &ldquo;build the engine instead of game&rdquo;, here the engine was built around the game, that&rsquo;s how it should be.</p>
<h1 id="20140325---steam-and-ios-launch">2014/03/25 - Steam and iOS launch</h1>
<p>I had tried to bring games to Steam before but with no success. The focus was on Mobile, with Desktop in mind, but where to sell it? Before Steam I was able to get confirmation for the new Humble Store, but Steam was still on my mind. In the past I had higher hopes for my first game <a href="/tags/vizati/">Vizati</a>, looked more polished, so QoD didn&rsquo;t seemed to have a chance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Screenshot-2022-11-01-at-19.38.50.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>But I decided to make a trailer and launch a GL page, and imagine my surprise when QoD was approved on Steam Greenlight within a week or so. Just look at my dumb face here that I just digged from some old Tweets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/david_amador_celebrating_qod_greenlight_2014-01-24_22.38.07.jpg" alt="David celebrating QoD approval on Steam Greenlight"  />
</p>
<p>With the trailer out, people seemed to enjoyed what they saw, I also thought I was near completing the game, there&rsquo;s always something right? So I pretty much crunched the entire rest of time between my day job and finishing the game.</p>
<p>Finally on March 25th it was out, everyone could play it. Since the game was only releasing around 18h on Steam, I went to my day job that day, and only took the next day off for checking &amp; fixing bugs etc.</p>
<p>Initially all I was getting was a flow of emails with some bugs and suggestions, but overall people seemed to like it, which was a relief. There was still tons of stuff to fix, but slowly, and for the next few weeks went through issues and suggestions. On the mobile side of things things were smoother, that version was the older one, had more testing, also less hardware configurations. I recall before launch, a conversation with some coworkers, that making it paid on mobile was probably a mistake, but I don&rsquo;t know how to design games around F2P/Ads, so I made it paid.  But, thankfully, even being a paid game, at $1.99, people were happy with what they were getting.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_tablet_iphone_desktop.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Android"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20140530---linux">2014/05/30 - Linux</h1>
<p>This one was something that I had in the back on my mind for a while, theoretically my engine could be ported to Linux, but I was scared of having too many versions at launch, handing those 4 SKUs was already a handful, so this was left for later. This actually ended up being a factor in Humble Bundle contacting me to participate in one of their bundles, back then having a game on all 3 platforms was a must.
Technically speaking it wasn&rsquo;t extremely complicated, by this time the engine was already relatively split in ways that it was easy to integrate new OS, it was just a matter of implementation.
Also, now that Steam Deck is a thing, it just worked out of the box.</p>
<h1 id="20140826---android">2014/08/26 - Android</h1>
<p>With Desktops and iOS versions being well received I started getting requests for an Android version, I had never worked on this platform, but with most of the know bugs fixed, I bought a cheap Android phone and I moved into porting the game to this platform, you can read more about that <a href="/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/">here</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_android_2014-05-29_00.05.50.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Android"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2014---ouya-cancelled">2014 - OUYA (cancelled)</h1>
<p>The hot thing around the time was OUYA, games like TowerFall were born there, so since I had an Android version I started to work on that, because it would be the closest to a traditional console that I thought I could put this game on. I started working on it, but once Microsoft accepted my pitch for the Xbox One (see below), I placed this in low priority. Between the time it took me to develop the Xbox One version, OUYA had it downfall, and by that time I just cancelled it.</p>
<h1 id="201509---xbox-one">2015/09 - Xbox One</h1>
<p>In the summer of 2014, after the launch of all those versions, relatively successfully, I started talking with ID@Xbox with the possibility of bringing QoD to Xbox One. There were a couple months of paperwork and mostly the conversation about &ldquo;this is a mouse game, how will it work on consoles?&rdquo;, which was when I started seeing that all the UI needed to be remade, and even some gameplay.</p>
<p>There are several posts, <a href="/2015/07/lets-talk-about-the-new-stuff-in-quest-of-dungeons-for-xbox-one/">here</a>, <a href="/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/">here</a>, <a href="/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/">here</a>, <a href="/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/">here</a> and <a href="/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/">here</a>  detailing what went into to that process, but after around 1 year the game was finally released, and all the work put into reworking the game to controller friendly interface and gameplay paid off, it was <a href="/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/">positively received</a>. I also took the opportunity to double the content available, and also add an <a href="/2015/04/necrodancer-is-joining/">extra character</a>. I&rsquo;m sure it was this combination of an almost remade version with increased content that led to it&rsquo;s positive feedback. I&rsquo;m really happy I decided to take all those months to remake it, it was daunting at first, I&rsquo;ll tell you that, but I&rsquo;m glad I did it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_xbox_one_launch.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons Xbox One launch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20160929---wii-u-and-nintendo-3ds">2016/09/29 - Wii U and Nintendo 3DS</h1>
<p>Around 2015 summer, before Xbox One release, and if I recall correctly, during Gamescom in Germany, I started talking with Nintendo about bringing the game to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U.</p>
<p>This was when Nintendo was a bit more restrictive in terms of third party developers, and I was fully expecting, that me, a solo developer, would not make the cut, and it took a lot of months and patience to finally be able to show the game to someone and get accepted as an official Nintendo developer.</p>
<p>At first my goal was to make Wii U port first because it would be similar to Xbox One, with some additional features for the GamePad. Nintendo 3DS would come later, it would take more work due to it&rsquo;s specifics.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, or fortunately (depending how you see it), I bricked my Wii U devKit after a couple months of work, when the game was in a good state already but before 100% finished. During the time I waited for repairs I started the Nintendo 3DS version.</p>
<p>I knew would take a LOT more work, from performance, to completely different UI for dual screen, hybrid of touch + buttons. But when the Wii U devKit arrived, I decided to launch them side-by-side, I talked with Nintendo about a cross-buy possibility, and once they gave the ok that was the goal.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_new_inventory.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons StreetPass"  />
</p>
<p>The Nintendo 3DS version was one of the most complicated ones to pull off. This was also the first time that working on my own engine was the only thing making it possible. A lot of people were suggesting me to use Unity, and I had would have saved time in porting, which can be true, but Unity didn&rsquo;t supported 3DS, so it would never have happened if not for my custom framework.</p>
<p>This is hands down my favourite version, there is no other like it, mostly because of the nature of the device.</p>
<p>It was so fun to work with that I found myself <a href="/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/">adding features</a> just because I wanted to test them, like the StreetPass, where you can get ghosts from other players you pass on the street. Nintendo had a really neat device here.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/3ds_qod_streetpass.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons StreetPass"  />
</p>
<p>There was some trouble having both versions on the same day, it&rsquo;s a lot of coordination required between me, Nintendo America and Europe teams, 4 different SKUs (3DS NA+EU, Wii U NA+EU), but in the end we made it.</p>
<p>Like I suspected during my own tests, on the 3DS it was the ideal portable version, it&rsquo;s a game that suits shorts sessions on the go.</p>
<p>This was also the first time I worked with a publisher for this game, for Japan, the game was published by Flyhigh Works, they took it to Tokyo Game Show, localized to JP, and were crucial in shaping up the 3DS version into what it is. I do recall many sessions where my stubbornness almost caused some bad decisions in the game, but they were really cool in guiding me to make the best of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_wiiu_3ds.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Wii U and Nintendo 3DS"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20170120---playstation-4-and-the-vita-version-that-never-was">2017/01/20 - PlayStation 4 and the Vita version that never was.</h1>
<p>I love my PlayStation 4, in fact it&rsquo;s the console I have more physical games for.</p>
<p>So it was with great excitement that after a Skype call with my PlayStation rep I had the greenlight to get the game there. This started around the time of Nintendo too, but sadly, and at first I wanted PS4 + Vita combo, like Wii U + 3DS, but for a variety of reasons the PlayStation Vita never happened.</p>
<p>This was one of the reasons the PS4 versions was one of the latter ones, I kept hoping I could launch both simultaneously but never happened. Fun fact, this version almost had a physical edition that got cancelled by the publisher at last moment, eventually I even got someone, another publisher, to take care of the PS Vita version, but that also got cancelled later on. So a combination of things that happened that were no one&rsquo;s fault, but also made it a bit hard for me to explain why it wasn&rsquo;t happening. In certain moments it was almost, but it never did happened. It was a bit frustrating that I didn&rsquo;t had clear answers for the players regarding this, but I couldn&rsquo;t, and I tried but failed in the end. Well, that&rsquo;s game development.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons on PlayStation 4"  />
</p>
<h1 id="20170810---nintendo-switch">2017/08/10 - Nintendo Switch</h1>
<p>Around 1 month after I released on Wii U and 3DS, Nintendo announced their new hybrid console, the Nintendo Switch. I immediately started getting questions from players about a port. This complicated promoting the new Nintendo versions while everyone was excited about the upcoming console, saving money for it and the games. By coincidence I had launched both versions right at the end.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t recall exactly when conversations started with Nintendo about this, since it was in hot demand, both for retail and developers, but eventually Nintendo shipped me a devKit and I started porting. It was released first in the Japanese regions, again by Flyhigh Works. But a few weeks later again by me in the rest of the world. This version had the portability of 3DS, and graphics/resolution and UI of the home consoles. This was also the first time I made a demo for the game, which still exists on the eShop.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/quest_of_dungeons_switch.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Nintendo Switch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2019---dreamcast-just-having-fun">2019 - Dreamcast (just having fun)</h1>
<p>In 2019 I got my hands on a Dreamcast I decided to &ldquo;wonder if I can port it there?&rdquo;, it was never really meant for a full release, that would take months of time that I don&rsquo;t have at the moment,
I just posting it here for the record, this was under a week of work, it was fun. Maybe if I reach retirement I&rsquo;ll take some time to finish it. There&rsquo;s a lot of work left in there.</p>
<p>After a while booting the game on an emulator,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_dreamcast_2.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons running on emulator 1"  />
</p>
<p>and then later when I got it booting on a real Dreamcast</p>
 

<video width=100% controls>
    <source src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_running_on_dreamcast.mp4" type="video/mp4">
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
</video>


<h1 id="20210413---switch-physical-edition">2021/04/13 - Switch Physical Edition</h1>
<p>Like I mentioned before, I tried to get the game in physical format before, and I kept trying for years but it simply wasn&rsquo;t happening. Until 2021, when by random chance, someone recommended me Leoful, and they accepted right away, in fact, from initial contact to production, it was just a couple months, I&rsquo;m really happy I was able to finally get the game on an actual box, it hits differently, as I <a href="/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/">grew playing Nintendo games</a>,  and also feels like a closure to a project that started on a smaller device and made it&rsquo;s way to a real physical game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Physical Edition for Nintendo Switch"  />
</p>
<h1 id="2022---">2022 - ??</h1>
<p>Right now the game still exists in several stores (R.I.P. Nintendo 3DS and Wii U), and it&rsquo;s in maintenance mode only. The platforms patched more regularly are the mobile ones, whenever Apple or Android come up with new rules or it breaks on new devices. Windows gives nearly no problems, MacOS breaks things more often, but overall it doesn&rsquo;t give a lot of work, the last time I had to mess with it, was the Linux version to patch stuff for Steam Deck, but it was relatively easy.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/quest_of_dungeons_steam_deck.jpg" alt="Quest of Dungeons on Steam Deck"  />
</p>
<p>So in the end things worked out, and I want to say a big thank you to everyone who supported this project, I read all the emails, DMs, messages everyone sent over the years, even fanart, you rock.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gKx4R.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<h1 id="some-trivia">Some trivia</h1>
<ul>
<li>The game has 79k of code (all platforms)</li>
<li>The game engine has 130k of code (all platforms)</li>
<li>Over 63800 years of total play time on Steam alone</li>
<li>The game allowing the player to drop items anywhere and being persistent was a side effect of saving the whole world to save instead of recreating it by seed. I just turned it into a feature.</li>
<li>I was only able to finish the game in Hell mode AFTER releasing it, the math seemed to check out, but I wasn&rsquo;t good enough.</li>
<li>The game was called Quest of Dungeons from day 1 of development, as a generic codename, I just grew too attached to it.</li>
<li>There was a pet system that got dropped, taming enemies, but it was dropped in favour of Shaman unique skill of summons.</li>
<li>There was a way for enemies to travel between floors, like Resident Evil added that later on, going between rooms, but it was too aggressive and made the game frustratingly hard.</li>
<li>All the level and combat damage math falls apart around character level 40 or above, but the game was designed below that.</li>
<li>The initial skull sign, which only exists at the very start, was a way to teach the player that death meant restarting, in 2013-14 roguelikes weren&rsquo;t as popular and it was seen as a shock for that to happen (play-testers would email me &ldquo;my save is lost&rdquo;). My goal was that by potentially learning that early on, the player would not get surprised.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you for reading all of this.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qod_characters_anniversary.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a cool image made by <a href="https://twitter.com/LeonorParra08">Leonor</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting the blog from WordPress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/01/converting-the-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/01/converting-the-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I shutdown the VPS that has been hosting all my websites for the last ~10 years. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved everything to static content, including this website.
📝 WordPress Since the very beginning (~2008) this blog has been powered by WordPress, it served me well, it worked, had a nice backend to make the posts, plugins and themes. After a couple years I moved from shared hosting to a VPS, I had other websites and services I needed running and all in same machine was better and cheaper.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I shutdown the VPS that has been hosting all my websites for the last ~10 years. I&rsquo;ve moved everything to static content, including this website.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/shutting-down-server.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<h1 id="-wordpress">📝 WordPress</h1>
<p>Since the very beginning (~2008) this blog has been powered by WordPress, it served me well, it worked, had a nice backend to make the posts, plugins and themes. After a couple years I moved from shared hosting to a VPS, I had other websites and services I needed running and all in same machine was better and cheaper. But WordPress needs a lot of things, PHP, MySQL, maintenance in all those moving parts.</p>
<p>So for the past couple of years I&rsquo;ve been thinking in migrating it to something like Jekyll or Hugo, to serve it as static content. But the few times I looked into the process it seemed like a big task especially because I have 184 posts, I wasn&rsquo;t just starting from 0, I wanted to maintain the existing content, posts, images, URLs etc. So, a couple days ago I decided it was time.</p>
<h1 id="-converting-and-moving-the-websites">📝 Converting and Moving the websites</h1>
<h3 id="-questofdungeonscom">🔗 questofdungeons.com</h3>
<p>This was the easier of them, it&rsquo;s just not working 100% as it was before (more on that in a bit). Site was just a couple of hand-made pages I hacked in HTML/CSS/JS years ago, so that was already done.</p>
<p>The only problem was the <a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com/stats.html">stats page</a>  relied on a PHP script to pull the stats from Steam. PHP was out of the question since I wanted to host on GitHub, so I tried the full JavaScript approach, but that hits the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-origin_resource_sharing">CORS</a> issue, and I would need a proxy for that, so for now I grabbed the last stats and it&rsquo;s serving it statically. I have to think of something else later since I don&rsquo;t have PHP anymore etc. But it&rsquo;s not important and the numbers aren&rsquo;t moving as much as they used to. I grabbed all files, pushed to a GitHub repo, activated pages, changed the nameservers, queued SSL cert, and voilá, the site is now live.</p>
<h3 id="-upfallstudioscom">🔗 upfallStudios.com</h3>
<p>The <a href="/2022/11/merged-personal-and-studio-blogs-into-one/">merging the Upfall Studios blog</a> a while ago was not an isolated act, I was thinking about this already. After the merge, <a href="https://www.upfallstudios.com">www.upfallstudios.com</a> was left with only the front page, which was static content already. I also had a doPresskit() <a href="https://www.upfallstudios.com/press/">page</a>, which was all PHP, and I need to keep it for games info etc. After a bit of search I found there is an <a href="https://github.com/Dvergar/dopresskit-static">alternative</a>, serving static content, so I converted and updated the site to use it, that way 100% of the site was ready. Easy and working as before.</p>
<h3 id="-david-amadorcom">🔗 david-amador.com</h3>
<p>And now I was free to focus on the one I knew would be a headache, this blog. Full wordpress site, no static content, everything dynamic using plugins, MySQL, PHP and custom .htaccess rules.</p>
<ul>
<li>❌ Jekyll</li>
</ul>
<p>From prior research, I was inclined to <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> since all I read online was that it was good, also it&rsquo;s been around for 15 years, so it has proved it works and should be stable.
But after a couple days of messing around with configs and pre-requisites, packages versions mismatches between Jekyll, ruby, wordpress exporters etc, I gave up. Booting up a new site can be achieved fast, but I needed to also be able to import all of my content, and that proved to be hard. Also I started thinking about the future of the blog, what if in a couple years the version breaks on modern OS version, and I can&rsquo;t run the latest one due to some incompatibility, even on a VM that would be a nightmare to keep around just for one site.</p>
<ul>
<li>✅ Hugo</li>
</ul>
<p>So I decided to go for <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a>, single executable, it works, it&rsquo;s fast. Highly recommend it. The documentation does lacks sometimes, but between the forums, and looking at other people&rsquo;s pages on GitHub it&rsquo;s perfectly doable.</p>
<p>I had to export the data, and there are a couple of Wordpress plugins for that, the problem was that my server was old, i386, outdated Ubuntu version, the PHP server version had no Zip support, which most of those plugins needed. After messing around a bit with the server trying to install the proper dependencies, which included actually breaking the entire thing and having to restore from backup, I decided a different approached. Created a Docker VM with wordpress, imported my existing WP files and database locally, installed the required plugins and was finally able to export all.</p>
<p>📄 Now that I had all the files in markdown format, it was really more of a going through Hugo documentation, placing all freshly made files in place and cleaning up stuff. One neat thing is that you can run and edit an Hugo website live.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span class="line"><span class="cl">Hugo.exe server -D
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This will make the site run on localhost:1313/ , so while you edit the markdown files, it will keep refreshing, I didn&rsquo;t even had to press F5, I could have it side by side and Ctrl+S, super fast to iterate.</p>
<p>🎥 There was a LOT of YouTube embed code, that I placed over the years, and was not ever working anymore on original website, some of it had Macromedia code, yeah, that old! So I tried to fix all that, then just regex replace some stuff like wrong image paths.</p>
<p>🧑‍💻 I also had to fix some of the programming code block notation. I was using</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="nt">pre</span> <span class="na">lang</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;LANG&#34;</span><span class="p">&gt;</span> 
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">&lt;/</span><span class="nt">pre</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>for code blocks, but the parser collapsed in a couple posts, leaving pre tags, which was helpful in searching for them actually. I fixed all I could find.</p>
<p>🗣️ As for the comments, I had Disqus installed on Upfall Studios blog, but on this blog it was on WP system, so what I did was just import all the comments on Disqus and merged both. So the comment system should work on the bottom of all posts (say Hi if you want :)</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if all the comments are there though, one particular post I had to go back and import it manually again, but it also had over 100 comments, so it might have failed the first time. I still have all the old data, so if needed (and I can spot it) I can always import it again on Disqus.</p>
<p>📰 The RSS feed should theoretically still work for everyone who had from the old blog, but I&rsquo;m not 100% sure, once I put this post live I guess I&rsquo;ll know.</p>
<p>💻 So my current workflow is: I have a git repo with all the markdown and website code and I have the live website as a submodule, so whenever I made a change, I export it with Hugo, git commit all changes and GitHub pages just deploys them, feels like magic :D</p>
<h3 id="-speed">🚀 Speed</h3>
<p>Oh its much faster, obviously, but look at the changes of before (left) and after (right) using PageSpeed Insights.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/david_amador_site_wordpress_vs_hugo_speed.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Still there? Well so far I&rsquo;m happy with the move, I do miss the nice WordPress backend thing if I&rsquo;m being honest, but I can live without it. I feel like in the long run I won&rsquo;t miss having to maintain that server, also the costs. Right now I&rsquo;m editing this on Obsidian, about to commit and see if it goes live, RSS and all. If you find any broken stuff or have suggestions let me know, either mastodon, email or a comment here.</p>
<p>Until the next time, where hopefully I&rsquo;ll talk about games! Thanks for reading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #2</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.
But onto game5 progress.
Importers I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&amp;gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.</p>
<p>But onto <a href="/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/" title="game5 devlog #1">game5</a> progress.</p>
<h2 id="importers">Importers</h2>
<p>I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them. I could have made the game parse the spreadsheet at boot time and create them, but I decided against it, I want to generate this process offline. One of the reasons is because I have more control over not replacing existing items GUIDs (to keep and existing links), and also I can tweak any individually generated files manually, if I need to.</p>
<h2 id="testing-amp-automation">Testing &amp; Automation</h2>
<p>As I start to get more pieces onto the game I’m hitting the time that I need to start testing what I do, obviously with beta testers etc, but also I need to find a way to test it on my own in an effective way. For bugs, balance and well, fun factor.</p>
<p>I recall for Quest of Dungeons I had several spreadsheets with the game combat formulas and it would show up curves of progression for each character stat as it levelled up, this helped me visualising pros and cons of each one of them. And even other stuff, like how many total XP points one could get by each floor, or gold, so even with the procedural nature, I knew lower and upper bounds.</p>
<p>That meant that even if I never ended up getting a really good, or bad combination of items during my tests, I could see the best and worst case, and I would tweak monsters and boss fights accordingly.</p>
<p>This leads me to this game, where given it’s nature of it’s progression, I’m still unsure of the best tools I can cook up to help me on this, before I place it on testers hands. It won’t be bullet proof but it would be best for me to get a general idea of what to expect.</p>
<p>Automation is something I had for QoD and already have it to a certain degree here, an “auto playtester”, basically a script that just does some dumb decisions and plays the game on it’s own, this doesn’t give much info but at least I can quicky test over crashes over certain periods of time, I just let it playing on it’s own. It has limitations but it’s nice.</p>
<h2 id="content">Content</h2>
<p>As I’m making importers for content I’m now starting to replace some testing placeholders with what I think will be final, in terms of mechanics and items, which is why the Testing phase will start to be important as I tweak content and also gameplay values, the fun factor of the game in a way.</p>
<p>This step is usually the one I get stuck the most, because as much as I can plan on paper, some things might not work at all when testing, also trying to keep the scope realistic for me, I’m just one person coding all this, got to be real here. I always think “oh 8 items might be too little content”, but then again sometimes less is more, as long as it’s well placed. Also being less we can always add more later if needed. Doing work unnecessarily hurts more, on Vizati and QoD locking down content amount like “7 floors max, 4 characters, 10 skills per character” really helped me early on, it was tangible and gives a sense of progression and motivation as we create each one. So that’s the sort of thing I’m trying to do here.</p>
<p>So that’s one of the reasons I’m trying to decide this stuff right now, considering the very low time and budget I have available, I’m trying to realistically get a good scope for what I can do, even if it turns out a short game (and that’s ok), match everything as close as possible to what I think I’ll need in the end, so I can decide the stage of art, where to get it, or who to hire, or even if it’s something I could do on my own (some of it anyway). Yeah I know I just described that I’m lacking a proper <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_design_document">GDD</a> 🙂</p>
<h5 id="mood">Mood</h5>
<p>So all around I feel a bit more optimistic about game5 this week, but as any game developer will tell you, this feeling goes up and down every given week xD. Sometimes I feel like I might have something here, other times “this sucks”.<br>
Until the next post!</p>
<p>post feature image from deviantArt, Halloween month! 🎃 (<a href="https://www.deviantart.com/hoshi-pan/art/witch-tea-818804167">https://www.deviantart.com/hoshi-pan/art/witch-tea-818804167</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.
So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.</p>
<p>So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.</p>
<h2 id="no-progress">No progress</h2>
<p>I haven’t been able to do make progress during the day because of contract work, so it’s mostly nights and weekends when physically possible. And I’m actually feeling a bit bad about this, so this might take a while. There’s been weeks of good productivity followed by weeks/months of just “seems to be the same”. To be honest some design decisions were also blocking me, the initial plan was enough to start but there’s always some roadblocks ahead.</p>
<h2 id="death-by-a-thousand-buttons">Death by a thousand buttons</h2>
<p>After QoD I specifically remember saying “My next game needs to have as little UI as possible”, but here we are, this game will (probably) live or die depending on how bad it is to use it. I mean the “game” part has to be fun as well obviously, but there is a lot of interconnection between both. You’ll understand what I mean by that later. No it’s not an RTS etc.</p>
<h2 id="slow-progress-is-better-than-none">Slow progress is better than none</h2>
<p>But the past 2-3 weeks I got a little lightbulb that gave me a general direction of a way to solve some stuff and it’s on a good track again I feel. And while there’s no real need for the UI to look good at this point, I already have 2 iterations of it, mostly from a functional standpoint.</p>
<p>I did a first prototype with the general idea, not all features, but turned out incredibly cumbersome to use from a UX standpoint. But this was good, I felt there was still something there in terms of “game”, just needs iteration.</p>
<p>I “quickly” remade it into a different one recently, and now I feel it’s much better, there’s still a lot to do in terms of making it coherent. But this is also the part where I feel I have to focus on the “toy” part of the game itself.</p>
<h3 id="planning">Planning</h3>
<p>A lot of my problems sometimes come from lack of planning some details more carefully, in a way it’s good to just jump in and get it rolling, but other times it comes back to bite you. With that in mind, and since I now have a general idea of functionalities and a barebones UI, I hired someone to freelance work with me on their spare time on the UI. At this point it’s compartmentalized enough that if they need to leave to other things I can carry on, and also I can focus a bit more on the gameplay components.</p>
<h3 id="iteration-and-automation">Iteration and Automation</h3>
<p>I do a lot of notes and value on spreadsheets, that end up on the game, for testing, and especially during prototype phase I found myself copying pasting values around. So I took a couple hours to write some python scripts that grab cvs, parse them and export the proper ScriptableObjects for what I need. This speeds up quick testing and changing values. I was getting tired of changing them directly on Unity inspector.</p>
<h2 id="next-steps">Next steps</h2>
<p>My next move is balancing out a initial progress/difficulty ramp. Right now I have most stuff “just there”, in a sort of chaotic way, to test out the fun of it, but I need to make a proper vertical slice. At this point I do have several mechanics in place, but a lot buggy and a bit all over the place, so I have to streamline that to make it more cohesive. I don’t have any new mechanics still missing (so far), so just cooking up a small prototype that I could just hand over to someone and have them play, and see what happens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity enshittification round 2, moving on to custom tech.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</guid>
      <description>After mostly a week of anxiety, for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity changed the rules again, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After mostly a <a href="/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/" title="The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I’m doing.">week of anxiety,</a> for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity <a href="https://blog.unity.com/news/open-letter-on-runtime-fee">changed the rules again</a>, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service. This will be impossible on mobile and consoles in a short time frame due to SDKs, but for PC should be fine.</p>
<p>So that’s good huh? Well not quite imo, because the rest pretty much maintains, more or less with some changes, Unity Plus still gone (although expected), but <a href="https://unity.com/pricing-updates">it’s a revenue/pay-per-install deal</a>, on top of the yearly license fees. I feel they fear they tainted their image so much they aren’t even forcing the Unity splash screen anymore, probably because players will now fear every Unity game will come with install tracking software.</p>
<p>I think the subscription plan, especially for mobile/consoles is needed, it’s a company and needs to make money to maintain the software, fair. However for me it’s a lot of the break of trust they did, and trying for the SECOND time (that I recall) to change the Terms of Service retroactively and only after industry-wide outrage did they backtracked slightly. So for now the new-new rules only apply to a smaller %, which I guess they expect will calm down most of the community. In a couple years they’ll pull some other stunt and we’ll recall “oh right, they did this before”.</p>
<p>Furthermore, they had deleted the transparency repo with the Terms of Service from GitHub, which raised many eyebrows, when enquired to why they deleted the answer was “low views so it was deleted”. The repo is back up meanwhile, I mean, what the heck?</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/unity/status/1705317639478751611"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-2.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<h2 id="moving-forward">Moving forward</h2>
<p>So as I mentioned in last post I have been working on a prototype for what I hope I can turn into a new game, in Unity. I decided that I’ll continue working on the prototype in Unity (actually taking a break from work right now to write this), it would be slightly silly to change now. And when I feel most of the features are done, I’ll try to move to my own tech, yes again.</p>
<p>I’ve been doing some research and tests and I’ll be dismantling <a href="/tags/quest-of-dungeons/" title="Quest of Dungeons development update">Quest of Dungeons</a> engine, which was all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming">OOP</a>, to adding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity_component_system">ECS</a>, using <a href="https://github.com/SanderMertens/flecs/">Flecs</a>, this is a major thing I’m taking with me from my time using Unity, I like that it helps solving a lot of issues sometimes, even if full ECS is not the solution for me. But having that will be nice, I can see the benefit now. Another thing might also be trying to mimick Prefabs and/or ScriptableObjects, that would be nice, but that’s just in the back of my head at the moment. I already started the process of integrating Flecs, so slowly and gradually, and hopefully, when it’s time to switch engine it will be a suitable alternative. If not well, better not update to 2023LTS I guess.</p>
<p>At least this is the plan right now, who knows, maybe I’ll reach a point where it feels too frustrating to rewrite it all in a different engine and language (c# to cpp), or ran out of budget to do so, plans do change. But at the moment at least it moves forward like this.</p>
<h2 id="list-of-mostly-open-source-game-engines-and-frameworks">List of mostly open-source game engines and frameworks</h2>
<p>Using suggestions I compiled a list of game engines and frameworks, mostly open-source and free, but there are a few with licenses, regardless, for anyone looking to test alternatives, there’s a bunch of stuff.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/DJLink/list-of-game-engines-and-frameworks">https://github.com/DJLink/list-of-game-engines-and-frameworks</a></p>
<p>My personal suggestion for anyone who wants to try the “make my own engine” approach, for 2D stuff (don’t get too deep the rabbit hole on 3D), will be to use SDL to bootstrap window creation, input etc. I’ve used that in a bunch of stuff in the past and can vouch for it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I&#39;m doing.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 11:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</guid>
      <description>So this was an “eventful” week in the game dev community. Unity, one of the most well know, and used game engines out there, after years of doing mostly good for the community, pulled a reverse card and broke years of trust the community had on them. Unity announced that they are retroactively charging (for example $0.2) for each game install, after developers hit a certain yearly revenue threshold, which sounds insane.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this was an “eventful” week in the game dev community. <a href="https://unity.com/">Unity</a>, one of the most well know, and used game engines out there, after years of doing mostly good for the community, pulled a reverse card and broke years of trust the community had on them. <a href="https://blog.unity.com/news/plan-pricing-and-packaging-updates">Unity announced </a>that they are retroactively charging (for example $0.2) for each game install, after developers hit a certain yearly revenue threshold, which sounds insane.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.unity.com/news/plan-pricing-and-packaging-updates"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unity-new-runtime-free-pricing-image.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Also they are removing the Plus subscription, which honestly this one I was kind of expecting for a while now. Which means a lot of people would have to jump to the nearly $2k yearly subscriptions. This on it’s own, while a big jump, at least is more understandable, building tech is expensive. The pay-per-install is crazy though.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link/status/1666532480646627329"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-1.png" alt=""  />
</a>On top of all, the thing that breaks trust the most, is the retroactive thing, games already released on older versions will be affected. The Terms of Service for those older versions, which developers agreed on installing X version, are no longer valid, they changed them, which means it’s no longer safe to trust the rules, Unity can just flip them. What’s for tomorrow?</p>
<h2 id="proprietary-tech">Proprietary tech</h2>
<p>This is, and always be one of the downsides of depending on other people technology, if the whole company depends on it, and there’s no easy replacement, a drastic change can hurt the whole business bad. This is not to say that we must avoid it 100% of the time, but it clearly shows that if a company amasses too much power, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy's_law">murphy’s law</a>!</p>
<p>I usually like to discuss this subject, even before this whole thing, not because I think everyone should do custom engines (even if fun) but because we shouldn’t trick ourselves in believing “my choice of engine is forever!”, it won’t be, unless it’s our own tech that we spend tons of time supporting/improving it, everything else eventually mutates too much, fades or gets killed. So we should always try to at the very least, be mentally prepared.</p>
<p>A very large amount of developers probably entered gamedev through Unity, it was mostly the goto suggestion everyone gave, and never tried anything else (and why would they, if it worked right?), but after years of learning that tool, it might be frustrating to change, but trust me, you got this. It will be hard, but if you ever change again it will be easier.</p>
<h2 id="what-im-up-to">What I’m up to</h2>
<p>Personally I’ve been using Unity for the ~5 years maybe, mostly for contract work and porting stuff. But recently, and after years of shipping stuff on <a href="/tags/basalt/">custom framework</a> I decided to work on my current game prototype in Unity, it made sense, my day work is 80% on that tech, built in Editor, multi-platform, so I would also be learning more and prototyping in Unity is generally quite fun. But these changes now mean I’ll be changing for something else, not because these rules will affect me, I don’t see ever reaching the $200k yearly, but because I don’t know what they’ll do next. I’d rather risk elsewhere.</p>
<h4 id="what-next">What next?</h4>
<p>For the past couple days I’ve trying to decide on exactly where, but haven’t made my mind yet. But I have decided that I’ll at least try to wrap up the prototype phase in Unity, makes sense, game is still a bit barebones (why I’m not talking about it yet) but there’s a lot done, so I’d rather pass the whole “toy prototyping messy code” in Unity, and when it feels time to move to production port the whole thing elsewhere and in the process hopefully have a cleaner code base.</p>
<p>Custom or another engine I’m unsure, but atm I’m leaning more towards custom, but that would mean I’d probably either reshape my entire custom engine, or do from scratch, reason being, it’s 100% object oriented, and while working with Unity I discovered there’s tons of advantages to the Entity Component System, so I want that on my framework. Might be more initial setup, but after shipping a couple games on tons of platforms in OOP, I discovered that some of the issues would have been easier to solve with ECS, not all but several.</p>
<p>Overall I’m excited about the possibility of working on my own tech, because well, it’s fun. As for my next game, progress has been slow, because I’m still taking the approach of contract work, and working on it on my spare time until it feels like a viable project and deciding full or part-time.</p>
<p>After working on Quest of Dungeons for many years (which I’m grateful) I did several prototypes that were, to be honest, not good games, and I will never ship something that at the very least I don’t find fun, so yeah sorry it’s been a while. The hope is that if I find it fun, more people will, so until that time, work moves on, maybe I’ll have more news about something sooner than later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some things to consider in multi-platform gamedev</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</guid>
      <description>Decided to write a couple things I feel can help a game in the long run when it comes to porting it to other platforms. It’s always inevitable we have to change elements in a game when targeting a new console/device we never considered, but some considerations, if done from start can save a lot of time, headaches, porting budget, and equally important, avoiding introduction of new bugs due to code changing drastically.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Decided to write a couple things I feel can help a game in the long run when it comes to porting it to other platforms. It’s always inevitable we have to change elements in a game when targeting a new console/device we never considered, but some considerations, if done from start can save a lot of time, headaches, porting budget, and equally important, avoiding introduction of new bugs due to code changing drastically. These are based on observations I made on a couple dozen projects that crossed my desk, I don’t expect this to be news for someone who’s been in the field for a while, and might even be “too basic” for many, but hopefully it can help someone, since I’ve seen these many times.</p>
<p>Many of these are not specific to a certain game engine (unless noted), so they can be used anywhere, it’s just a collection of things I’ve encountered while porting games which can help.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t hard-code strings in your code.</strong></p>
<p>This is one of the most well know ones and it’s not specific to games either, any software, but there’s still a lot of games that have it. It’s not hard to happen either, a gamejam or prototype starts, even if just a couple some strings that we leave near a <em>//todo:</em>, but suddenly we’re months in development with strings all over the place. Now you need to add another language and it’s a problem. Write some get_localization(ID) function, read all text from a file as early as possible. Also never write them directly on images, even if it looks prettier, it’s going to be a problem trust me, you don’t want image variations of each language, I can tell you first hand that becomes big problem whenever small text changes are required.</p>
<p><strong>Avoid string concatenation in localizable text as much as possible.</strong></p>
<p>If we need to mix in dynamic content with text, very common but this examples poses an issue:</p>
<p><em>string label = localize(“Our score is “) + to_string(int_value) + localize(“, which is very good!”);</em></p>
<p>This is not very flexible when it comes to localization. It assumes 2 different strings being localized, and the phrase has to make sense in all languages in this order, and that’s not always the case, what if a certain language needs the value to be in a different place in the concat order? The person localising won’t have any way to do it.</p>
<p>So let’s look at this example:</p>
<p><em>string label = localize(“Our score is {0}, which is very good!”, int_value);</em></p>
<p>Many languages have string utils to allow this, the {0} will be replaced with our variable, which means that the localisation team can put the {0} wherever they want, your code only assumes there’s a {0} somewhere, doesn’t matter where.</p>
<p><strong>Separate Accept/Back button bindings in menus from other gameplay actions.</strong><br>
Let’s say our game uses the A button on a controller to Fire a bullet, it’s also the most appropriate button for the “accept” action on a menu button. We might be tempted to only query for a “fire” action everywhere, but that’s not the best idea. First of all if you later need to change that “fire” to something else you break menus, and more, on some platforms you might need a different button, for example PS4 in Japan the X button might not be “Accept” but O instead, so you’d have to flip your mapping, having them separate prevents breaking the whole code. If you want to read more about the PS4 specific case here’s a good article about the subject <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/9/18255901/ps4-x-o-cross-circle-remap-firmware-6-50-dualshock-4">https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/9/18255901/ps4-x-o-cross-circle-remap-firmware-6-50-dualshock-4</a></p>
<p><strong>Leaving unused assets/textures on scenes/projects</strong></p>
<p>This is not necessarily a porting issue on it’s own, but can hurt performance on lower spec devices and it’s something I encountered more on Unity. I get it, it’s still development phase, something gets removed, but we leave it on the scene disabled, that on it’s own might not be a problem, but let’s say the object happens to be an entire older level that we remade better, and wanna keep the old one around “just in case”. It will be imported to the final build, all the meshes, textures etc, the level might be loaded, just not used. A variety of times I’ve seen build sizes reduce a lot just be removing unused things, but this is a more complicated process after the game is done, because they might be hard to spot, my example was an obvious one, but dozens of tiny things won’t, someone looking might just think disabled stuff will be activate later in script somewhere.</p>
<p><strong>Gigantic non power of 2 textures</strong></p>
<p>This is a recurring issue I see, a couple texture asset packs etc, really big textures, works on PC, even uncompressed. Many textures that are non power of two textures, you target another lower spec device and now there’s a problem, most engines will allow NPOT textures on their pipeline, but for example Unity won’t even allow compression, because it will only happen on POT textures, this is because, textures like 256×256, 512×512, 1024×1024, to keep it short and a bit more simplistic, is a form of optimisation for images feed in to the GPU pipeline. Many years ago most devices wouldn’t even allow something like 125×125, you’d need to find the next POT value, 128×128. A game with big textures in weird sizes will use immensely more disk space than if we use POT and some compression.</p>
<p><strong>Particles</strong></p>
<p>They look pretty, it’s easy to get distracted, don’t start by high particle count and go down until it looks good. Start by 1 and go up until it looks good. I’ve seen particle systems with 100 particles look nearly the same as a 5000 one, multiple that with a couple explosions on screen and you got yourself a problem.</p>
<p><strong>Naming controller buttons in text</strong></p>
<p>“Press A to jump”<br>
But on PlayStation it might be “Press X to jump”<br>
Inject a way in your code so that strings where you use buttons are parsed in runtime, and you can query the platform for the button itself. If it’s just a button sprite on a menu, it’s relatively easier, you just need a sprite and flip it accordingly. For written text like a tutorial or a message somewhere there are several ways to accomplish that, and one way might be to put the icons directly on a font.</p>
<p>For example<br>
“Press A to jump” becomes “Press [JUMP_BUTTON] to jump”, and then in code you can search and replace [JUMP_BUTTON] with a glyph in your font that corresponds to the right controller button. That way localization team can write it in any order, and the code simply replaces it. Another advantage of this is if instead of actual glyphs you want to write it, you can also localize it.</p>
<p>Imagine “Move Left Thumbstick to walk”, in another language we might want to change the part “Left Thumbstick” to something else, probably by console certification requirements, so having “Move [Left_Thumbstick] to walk” can help here with the string find replace, you get the idea.</p>
<p><strong>Avoid constant file saving</strong></p>
<p>Disk access even if faster these days is a big bottleneck, that’s why loading something takes, well… time. A few times I saw cases where games would save something every time a certain action happened, and I’m not talking about game progress checkpoints, which is fine, but for example a game wants to save “steps taken” for some stats, and it would auto-save a certain file every time. Needless to say, while it might not be a problem on PC (SSDs etc) even if wrong, but on certain consoles that will not only be a problem, as well as a possible certification failure. So bulk up actions to save, and save them once in a while, the ones that don’t require the player to press “Save”, you can also enforce saving on application quit.</p>
<p><strong>Framerate consideration</strong></p>
<p>If you coded the game to consider 60FPS only, not considering that it might have to be locked at 30FPS due to lower hardware, using what we can call fixed delta (time since last update) this will be a big problem. If your character movement isn’t taking into account different framerate, for example Unity has FixedUpdate() and Update(), you’ll have problems later if you can’t reach the 60FPS for some reason, everything in-game will run much slower as we only get half the updates. And this is much harder to change later in development, most of the game feel &amp; calculations might be tied into those values. This is an article explaining it from a Unity perspective but you’ll get the idea. <a href="https://gamedevplanet.com/delta-time-vs-fixed-delta-time-differences-and-purposes/">https://gamedevplanet.com/delta-time-vs-fixed-delta-time-differences-and-purposes/</a></p>
<p><strong>That’s it for now</strong></p>
<p>I’ll probably update it if I think of something else, there are many other things specific for each engine but I just tried to focus mostly on engine-agnostic stuff. If all these are covered this already helps a lot most of the port work. Let me know if you find errors or have any other suggestions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Mastodon, and why does it matter that it&#39;s decentralised?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2022/11/what-is-mastodon-and-why-does-it-matter-that-its-decentralised/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2022/11/what-is-mastodon-and-why-does-it-matter-that-its-decentralised/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; At the bottom of the article I added a couple links that help finding your Twitter following/followers on Mastodon and follow them
With the recent Twitter purchase, change of ownership and rules, a lot of people are leaving the platform or just searching for alternatives. Among other platforms one that keeps showing up as an alternative is Mastodon, but change is always hard, some people have been on Twitter for years, so what exactly makes this any different?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bn-ba-mastodon.jpg" alt=""  />
&gt; <strong>At the bottom of the article I added a couple links that help finding your Twitter following/followers on Mastodon and follow them</strong></p>
<p>With the recent Twitter purchase, change of ownership and rules, a lot of people are leaving the platform or just searching for alternatives. Among other platforms one that keeps showing up as an alternative is <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a>, but change is always hard, some people have been on Twitter for years, so what exactly makes this any different?</p>
<hr>
<p>I created a Mastodon back in 2018 but never really payed much attention to it, I have to be honest, there weren’t as many people using it back then, I lost interest a bit fast, and I never really got past the “just another social network”. But recently things changed, a LOT of people have joined, it feels more alive, and I started to look more into the decentralised nature of it, which is the opposite of Twitter centralised, and one of it’s best weapons at keeping ppl stuck there, you’ve build up a network, if you leave, it’s all gone.</p>
<hr>
<p>Ok so right now one of the problems with Twitter is, either you agree with how things are or not, but your profile is locked on that platform, if you leave all is gone, followers, posts etc, you start from scratch elsewhere. This was never particularly too much of any issue until now, I wanna keep in touch with people I follow, updates on their work, they are leaving, ideally I should be able to follow them if they leave twitter server, regardless if I wanna move or not.</p>
<p>But let’s start by the similarities, on Mastodon you can make posts (the tweets), follow people, be followed, make lists, search hashtags, post pictures etc, on the surface level, give or take, it’s more or less the same, but Mastodon gives us more control on a couple levels, but one of the best features might be the decentralisation.</p>
<p>And this is were the big differences show up, Mastodon doesn’t exist in a single place, Twitter entry point is twitter.com, everyone logins there, and everything is there, if Twitter closes tomorrow, they own all the data, everything is gone.</p>
<p>But with Mastodon anyone can make a new server, based on interests, topics, workplace, whatever. By now you might be asking</p>
<blockquote>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->But that just means everyone is a different place, multiple servers, where do I join, that sounds too much work, what if I join a server with few people or that stagnates?<br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
</blockquote>
<p>All good questions, which I made myself, but here’s where the decentralised part enters, all Mastodon servers talk with each other, so you can follow people from any server, get their notifications and talk with them, regardless of where you created your account, they are all connected. On top of that, you can migrate your account to different servers if you don’t agree with any new rules, it’s too crowded, or too empty or you just wanna go to a new one, you can even run your own server, just your account, and never be isolated, I’m following 3 people who run their own instance, and it doesn’t matter.</p>
<p>The server you choose matters for the Local Timeline, where you see a feed of all updates from anyone in the server you choose, so in my case, I joined the <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place">https://mastodon.gamedev.place</a> and I see a local timeline with a lot of gamedev content, but there is also a Federated tab, which shows updates from all Mastadon instances, like a “global feed” list.</p>
<p>So we have 3 levels:</p>
<p>–<strong>The people you follow</strong>: doesn’t matter which server they are on, you’ll see their stuff.<br>
–<strong>The Local Feed</strong>: here it will matter the server you pick, you see content of all people in your server, but don’t worry, don’t like it? Move your account to another one.<br>
–<strong>The Federated Feed</strong>: Posts from people in from the whole network related to the people you follow.</p>
<p>But you can just see the people you follow of course, you have a lot of control, nothing forces you to see stuff from people you don’t follow.</p>
<p>All this together has been very interesting to me, because that means as we grow a userbase on Mastodon, if somewhere in the future we are unhappy with the server picked, we can move, create our own and still keep our data, just elsewhere, still following the same people. It’s a different kind of concept which has tremendous potential in a future where we want to be more and more in control of our own data.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>If people you are following created Mastodon accounts there are a few tools you can use to find them, these will search their bios for Mastodon links, or even if someone you follow on Twitter used the same tool to search, which means they have an account. I used these and found several people I was following, as time passes more will join so running the tools in a couple weeks will probably bring more results. After you use it, it will export a .csv file which you can use to import on Mastodon, don’t forget to use “merge” and not “replace”.</p>
<p><a href="https://pruvisto.org/debirdify/">https://pruvisto.org/debirdify/</a><br>
<a href="https://fedifinder.glitch.me/">fedifinder.glitch.me</a><br>
<a href="https://twitodon.com/">https://twitodon.com</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mastodon_importer.png" alt=""  />
I’m not leaving Twitter for now, but I’m actively using Mastodon, can’t hurt, and it’s kind of exciting, I’m meeting a ton of new developers. I’m also using a Mastodon to Twitter cross poster <a href="https://crossposter.masto.donte.com.br/">https://crossposter.masto.donte.com.br</a>, which makes all my tweets post on Mastodon as well. You can control not to post RTs for example, which might look weird on Mastodon and vice versa.</p>
<p>If anyone wants to follow me feel free I’m <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@djlink">DJLink@mastodon.gamedev.place</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merged personal and studio blogs into one</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2022/11/merged-personal-and-studio-blogs-into-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 20:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2022/11/merged-personal-and-studio-blogs-into-one/</guid>
      <description>I have no idea how many people, if any, are still subscribed to this blog RSS feeds, but if they are, they probably saw a couple of new posts in burst yesterday, apologies.
This happened because I decided to merge all the posts from my studio into this one for “cleaning house”. I’ve been thinking about it for a while that I have these 2 blogs mostly abandoned and it’s a shame, I used to be very active, but IRL stuff and especially Twitter and QoD launch got me busy elsewhere and I mostly abandoned blogging, which I enjoyed a lot.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have no idea how many people, if any, are still subscribed to this blog RSS feeds, but if they are, they probably saw a couple of new posts in burst yesterday, apologies.</p>
<p>This happened because I decided to merge all the posts from my <a href="https://www.upfallstudios.com" title="Upfall Studios link">studio</a> into this one for “cleaning house”. I’ve been thinking about it for a while that I have these 2 blogs mostly abandoned and it’s a shame, I used to be very active, but IRL stuff and especially Twitter and QoD launch got me busy elsewhere and I mostly abandoned blogging, which I enjoyed a lot. It felt like the audiences were in other places so it made more sense. Upfall Studios blog was mostly created as I felt it needed to have a more professional look for the devlogs of all the ports I made, and it helped doing that, explaining the new features, it was a place for players to see the roadmap, and blogs are perfect for that.</p>
<p>Twitter is still a place that I enjoy (even if less these days) doing little silly posts but I’d like to revive an alternative, and I now had these 2 blogs that only I post, one for more personal stuff, the other for work stuff, maintaining both is probably not a good idea in the long run, so I moved all the studio blog posts here, so they can still exist, and redirected everything under upfallstudios.com/blog/ to this domain, under a <a href="/categories/upfall-studios/" title="Upfall Studios Blog Category">Upfall Studios category</a>, I 301 the URLS there via .htaccess, I hope I covered all, so everyone following old links should be redirected here for the blog content, there might be some weird broken images (I found a few and fixed) since WordPress is kinda weird with importing, so for any future game updates, tech stuff, or roadmaps I’ll use this space.</p>
<p>This blog has a lot of content, which for most part is now outdated (most of my XNA stuff) but I’ll keep it alive as long as I can, like a diary.</p>
<hr>
<p>With the recent Twitter changes there seems to be a lot of people unhappy and wanting to try other stuff, like CoHost, which I investigated a bit, looks like a cool mini blog sort of social network, reminded me a bit about Medium, which just reminded me again “David, you HAVE a blog, just use it”. I think the new rules of websites requiring the “must gather followers” for helping reach more people has conditioned me a lot, and usually is the thing that I (and probably more people) look into when evaluating any social website, the growth potential. But it doesn’t always have to be about that, and blogs have served me well in the past to talk about something or pass a message.</p>
<hr>
<p>In terms of work related stuff I’ll do a more detailed post eventually, but I’ve been very busy with contract work, since a while before the pandemic started in March 2020, I’ve been working in porting games to consoles, Unity and GameMaker 2, it has been a very interesting learning experience. I really like coding my own frameworks (heck this whole blog is mostly about that kind stuff), but it has been interesting to code on other engines, take inspiration, see tools that work in new modern paradigms, tech moves so fast that it’s easy to stand still, and using these tools has re-think a lot of things, that I would probably approach different the next time I decide to “code from scratch”.</p>
<p>Unity has made me go back again to C#, which was my main language during XNA time (how I miss it), and after a few years of C++ I sort of missed some of it’s things, that C++ still complicates often, even if it’s better these days.</p>
<hr>
<p>Well that’s it for now, this ran a bit longer than I anticipated, I just wanted to update on the blog merge, for any possible visitors. If you are still around thank you so much, I’ll see you next time.</p>
<p>PS: I have no idea if the comment section still works, I should test it myself to see if it does. (I should probably shape up the presentation of the site when I find the time, a lot of stuff got broken over the years, might not be suitable for mobile devices either.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons Switch Physical Release</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got several other versions and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.
One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with Leoful, it’s finally happening, and soon too, release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (begin tomorrow, March 26).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch-1024x576.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Nintendo Switch Physical"  />
</a>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got <a href="/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/">several</a> <a href="/2016/09/qod-is-now-available-on-eshop-for-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/">other</a> <a href="/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/">versions</a> and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.</p>
<p>One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with <a href="https://leoful.com/quest-of-dungeons-celebrates-7th-anniversary-with-a-nintendo-switch-physical-release/">Leoful</a>, it’s finally happening, and soon too, <strong>release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (<!-- raw HTML omitted -->begin tomorrow, March 26<!-- raw HTML omitted -->).</strong></p>
<p>This is a limited release, and for this special occasion we have a reversible cover, with the front art made by <a href="https://www.spacecoyote.com/">Nina Matsumoto</a>, and the reversible side by <a href="https://www.artstation.com/vascomarianoart">Vasco Mariano</a>, think it looks great and can’t wait for everyone to start receiving it.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Reversible and front cover<!-- raw HTML omitted --><strong><!-- raw HTML omitted -->-F.A.Q.-<!-- raw HTML omitted --></strong></p>
<p><strong>Where can I buy it?</strong><br>
[<em>PLEASE STAND BY FOR LINKS, I’LL LINK AS I HAVE THEM, UPDATE IN PROGRESS</em>]<br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Play Asia:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt">https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->NintendoSoup:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/">https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bazaar-Bazaar:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->XtraLife:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724">https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Agugames:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons</a></p>
<p><em>*Note: not in affiliation with any of the store links listed here, the order they are is random and not an indication of preference of any kind. Make sure to check where it ships from, for shipping costs &amp; possible import taxes etc.</em></p>
<p><strong>Is it region free?</strong><br>
Yes.</p>
<p><strong>Is it a cartridge or a downloadable code inside the box?</strong><br>
A cartridge, also has a reversible cover.</p>
<p><strong>How much does it cost?</strong><br>
Suggested Retail Price: USD24.99 / HKD195 / NTD710 / SGD34 (all prices exclude sales tax)</p>
<p><strong>Any differences between with the digital version?</strong><br>
Both versions contain the same content, if you already own the digital it’s the same game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/shaman_assassin_conversation_switch_cartridge.png" alt=""  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati 10th anniversary and making if free.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; Hey everyone, wow ok so first of all it’s been a long time since my last post, I keep telling myself I need to return to do more regular posts, but twitter kinda replaced it in many ways for my daily-rambles. However I’ve been trying to work on something new and gotta get back to more regular blogging, but more on that later.
Second, but not least important, Vizati is turning 10 years old today (11 June 2010), feels only yesterday we (me coding and Rita with the art) were doing the first puzzles and trying to figure out the best way for making this a fun game.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/vizati_letterbox.jpg" alt=""  />
</a>&gt; Hey everyone, wow ok so first of all it’s been a long time since my last post, I keep telling myself I need to return to do more regular posts, but <a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link">twitter</a> kinda replaced it in many ways for my daily-rambles. However I’ve been trying to work on something new and gotta get back to more regular blogging, but more on that later.</p>
<p>Second, but not least important, Vizati is turning 10 years old today (11 June 2010), feels only yesterday we (me coding and <a href="http://rita-silva.com/" title="rita-silva.com/">Rita</a> with the art) were doing the first puzzles and trying to figure out the best way for making this a fun game. Things changed a lot over the years and the original team is no longer working together, also because of OS updates, like the iOS versions etc or hardware not being around anymore the game has mostly vanished from all stores. The other day I was thinking about game preservation and thought it would be a shame to leave this only in our computers, combined with the 10th anniversary we decided to make it free to everyone, the original game can now be downloaded and played even on the newest Windows versions (thank you XNA).</p>
<p>Here’s the official <a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati" title="https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati">itch.io</a> page, there you’ll find not only the original XNA version that was being sold, but also an unfinished version using a custom engine that I build when porting it to iOS, this framework ended up powering <a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com" title="https://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a>, a game I made a few years after. It’s not finished but should be mostly playable, although only works in window mode.</p>
<p>I also created a GitHub repo, which has a couple more things, like the original website code, some screenshots, the code using for creating the XNA installer, PDF manual and a couple more things. This way those things will never get lost in case my computer + backups ever go bad.</p>
<p>Download: <a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati">https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati</a><br>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/DJLink/Vizati">https://github.com/DJLink/Vizati</a></p>
<p>Hope you have fun, either you are rediscovering the game or playing it for the first time, it’s a product of it’s time, from an inexperienced team trying to make their first indie game, but I’m proud of how it turned out.</p>
<p>See you around!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made a small game for Ludum Dare 42</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</guid>
      <description>Hey,
It’s been ages since my last post, feel like things keep getting in the way, also not much exciting stuff lately.
But decided to take a break from my current project to participate in Ludum Dare 42, it’s been years since the last time, also I liked the theme “Running out of Space” so I decided to hack something. To try and get out of my comfort zone I made my first game in Unity, so that was a fun experiment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey,</p>
<p>It’s been ages since my last post, feel like things keep getting in the way, also not much exciting stuff lately.</p>
<p>But decided to take a break from my current project to participate in Ludum Dare 42, it’s been years since the last time, also I liked the theme “Running out of Space” so I decided to hack something. To try and get out of my comfort zone I made my first game in Unity, so that was a fun experiment.</p>
<p>The game is a small top down shooting game, but when you miss an enemy you create a block instead, so the more you miss the less area to fly around. Here’s a gif illustrating.</p>
<p><a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/dont-miss"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Honeycam-2018-08-13-22-21-37.gif" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Made code, art and sounds, cod is c# in Unity, art was made in photoshop, the sound effects I think you’ll notice right away how they were made, and finally used <a href="https://boscaceoil.net/">Bosca Ceoil</a> for music.</p>
<p>There’s a webGl version so you an try it directly in your browser.</p>
<p><a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/dont-miss">https://dj_link.itch.io/dont-miss</a></p>
<p>Here’s the LD Jam entry: <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/42/dont-miss-1">https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/42/dont-miss-1</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</guid>
      <description>EDIT (09/09/2017):
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.
Hey,
So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.
Super happy to say that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>EDIT (09/09/2017):<br>
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hey,</p>
<p>So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.</p>
<p>Super happy to say that <strong>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</strong>. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away. In <strong>Japan is already releasing next week, August 10</strong>, <a href="http://flyhighworks.heteml.jp/games/">Flyhigh Works</a> is handing publishing in the Japanese territory.</p>
<p>I’ll be taking care of the rest of the world, but for <strong>Europe and America I’m still working on it</strong>, but hopefully it won’t take much more time.</p>
<p>Meanwhile a sneak peek at the new logo and the new main animation made by <a href="https://twitter.com/rephildesign">@rephildesign</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pixel_logo_v1_4x.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/character_animations_1x.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>I already got a couple questions asked via twitter so I’ll try to put here the most frequent ones.</p>
<p>F.A.Q. / tl;dr</p>
<p><strong>-Release date?</strong><br>
In Japan the game will be releasing in August 10. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->NA/EU dev still under way, I’ll update this when there are changes.<!-- raw HTML omitted --> It will be released on September 14 in Europe, America and Australia.</p>
<p><strong>-How much?</strong><br>
Same as the Wii U/Nintendo 3DS, $8.99</p>
<p><strong>-New features?</strong><br>
Yes there are some new things, there’s a new Mansion, so you have a couple more different themes and sprites. Also a new Feats system to track Achievements, there are several other optimizations/tweaks/changes, but those are the main changes.</p>
<p><strong>-Who ported the game?</strong><br>
Port was made in-house. Flyhigh Works is publishing in Japan, Upfall Studios will be doing the publishing on rest of the world.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press)I want to receive news from your studio</strong><br>
You can use the form at the bottom of the website to subscribe to our newsletter, only used for announcements etc, we don’t spam much<br>
<a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact">http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact</a>. Direct email for any other questions or inquires is listed there as well.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press) Press-Kit?</strong><br>
There is one here with screenshots, videos and some info <a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons">http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 3 years old, a small message for the community</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.
Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.
A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/quest_of_dungeons_steam_page_header.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link/status/419147399375118336"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Screenshot-2022-11-01-at-19.38.50.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</p>
<p>I wanted to take this chance to say thank you to everyone who purchased the game, who helped by making Youtube videos, streaming, recommending to friends, and all the support. If I was able to convince anyone to accept the game on their console/platform it was because the players were talking about it, purchasing and saying they cared. So while I may have built the game, without the community this wouldn’t have happen, I couldn’t have done this without you.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gKx4R.gif" alt="Hugs"  />
</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
Many of you have been asking if I’m working on something new, and the answer is yes, but it’s still a bit soon to discuss what it is, I’ll share more details at a later time. But I’m excited (although a bit nervous) to start working on something new after 4 years of dev in the same project.</p>
<p><strong>What about QoD now?</strong><br>
Although I’m moving to new projects that doesn’t mean work on QoD is completely halting. I intend to keep fixing issues with new devices/OS, this is particularly true with mobile devices which rapidly evolve. I don’t have immediate plans for new content (another popular question), but again, might happen if something makes sense to add in order to improve the game.<br>
As of recently a common question is “Quest of Dungeons on Switch when?”, and while I would love to have the game there, especially with Wii U fading out, and because the game fits well on a portable mode, the ultimate decision to have the game there is up to Nintendo. All I can say about this is that I’ll talk with them and will inform you of any changes.</p>
<p>That’s it for now, thank you for reading. As always feel free reach me via twitter, email, etc. Until the next update.<br>
-David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is out now on PlayStation 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 10:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</guid>
      <description>It’s here, it finally happened! Quest of Dungeons is finally out for PlayStation 4 😀
PS4 dashboard showing Question of Dungeons
First of all, here are the links for the respective stores, you can also just search for the game and it should show on PSN Store.
US PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
EU PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
Since I did this in the past, I decided to find a review video on Youtube that goes into detail about the game running on PS4, this should cover all things, so you can decide if this is a game that you might enjoy or not.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s here, it finally happened! <strong>Quest of Dungeons is finally out for PlayStation 4</strong> 😀</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/qod_ps4_no_name.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->PS4 dashboard showing Question of Dungeons<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>First of all, here are the links for the respective stores, you can also just search for the game and it should show on PSN Store.</p>
<p><strong>US PSN Store:</strong> <a href="https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001">https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001</a><br>
<strong>EU PSN Store:</strong> <a href="https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001">https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_01.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_01-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_09.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_09-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_05.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_05-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_14.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/PS4_Image_14-768x432.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Since I did this in the past, I decided to find a review video on Youtube that goes into detail about the game running on PS4, this should cover all things, so you can decide if this is a game that you might enjoy or not.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lAqTpf9Tl5g" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I want to thank everyone for all the support while this was being made, really appreciate that.<br>
As always you can reach me anytime via twitter or email and I’ll get back asap.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
