<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upfall Studios on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/categories/upfall-studios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upfall Studios on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/categories/upfall-studios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons Switch Physical Release</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got several other versions and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.
One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with Leoful, it’s finally happening, and soon too, release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (begin tomorrow, March 26).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</guid>
      <description>EDIT (09/09/2017):
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.
Hey,
So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.
Super happy to say that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 3 years old, a small message for the community</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.
Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.
A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is out now on PlayStation 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 10:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/</guid>
      <description>It’s here, it finally happened! Quest of Dungeons is finally out for PlayStation 4 😀
PS4 dashboard showing question of dungeons
First of all, here are the links for the respective stores, you can also just search for the game and it should show on PSN Store.
US PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-us/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=UP1670-CUSA06182_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
EU PSN Store: https://store.playstation.com/#!/en-gb/games/quest-of-dungeons/cid=EP1656-CUSA04830_00-QUESTDUNGEPS0001
Since I did this in the past, I decided to find a review video on Youtube that goes into detail about the game running on PS4, this should cover all things, so you can decide if this is a game that you might enjoy or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to PlayStation 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/11/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-playstation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 08:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/11/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-playstation-4/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: Release date will be January 17th 2017!
Exciting news, Quest of Dungeons is on it’s way to PlayStation 4!!
It’s actually been in development for some time, and it’s very near completion, so it’s not going to be a huge wait until release hopefully.
The official QoD page on PlayStation went live just now so I decided it was a good time to let you know that this is happening, since I’ve been getting questions about a PS4 version for some time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD is now available on eShop for Nintendo 3DS and Wii U</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/qod-is-now-available-on-eshop-for-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 07:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/qod-is-now-available-on-eshop-for-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</guid>
      <description>The day has finally arrived!!
Quest of Dungeons is now available in EU and US for your Wii U and/or Nintendo 3DS. If you search for the name on eShop in our device it should appear.
Game costs $8.99/€8.99 and allows for cross buy, so if you buy the game for Wii U you’ll get the Nintendo 3DS version for free (and vice-versa).
US Links
Wii U
Nintendo 3DS
EU Links</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons also coming to Nintendo 3DS on September 29</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-on-september-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 09:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/09/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-on-september-29/</guid>
      <description>I have great news.
Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo 3DS on September 29.
A couple weeks ago I announced that QoD was being released for Wii U on September 29 but I didn’t had a specific release date for the Nintendo 3DS version.
I spent the last few weeks trying to sort all know issues on the Nintendo 3DS version and I’ve been working with Nintendo to see if it can be released at the same time as the Wii U version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons coming to Wii U on September 29</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/08/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-wii-u-on-september-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 08:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/08/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-wii-u-on-september-29/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I have some good news,
I just got confirmation of the final release date for Quest of Dungeons on Wii U, it’s coming on September 29, both Europe and America. So we are nearly there, “hype.jpg”.
Quest of Dungeons Wii U
F.A.Q. -Does it have off-TV support?
Yes, you can play with the GamePad only.
-Does it support Wii U Pro Controller?
Yes.
-What does the GamePad screen shows?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons for Nintendo 3DS screenshots</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/07/quest-of-dungeons-for-nintendo-3ds-screenshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/07/quest-of-dungeons-for-nintendo-3ds-screenshots/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys, here are some screenshots of Quests of Dungeons for Nintendo 3DS. Hope you like it. Stay tuned for some news soon.
Nintendo 3DS is a trademark of Nintendo. © 2011 Nintendo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD 3DS/Wii U port devlog 1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 08:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/05/qod-3dswii-u-port-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>So how are the Nintendo ports coming along?
It’s been sometime since I announced Quest of Dungeons for 3DS and Wii U, so it’s time to talk about what’s been happening in the “backstage”.
I’m working on both versions at the same time, potentially for a simultaneous release. But this adds some extra challenges since both are very different and well, I’m juggling between two ports on my own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/02/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 17:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/02/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/</guid>
      <description>Nintendo fans rejoice!!!
It’s time to reveal what I’ve been up to lately, I’ve been very cryptic on Twitter about what I was actually doing but it was for a good cause, because Quest of Dungeons is making it’s way on to Nintendo 3DS and Wii U.
Development started a couple months ago, so I still don’t have an ETA, but from now on I can be less vague to what I’m really doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons reviews roundup</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/10/quest-of-dungeons-reviews-roundup/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone,
Quest of Dungeons was released on Xbox One exactly a month ago, and the response has been very positive from both players and reviewers, so I decided to list a couple review links here. There are several more, and tons of Youtube videos, so thank you all for helping spreading the word.
9/10 – Xbox Tavern
8.1/10 – Sticky Trigger
8/10 – What’s Your Tag
8/10 – ICMX</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your own QoD Xbox One controller</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/make-your-own-qod-xbox-one-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/make-your-own-qod-xbox-one-controller/</guid>
      <description>A lot of you asked me how they could have their Xbox One controller to look like this
So today I’m sharing the template that you can use to print your own controller 😀
Start by downloading this image: (Right click, open in new tab, Hi-res download)
For my own controller I used a website called decalGirl, but use whatever similar service you prefer or a local store if you have it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available on Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available-on-xbox-one/</guid>
      <description>It’s alive!!!!
Quest of Dungeons finally landed on the Xbox One, and it’s available to buy right NOW!!
Xbox Store link: https://store.xbox.com/en-US/Xbox-One/Games/Quest-of-Dungeons/c5fc3166-ea13-4a23-becb-9e52ed638652</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons coming to Xbox One on September 4</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 18:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone!
You know that thing you’ve been asking me these past few weeks? I finally have a release day.
I’m very pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Xbox One on September 4th via the ID@Xbox self-publishing program.
After months of development I’m very excited to finally be able say that it will be available on your console on that day.
Quest of Dungeons is a turn based roguelike game, featuring that good old 16-bit art style we grew up with.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
