<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Devlog on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/devlog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devlog on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/devlog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #2</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But onto &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/&#34; title=&#34;game5 devlog #1&#34;&gt;game5&lt;/a&gt; progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;importers&#34;&gt;Importers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&amp;gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them. I could have made the game parse the spreadsheet at boot time and create them, but I decided against it, I want to generate this process offline. One of the reasons is because I have more control over not replacing existing items GUIDs (to keep and existing links), and also I can tweak any individually generated files manually, if I need to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.</p>
<p>But onto <a href="/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/" title="game5 devlog #1">game5</a> progress.</p>
<h2 id="importers">Importers</h2>
<p>I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them. I could have made the game parse the spreadsheet at boot time and create them, but I decided against it, I want to generate this process offline. One of the reasons is because I have more control over not replacing existing items GUIDs (to keep and existing links), and also I can tweak any individually generated files manually, if I need to.</p>
<h2 id="testing-amp-automation">Testing &amp; Automation</h2>
<p>As I start to get more pieces onto the game I’m hitting the time that I need to start testing what I do, obviously with beta testers etc, but also I need to find a way to test it on my own in an effective way. For bugs, balance and well, fun factor.</p>
<p>I recall for Quest of Dungeons I had several spreadsheets with the game combat formulas and it would show up curves of progression for each character stat as it levelled up, this helped me visualising pros and cons of each one of them. And even other stuff, like how many total XP points one could get by each floor, or gold, so even with the procedural nature, I knew lower and upper bounds.</p>
<p>That meant that even if I never ended up getting a really good, or bad combination of items during my tests, I could see the best and worst case, and I would tweak monsters and boss fights accordingly.</p>
<p>This leads me to this game, where given it’s nature of it’s progression, I’m still unsure of the best tools I can cook up to help me on this, before I place it on testers hands. It won’t be bullet proof but it would be best for me to get a general idea of what to expect.</p>
<p>Automation is something I had for QoD and already have it to a certain degree here, an “auto playtester”, basically a script that just does some dumb decisions and plays the game on it’s own, this doesn’t give much info but at least I can quicky test over crashes over certain periods of time, I just let it playing on it’s own. It has limitations but it’s nice.</p>
<h2 id="content">Content</h2>
<p>As I’m making importers for content I’m now starting to replace some testing placeholders with what I think will be final, in terms of mechanics and items, which is why the Testing phase will start to be important as I tweak content and also gameplay values, the fun factor of the game in a way.</p>
<p>This step is usually the one I get stuck the most, because as much as I can plan on paper, some things might not work at all when testing, also trying to keep the scope realistic for me, I’m just one person coding all this, got to be real here. I always think “oh 8 items might be too little content”, but then again sometimes less is more, as long as it’s well placed. Also being less we can always add more later if needed. Doing work unnecessarily hurts more, on Vizati and QoD locking down content amount like “7 floors max, 4 characters, 10 skills per character” really helped me early on, it was tangible and gives a sense of progression and motivation as we create each one. So that’s the sort of thing I’m trying to do here.</p>
<p>So that’s one of the reasons I’m trying to decide this stuff right now, considering the very low time and budget I have available, I’m trying to realistically get a good scope for what I can do, even if it turns out a short game (and that’s ok), match everything as close as possible to what I think I’ll need in the end, so I can decide the stage of art, where to get it, or who to hire, or even if it’s something I could do on my own (some of it anyway). Yeah I know I just described that I’m lacking a proper <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_design_document">GDD</a> 🙂</p>
<h5 id="mood">Mood</h5>
<p>So all around I feel a bit more optimistic about game5 this week, but as any game developer will tell you, this feeling goes up and down every given week xD. Sometimes I feel like I might have something here, other times “this sucks”.<br>
Until the next post!</p>
<p>post feature image from deviantArt, Halloween month! 🎃 (<a href="https://www.deviantart.com/hoshi-pan/art/witch-tea-818804167">https://www.deviantart.com/hoshi-pan/art/witch-tea-818804167</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.</p>
<p>So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.</p>
<h2 id="no-progress">No progress</h2>
<p>I haven’t been able to do make progress during the day because of contract work, so it’s mostly nights and weekends when physically possible. And I’m actually feeling a bit bad about this, so this might take a while. There’s been weeks of good productivity followed by weeks/months of just “seems to be the same”. To be honest some design decisions were also blocking me, the initial plan was enough to start but there’s always some roadblocks ahead.</p>
<h2 id="death-by-a-thousand-buttons">Death by a thousand buttons</h2>
<p>After QoD I specifically remember saying “My next game needs to have as little UI as possible”, but here we are, this game will (probably) live or die depending on how bad it is to use it. I mean the “game” part has to be fun as well obviously, but there is a lot of interconnection between both. You’ll understand what I mean by that later. No it’s not an RTS etc.</p>
<h2 id="slow-progress-is-better-than-none">Slow progress is better than none</h2>
<p>But the past 2-3 weeks I got a little lightbulb that gave me a general direction of a way to solve some stuff and it’s on a good track again I feel. And while there’s no real need for the UI to look good at this point, I already have 2 iterations of it, mostly from a functional standpoint.</p>
<p>I did a first prototype with the general idea, not all features, but turned out incredibly cumbersome to use from a UX standpoint. But this was good, I felt there was still something there in terms of “game”, just needs iteration.</p>
<p>I “quickly” remade it into a different one recently, and now I feel it’s much better, there’s still a lot to do in terms of making it coherent. But this is also the part where I feel I have to focus on the “toy” part of the game itself.</p>
<h3 id="planning">Planning</h3>
<p>A lot of my problems sometimes come from lack of planning some details more carefully, in a way it’s good to just jump in and get it rolling, but other times it comes back to bite you. With that in mind, and since I now have a general idea of functionalities and a barebones UI, I hired someone to freelance work with me on their spare time on the UI. At this point it’s compartmentalized enough that if they need to leave to other things I can carry on, and also I can focus a bit more on the gameplay components.</p>
<h3 id="iteration-and-automation">Iteration and Automation</h3>
<p>I do a lot of notes and value on spreadsheets, that end up on the game, for testing, and especially during prototype phase I found myself copying pasting values around. So I took a couple hours to write some python scripts that grab cvs, parse them and export the proper ScriptableObjects for what I need. This speeds up quick testing and changing values. I was getting tired of changing them directly on Unity inspector.</p>
<h2 id="next-steps">Next steps</h2>
<p>My next move is balancing out a initial progress/difficulty ramp. Right now I have most stuff “just there”, in a sort of chaotic way, to test out the fun of it, but I need to make a proper vertical slice. At this point I do have several mechanics in place, but a lot buggy and a bit all over the place, so I have to streamline that to make it more cohesive. I don’t have any new mechanics still missing (so far), so just cooking up a small prototype that I could just hand over to someone and have them play, and see what happens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity enshittification round 2, moving on to custom tech.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After mostly a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/&#34; title=&#34;The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I’m doing.&#34;&gt;week of anxiety,&lt;/a&gt; for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.unity.com/news/open-letter-on-runtime-fee&#34;&gt;changed the rules again&lt;/a&gt;, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service. This will be impossible on mobile and consoles in a short time frame due to SDKs, but for PC should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After mostly a <a href="/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/" title="The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I’m doing.">week of anxiety,</a> for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity <a href="https://blog.unity.com/news/open-letter-on-runtime-fee">changed the rules again</a>, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service. This will be impossible on mobile and consoles in a short time frame due to SDKs, but for PC should be fine.</p>
<p>So that’s good huh? Well not quite imo, because the rest pretty much maintains, more or less with some changes, Unity Plus still gone (although expected), but <a href="https://unity.com/pricing-updates">it’s a revenue/pay-per-install deal</a>, on top of the yearly license fees. I feel they fear they tainted their image so much they aren’t even forcing the Unity splash screen anymore, probably because players will now fear every Unity game will come with install tracking software.</p>
<p>I think the subscription plan, especially for mobile/consoles is needed, it’s a company and needs to make money to maintain the software, fair. However for me it’s a lot of the break of trust they did, and trying for the SECOND time (that I recall) to change the Terms of Service retroactively and only after industry-wide outrage did they backtracked slightly. So for now the new-new rules only apply to a smaller %, which I guess they expect will calm down most of the community. In a couple years they’ll pull some other stunt and we’ll recall “oh right, they did this before”.</p>
<p>Furthermore, they had deleted the transparency repo with the Terms of Service from GitHub, which raised many eyebrows, when enquired to why they deleted the answer was “low views so it was deleted”. The repo is back up meanwhile, I mean, what the heck?</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/unity/status/1705317639478751611"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-2.png"></a></p>
<h2 id="moving-forward">Moving forward</h2>
<p>So as I mentioned in last post I have been working on a prototype for what I hope I can turn into a new game, in Unity. I decided that I’ll continue working on the prototype in Unity (actually taking a break from work right now to write this), it would be slightly silly to change now. And when I feel most of the features are done, I’ll try to move to my own tech, yes again.</p>
<p>I’ve been doing some research and tests and I’ll be dismantling <a href="/tags/quest-of-dungeons/" title="Quest of Dungeons development update">Quest of Dungeons</a> engine, which was all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming">OOP</a>, to adding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity_component_system">ECS</a>, using <a href="https://github.com/SanderMertens/flecs/">Flecs</a>, this is a major thing I’m taking with me from my time using Unity, I like that it helps solving a lot of issues sometimes, even if full ECS is not the solution for me. But having that will be nice, I can see the benefit now. Another thing might also be trying to mimick Prefabs and/or ScriptableObjects, that would be nice, but that’s just in the back of my head at the moment. I already started the process of integrating Flecs, so slowly and gradually, and hopefully, when it’s time to switch engine it will be a suitable alternative. If not well, better not update to 2023LTS I guess.</p>
<p>At least this is the plan right now, who knows, maybe I’ll reach a point where it feels too frustrating to rewrite it all in a different engine and language (c# to cpp), or ran out of budget to do so, plans do change. But at the moment at least it moves forward like this.</p>
<h2 id="list-of-mostly-open-source-game-engines-and-frameworks">List of mostly open-source game engines and frameworks</h2>
<p>Using suggestions I compiled a list of game engines and frameworks, mostly open-source and free, but there are a few with licenses, regardless, for anyone looking to test alternatives, there’s a bunch of stuff.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/DJLink/list-of-game-engines-and-frameworks">https://github.com/DJLink/list-of-game-engines-and-frameworks</a></p>
<p>My personal suggestion for anyone who wants to try the “make my own engine” approach, for 2D stuff (don’t get too deep the rabbit hole on 3D), will be to use SDL to bootstrap window creation, input etc. I’ve used that in a bunch of stuff in the past and can vouch for it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about a 4 year game dev cycle</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 12:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.&lt;br&gt;
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questofdungeons.com&#34;&gt;Quest of Dungeons&lt;/a&gt;, which started development in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.<br>
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.</p>
<p>For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was <a href="http://www.questofdungeons.com">Quest of Dungeons</a>, which started development in 2013.</p>
<p><strong>Right now</strong> I still have one more platform to release, on Playstation 4, 17 January 2017, it passed certification, ready to be released, so for the first time in years it feels that my QoD journey is finally completing. I still intend to patch the Android port with all last updates and sure, there will always be patches and things to take care of, but it will be in a whole different way now. Until now it always felt incomplete and a never ending task that extended for months, years.</p>
<p><strong>Working for so much time</strong> on the same project can be incredibly frustrating, especially if working alone, so one thing that I’m proud of myself is that I actually finished it. You wouldn’t believe the amount of times that I said “F** it, is not worth it”. Things went good with the game, in a sense that I was able to put it on a lot of platforms and it was well received for the most part.<br>
I think I was able to find a good “niche” of players that understood what QoD was all about, with all its flaws and good things.</p>
<p>The game was never meant to be released outside of PC, heck, during the first month of development it was a Tablet only game. That led to decisions that I regretted later when porting to consoles, but also allowed me to cut corners and not caring about things that weren’t meant for a PC game early on, thus speeding up development time. I spent a lot of time just rethinking the whole interface for each new platform (except PS4 which is identical to Xbox One) and that is time consuming, not to mention specific console features, on the other hand players do feel like it was hand-crafted for their device, so there’s that. Each new platform was made possible with the previous one, so it’s not something that I can say it was a total mistake.</p>
<p><strong>Technology wise</strong>, I’ve kept using my own tech for all releases, stubbornness perhaps? And that is not without it’s caveats. With engines like Unreal 4, Unity and Gamemaker these days if feels almost ridiculous to consider building your own tech for many, but not for me, not yet anyway. I used other engines in the past, I did release my first 2 games on XNA, and after that I decided that it was time to build my own tech, so I could be more flexible and not caring if an engine is discontinued or not, that was the goal. And on that part it succeeded, the same code runs on all platforms, except for specific render, input, etc. It took work, a lot, and after so many platforms I have a better idea of things that need better abstraction, in fact for the past week I’ve been just cleaning up code for future projects, feels more robust now. But I have a bit of regret of platforms that I ported the engine and possibly will never use it again, like Wii U, maybe even Nintendo 3DS. While the others, now that the work is done I can reuse for future games, it’s possible that I’ll never use for some again, so it was an effort for a one time only, and that is a problem, one that could have been prevented by using an existent engine.<br>
I tried using Unity for 3 weeks, did some tests with GameMaker, and it was a cool experience, knowledge doesn’t hurt right? But haven’t made my mind yet about switching away from my own tech, mostly because I know it well, I can quickly changes things around for each project and mostly because I love working on that part as well, it’s fun, even if it’s just for me. I’ll revisit this if/when I need to switch to a “full 3d” game.</p>
<p><strong>So many platforms!!</strong><br>
It’s a game that’s on a lot of devices now, and there are several reasons to do so, more audience, chance to make more money, get the game more known, etc, brand recognition and proving the studio is capable of delivering. I also made it because I had the chance right now, I don’t know the future, may not be able to pull that again, also it was a chance to establish a relation with Steam, Xbox, Nintendo and Sony. My idea is to keep making games for platforms that each makes sense, but trying to cut down time between each release. It was too sparse now, because of the reasons mentioned above.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing</strong> is still something I suck at, I do have a twitter account where I talk about my games, but also about tons of other stuff, mostly movies and general day things, is that even called marketing? Too late I decided to setup a newsletter list and put it on Upfall Studios website, should have done it earlier, I got 100 people to subscribe in the last year and half, I could have way more in these nearly 7 years as indie dev.<br>
I also created a twitter account for <a href="http://www.twitter.com/UpfallStudios">Upfall Studios</a>, so it’s basically a cleaned up version of my own, just news about the games and launches, a more “professional” account I call it. Taking care of so many social stuff, twitter, facebook, etc is time consuming and doesn’t come to me as naturally as using my personal account, so that is still a problem probably. For the most part I follow devs and not “companies” even when they are indies, so that’s mostly what I like to do, chances are there are more people like me.</p>
<p><strong>Community</strong> (love you guys)<br>
I like responding to people, I don’t mind getting asked questions and I’ve answered to 100% of emails I got, either about the game or gamedev in general. I’ve taken time to meet other developers in person when they wanna ask me questions. Treat others the way you wanna be treated, easy right?<br>
I’ve been extremely luck with the players and community surrounding QoD, they are nice, active in recommending the game to friends and I couldn’t have wished for a better community. Goal is to keep incrementing the amount of course =)<br>
Never lie or go on radio silence regarding customers. There are tons of Early access games that suddenly stop and not even a goodbye post, that’s the worse part, the waiting for months to see if project is alive. They won’t trust you again, even if you switch to a different studio, they won’t forget. So if project fails explain it, if you are delayed on a patch say so. Almost all the time players will understand and be supportive. When I was making the Xbox One and Nintendo ports I had to delay the PC updates for a couple months and players were really supportive, as long as they know why you are late on some promise.</p>
<p><strong>It’s never just “X more months of dev”</strong><br>
NEVER, ever, if you think it’s just 2 more months, odds are that it’s 4 more. We suck at calculating time for the most part (or at least I do), because we conceive the game in your minds and you can see it, mostly complete, but making that happen takes much more time. PC version was delayed, both Xbox and Nintendo ports took much longer than I expected, the PS4 one was shorted, because I counted with worst case scenario but things went well at first try. In my experience completing the game 1-2 months before the release can have a positive effect, especially for a 1 man team. I finished the Xbox One version 2 months before, full approved on certification, and spent that time just trying to promote it, and was able to gather some awareness for the game. I finished the Nintendo versions just 10 days before, and even had to delay the game once, I regret now that I didn’t calculated/handled things better. Lesson learned, let’s see if I don’t make that mistake again.</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong><br>
I made that mistake in the past and I still do, I can’t separate well development time and actual life time, so I end up working too many hours, and it’s addicting.<br>
QoD was made partially at night when I still had a day job, and the last 1 and a half year in full time, but that doesn’t mean I was able to do twice as much work unfortunately.<br>
When you work for someone else you have a schedule, but if you work on your own time, it’s harder. Most people tell me it’s hard to stay focused working, and I have that problem too, but not in a way that I can’t work, but mostly because I blend in leisure time with work, and working from home doesn’t help. It’s easy to get distracted, then you feel guilty and spend a couple more hours working. And while I don’t think I’m super slow, I could be using my time better. That’s something I want to change, I don’t thing strict work schedules work well, but not having clear boundaries doesn’t either. If anyone is managing this well please let me know. Open to suggestions 🙂<br>
It’s easy to find people saying this, but I’ve now experienced it myself, when you have a problem that you can’t solve don’t spend hours on the PC, take a walk, go do something else, the solution will come to mind, seriously, it works very often. You trick your mind into something else and the other problem keeps getting solved in the background.</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
In approximately 3 weeks the PS4 version will be released, I don’t any plans for more ports so I intend to move to a new game, and honestly I’m scared, I don’t have a solid idea yet, been mostly sketching ideas or trying some prototypes, and the thought of deciding “let me spend 1-2 years” in this new game is a bit scary, “can I come up with all the money?”, “will it be good?”.<br>
I wish I had a small cool idea to try for a couple months instead of a bigger one, but as I mentioned before, QoD was also supposed to be a 6 months project that turned out into 4 years so better not force anything. I’m trying not to think of “this is gonna be a cool idea that everyone will like” and instead trying to come up again with something that I would like to play, even if others don’t like it, development flows more naturally like that.<br>
Oh and I want to take 2 weeks of proper vacations after the PS4 release, haven’t had vacations in over two years, thinking of backpacking a couple countries, it’s cheaper and it’s good “mind food”-</p>
<p>Still there? thanks for reading – David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD XO devlog 3</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 18:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/02/qod-xo-devlog-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/&#34; title=&#34;QoD XO devlog 2&#34;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt; we talked I was porting the engine to run on the actual Xbox One hardware, since them I managed to port the whole engine, it’s now running (not 100% stable), sound, rending, and input, all working. Since that part is a bit better now I decided to focus some time on new content, such as localization, the new dungeons and stuff that still doesn’t properly work with a controller.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/2015/01/qod-xo-devlog-2/" title="QoD XO devlog 2">Last time</a> we talked I was porting the engine to run on the actual Xbox One hardware, since them I managed to port the whole engine, it’s now running (not 100% stable), sound, rending, and input, all working. Since that part is a bit better now I decided to focus some time on new content, such as localization, the new dungeons and stuff that still doesn’t properly work with a controller.</p>
<p>Almost the entire game is now fully playable with the Xbox One controller but there are still a couple of things that I’m not happy, such a way to check the active buffs/debuffs and properly using ranged skills that don’t use enemy targets, like Teleport or Summon. I need to find a way to make this coherent with the rest of the game.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/qod_active_buffs.png"><img alt="qod_active_buffs" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/qod_active_buffs.png"></a></p>
<p>Another thing that I’m concerned with, is the font size on TV’s, some parts of the game are heavily text based, such as items descriptions etc, on smaller TV’s it may be hard to read, finding the right size is not easy. I’ve been considering having an option for scaling the text, but this would break all the UI, so I need to think of a way to solve this. I also need to rework some parts of the game to accommodate for TV safe areas, some televisions can hide up to 10% of the screen area, and I need to make sure no crucial UI is there, which is pretty much where the UI is on the PC version.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/dt_safe_viewing_area9.png"></p>
<p>That’s it for now, as always thanks for taking the time reading. See you on the next post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QoD XO devlog 1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 18:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/11/qod-xo-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a lot of menus and gamepad specifics related work lately.&lt;br&gt;
My first step has been to make sure all menus are easy to use with a Xbox One controller, and while most of the menus in the main screen are usable, inside the game they are not.&lt;br&gt;
Everything was made with mouse in mind at first so I decided to remake all of them again in a different way.&lt;br&gt;
The idea is that you press a button, popup a full blown menu and can use the shoulder buttons to switch tabs, DPAD to navigate items and ABXY for actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been doing a lot of menus and gamepad specifics related work lately.<br>
My first step has been to make sure all menus are easy to use with a Xbox One controller, and while most of the menus in the main screen are usable, inside the game they are not.<br>
Everything was made with mouse in mind at first so I decided to remake all of them again in a different way.<br>
The idea is that you press a button, popup a full blown menu and can use the shoulder buttons to switch tabs, DPAD to navigate items and ABXY for actions.</p>
<p>While this is still a work in progress and subject to change here’s a video of how it’s turning out.</p>
<p><em><strong>(EDIT 2022 : Unfortunately the video attached was from Vine, which is long gone, sorry)</strong></em><br>
As always thank you for such a great support, I’ll keep you posted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dary&#39;s Legend development Timelapse sample</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/darys-legend-development-timelapse-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/darys-legend-development-timelapse-sample/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working on Dary’s Legend has been my daily routine so I decided to make a time lapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a video compiled using Chronolapse, by taking a screenshot every 60s during a couple of days while I’m working on Dary’s Legend, the new game from Different Pixel. The video is being played back at 10 real minutes per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was recorded between 14-06-2012 and 30-06-2012 (some days are missing)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Working on Dary’s Legend has been my daily routine so I decided to make a time lapse.</p>
<p>So this is a video compiled using Chronolapse, by taking a screenshot every 60s during a couple of days while I’m working on Dary’s Legend, the new game from Different Pixel. The video is being played back at 10 real minutes per second.</p>
<p>This was recorded between 14-06-2012 and 30-06-2012 (some days are missing)</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STazyKAMBsE?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
