<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Development on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/categories/game-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Development on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/categories/game-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #2</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.
But onto game5 progress.
Importers I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&amp;gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.
So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity enshittification round 2, moving on to custom tech.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</guid>
      <description>After mostly a week of anxiety, for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity changed the rules again, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I&#39;m doing.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 11:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</guid>
      <description>So this was an “eventful” week in the game dev community. Unity, one of the most well know, and used game engines out there, after years of doing mostly good for the community, pulled a reverse card and broke years of trust the community had on them. Unity announced that they are retroactively charging (for example $0.2) for each game install, after developers hit a certain yearly revenue threshold, which sounds insane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some things to consider in multi-platform gamedev</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</guid>
      <description>Decided to write a couple things I feel can help a game in the long run when it comes to porting it to other platforms. It’s always inevitable we have to change elements in a game when targeting a new console/device we never considered, but some considerations, if done from start can save a lot of time, headaches, porting budget, and equally important, avoiding introduction of new bugs due to code changing drastically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati 10th anniversary and making if free.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; Hey everyone, wow ok so first of all it’s been a long time since my last post, I keep telling myself I need to return to do more regular posts, but twitter kinda replaced it in many ways for my daily-rambles. However I’ve been trying to work on something new and gotta get back to more regular blogging, but more on that later.
Second, but not least important, Vizati is turning 10 years old today (11 June 2010), feels only yesterday we (me coding and Rita with the art) were doing the first puzzles and trying to figure out the best way for making this a fun game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made a small game for Ludum Dare 42</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</guid>
      <description>Hey,
It’s been ages since my last post, feel like things keep getting in the way, also not much exciting stuff lately.
But decided to take a break from my current project to participate in Ludum Dare 42, it’s been years since the last time, also I liked the theme “Running out of Space” so I decided to hack something. To try and get out of my comfort zone I made my first game in Unity, so that was a fun experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about a 4 year game dev cycle</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 12:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</guid>
      <description>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.
For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was Quest of Dungeons, which started development in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first ever console game is out</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Hey, it’s been a while.
For the past few months I’ve been working on porting Quest of Dungeons to Xbox One, and I’m super happy that it’s finally out. It was released around a week ago, on September 4.
This took some time but I’m happy of the way the game is played with a gamepad, after a lot of changes to the UI I really feel like it was worth all the effort I put into it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestion for where to store save games</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/suggestion-for-where-to-store-save-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 09:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/suggestion-for-where-to-store-save-games/</guid>
      <description>Standards are a lovely thing, but hard to achieve, it depends on one thing, everyone actually using it, otherwise it’s just a rule no one cares about.
There is one thing that is very common to see in the “game sphere”:
Where are [X] save games located?
There are a couple of common directories used but I think as game developers we could do a bit better and using a common location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Xbox One developer now, QoD getting a port</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/im-a-xbox-one-developer-now-qod-getting-a-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/im-a-xbox-one-developer-now-qod-getting-a-port/</guid>
      <description>So a lot has happened since my last post. Even before EGX I was already in talks with Microsoft for becoming a Xbox One developer and maybe get Quest of Dungeons to XO. I was extremely happy when they accepted both, so right now I’m working on porting the game to Xbox One.
I don’t think this would have been possible without all the gamers that have played and are still playing the game, that’s what brought all the positive vibe surrounding the game, so a big thank you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indie Dev &amp; Day Job, Making it work / Building Quest of Dungeons</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 11:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/</guid>
      <description>During Gamedev Camp 2014 in Lisbon I got to talk a bit about the development of Quest of Dungeons, and some of the problems that I had making it while still having a day job.
Most indie developers don’t have enough money to work on their game full-time so they have to keep a day job in order to support it, so this is a bit of my own personal experience doing it, some of the problems that came with it and mistakes I did during the development and launch of the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Native game on Android &amp; Porting Quest of Dungeons</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 13:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/</guid>
      <description>Quest of Dungeons was made in C++ and OpenGL, it runs on Windows, Mac and Linux in native code. iOS is not a problem either since I just have a thin layer of Objective-C to access some functionality like touch, accelerometer, etc and the rest of the code just runs.
I never made anything for Android, in fact I never even used one before this, so when I decided to port QoD to it, I had no idea of what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 11:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>I’m pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is finally out.
I didn’t get to make a post on day one, and it’s been nearly two weeks since launch but these past 2 weeks have been one crazy roller coaster.
It was released on March 25th, for PC, Mac and iOS. You can get it on Steam, iOS App Store or directly from the site via Humble Store.
I released all platforms on the same day, which was something I always wanted to try, and I have to say that it didn’t went as bad as I thought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons approved on Steam</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/02/quest-of-dungeons-approved-on-steam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 21:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/02/quest-of-dungeons-approved-on-steam/</guid>
      <description>A lot of stuff happened since my last post.
I launched a GreenLight campaign for Quest of Dungeons on Jan 16 and it got greenlit on Jan 21, votes were coming in like crazy, I did not see that coming.
Some sites posted about the game, like TouchArcade and PocketGamer, which was also very cool.
So right now I’m working like crazy to implement everything from steam onto the game (Mac/PC) but I still don’t have an exact launch date, although the iOS version is 90% certain to come out this February.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons development update</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on Quest of Dungeons and I’m nearing Gold. I’m attempting to release every version on the same day, which I never managed to do before but would like to do this time.
I have both the iOS, Mac and Windows version very stable, the Mac and iOS apps were already accepted by the App Store, for Windows I’m still trying to wrap up the process of getting it on a digital store too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGL Camera 2d with zoom and rotation</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/07/opengl-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 12:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/07/opengl-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on OpenGL for some time now and one of the things that some people have asked me is how to do that 2d camera with zoom and rotation in a similar way to a post regarding a XNA 2D Camera I wrote some time ago.
Some of them where just subtracting the camera position to all objects drawn, but that’s just ‘ugly’ in my opinion. And the advantage of using a more complicated (at first glance) system as a matrix is that you can easily apply more complicated operations like scaling and rotation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puwang is running on PC, releasing it for free</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/puwang-is-running-on-pc-releasing-it-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 23:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/puwang-is-running-on-pc-releasing-it-for-free/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys,
Decided to spend the afternoon making Puwang run on Windows, really don’t know why but I did it.Took me around 3 hours, mostly because I had to add Mouse and Keyboard controls. I also added support for an Xbox360 controller to control the game, it’s very cool. You can’t use the gamepad to control menus though, sorry.
I decided to release it for Windows for free, because the game isn’t exactly designed for PC’s, has a smaller resolution, runs on window mode only and doesn’t have Leaderboards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGL 2D Independent Resolution Rendering</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/opengl-2d-independent-resolution-rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 11:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/opengl-2d-independent-resolution-rendering/</guid>
      <description>Around two years ago I made a tutorial for XNA in which you could render 2D games scaled to the current window resolution with proper letter-boxes or pillar-boxes.
As many know since then I moved to C++ and OpenGL, and ocasionally people ask me “Can you still do that independent resolution thing?”, and yes it’s perfectly possible. I’ve used this on all latest Windows, Mac and iOS, in case you are wondering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates, development and new feed url</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/updates-development-and-new-feed-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/04/updates-development-and-new-feed-url/</guid>
      <description>Almost 4 months without a post, this is the first time it happened.
It was nothing in particular that held me back, I just kept postponing and, to be honest, I only write posts when I have something I really want to write about.
Before going into the rest of the post, I would like to ask people to update my feed url on your RSS readers. I always used Feedburner to redirect feeds, and with Google Reader going down I decided to start switching, so in your new FeedsReader use this address: (&amp;lt;/feed/&amp;gt;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dary&#39;s Legend alpha released</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/12/darys-legend-alpha-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 13:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/12/darys-legend-alpha-released/</guid>
      <description>Yay, so a milestone was reached with this project. If you follow my blog you probably already know that between small projects like Puwang and other mandatory freelancing stuff my big project in hands for these past few months is Dary’s Legend, a roguelike.
Around two months ago I coincidentally bumped into a conversation about funding and the whole kickstarter thing where one of Desura staff members was participating, and while talking about my own problems funding a whole game out of my pocket he mentioned that he knew the game and that Desura’s Alpha Funding might be a good place for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puwang is out on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/10/puwang-is-out-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/10/puwang-is-out-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>So tonight, while I was sleeping, Puwang was approved and released on the App Store.
I made a small gameplay video where, directly from the screen.
and there’s another one, offscreen, on a real iDevice here
Spread the word, buy it if you like =)
App Store Link: http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?l=en&amp;amp;mt=8</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puwang - a 5 day work</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 20:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</guid>
      <description>Hi, how’s everyone doing?
So this was a different week for me. It’s been a long time that I had the chance to work on a small prototype or a 48H competition because of my work on Dary’s Legend so I decided to stop for a couple of days and do something else.
Also my cat’s been quite sick, and between the Vet and taking care of him, working on a fun project gave me more time do everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to take screenshots in opengl</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/how-to-take-screenshot-in-opengl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 16:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/how-to-take-screenshot-in-opengl/</guid>
      <description>So here’s some quick code to save a screenshot of your OpenGL game in a TGA file.
bool save_screenshot(string filename, int w, int h) {	//This prevents the images getting padded // when the width multiplied by 3 is not a multiple of 4 glPixelStorei(GL_PACK_ALIGNMENT, 1); int nSize = w*h*3; // First let&amp;#39;s create our buffer, 3 channels per Pixel char* dataBuffer = (char*)malloc(nSize*sizeof(char)); if (!dataBuffer) return false; // Let&amp;#39;s fetch them from the backbuffer	// We request the pixels in GL_BGR format, thanks to Berzeger for the tip glReadPixels((GLint)0, (GLint)0, (GLint)w, (GLint)h, GL_BGR, GL_UNSIGNED_BYTE, dataBuffer); //Now the file creation FILE *filePtr = fopen(filename.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QuakeCon 2012 - John Carmack Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/08/quakecon-2012-john-carmack-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 18:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/08/quakecon-2012-john-carmack-keynote/</guid>
      <description>I usually don’t do this, but come on, it’s John Carmack, and this 3h30m keynote given at QuakeCon 2012 is fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamedev is like a house of cards</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/gamedev-is-like-a-house-of-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/gamedev-is-like-a-house-of-cards/</guid>
      <description>It all starts so pretty isn’t it?
A clean project, a quick prototype, it works! It’s beautiful.
Now it’s time to add more features, everything is planned out, all cogs have a place to be, it goes smoothly for a while.
Now you realize other small components are needed, no problem, let’s make them…
Eventually you do need to plug them into the game itself, and that’s when the problems start, most of the other stuff wasn’t built considering these new components.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dary&#39;s Legend development Timelapse sample</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/darys-legend-development-timelapse-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/07/darys-legend-development-timelapse-sample/</guid>
      <description>Working on Dary’s Legend has been my daily routine so I decided to make a time lapse.
So this is a video compiled using Chronolapse, by taking a screenshot every 60s during a couple of days while I’m working on Dary’s Legend, the new game from Different Pixel. The video is being played back at 10 real minutes per second.
This was recorded between 14-06-2012 and 30-06-2012 (some days are missing)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dary&#39;s Legend First Teaser</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/06/darys-legend-first-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 11:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/06/darys-legend-first-teaser/</guid>
      <description>So, yeah I know I’ve been a little lazy about my blog it’s for a good cause.
We decided to release a small teaser showing what we have. I can’t stress this enough, it’s a work in progress.
I can’t find out how to embed the video with HD by default so don’t forget to see in 720p
Lately I’ve been working mostly on small UI stuff, pixel tuning every menu/button and graphical interfaces in the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xbox 360 Controller Input in C&#43;&#43; via XInput</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/04/xbox-360-controller-input-in-c-via-xinput/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 11:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/04/xbox-360-controller-input-in-c-via-xinput/</guid>
      <description>So you have that Xbox360 controller laying around and want to connect it to your game?
On XNA this is an out of the box option but if you’re using C++ you have a bit more work to do first.
First of all, you will need the DirecX 9.0+ sdk.
The includes.
#define WIN32_LEAN_AND_MEAN // We don&amp;#39;t want the extra stuff like MFC and such #include &amp;lt;windows&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;XInput.h&amp;gt; // XInput API #pragma comment(lib, &amp;#34;XInput.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screenies time...</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/screenies-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 21:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/screenies-time/</guid>
      <description>We finally released some screenshots of Dary’s Legend.
Lately I’ve been working on the light system and fog of war for the game, it’s visible on the images.
Here’s the official post but I’ve placed the images here for convenience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New game...</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/new-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 17:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/new-game/</guid>
      <description>New game, called Dary’s Legend, a roguelike, dungeon crawling type.
This is what I’ve been working on lately, and … well not much more to say.
I’ll try and do posts with relevant stuff regarding the development of the game from now on.
Going back to coding now…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do you like games to store their save data?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/where-do-you-like-games-to-store-their-save-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 12:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/03/where-do-you-like-games-to-store-their-save-data/</guid>
      <description>Quick question.
I’m trying to decide where my next game should store their save files so I decided to make a poll.
Personally I think that
C:/Users/$USER$/AppData/Local/ is a total idiotic thing.
Starting on Windows Vista there’s a pre-created “Saved Games” folder but most people seem to miss it since it’s not on the “My Documents” folder.
There’s also other possibilities which many games I own use like
My Documents\My Games\Game\ Others just create a folder directly on “My Documents” which some users find a bit obstructive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engine, video player and tools, tools tools!</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/01/engine-video-player-and-tools-tools-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 19:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/01/engine-video-player-and-tools-tools-tools/</guid>
      <description>So these past 2 weeks I’ve been adding some “bits and bytes” to the engine.
Taking a rest between some more complex game mechanisms I decided to start doing a video player.
After a bit research I decided to choose theora, but a bit skeptic, I’ve used it before on a game company I worked at and I remember being a tiny nightmare, specially because of YUV-&amp;gt;RGB(A) conversion and because of video/audio sync.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt code swarm</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/basalt-code-swarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 16:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/basalt-code-swarm/</guid>
      <description>I discovered code swarm a while ago and decided to test on my own repositories.
This is a test on Basalt, and although I’ve been working on the engine since January 2010, only in 2011 did I placed in on a repository so a bunch of stuff is added right on the beginning.
This is the result.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>something new in the horizon...</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/10/something-new-in-the-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 10:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/10/something-new-in-the-horizon/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve been out for quite some time, and this is just a quick update.
First, I have tones of unread, thus answered emails on my inbox. I haven’t managed to go through that lately. I usually scroll to see if there’s a really urgent one, I will eventually read them all.
I decided to quit my current job, my last day is October 31st. I couldn’t glimpse a very promising carrier there and I practically staggered learning-wise for the past months due to the type of work we develop so yeah, that’s it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurry you only have 16 ms to render everything</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/08/hurry-you-only-have-16-ms-to-render-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 21:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/08/hurry-you-only-have-16-ms-to-render-everything/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve been working on my new game and I’m doing some tweaks here and there on the engine.
Mainly with the rendering section, trying to squeeze as much as possible, thus maintaining an acceptable framerate. It’s not like I’m doing a heavily graphic game but I like to know that It can be used even on slower pcs and that I’m not using more cycles than necessary.
This past week and after reading a bunch of stuff and keynotes from John Carmack about Rage (60FPS ftw) I decided to measure my own stuff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Git for revision control</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/07/using-git-for-revision-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 13:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/07/using-git-for-revision-control/</guid>
      <description>If you are coding, no matter what it is, games, software, websites, you should be using a code revision control of some sort.
Are you using? Cool. Is it Git? Smart choice, so you probably don’t need to read the rest of this post.
For the rest I’m giving some help on how to start from scratch.
First of all I recommend some reading on Revision Control so that you understand what I’m talking about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So what have I learned after eight months on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 21:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>First of all I think this is my last idevblogaday post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn. Actually it’s just the 9th.
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing sound using OpenAL</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/playing-sound-using-openal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 09:22:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/playing-sound-using-openal/</guid>
      <description>For sound I use OpenAL, it’s free, cross-platform, I’ve managed to get it working on iPhone, Windows and Mac.
Setting up OpenAL to play a sound is pretty straight forward, a bit like OpenGL.
First you need to create a context.
ALCcontext *context; ALCdevice *device; device = alcOpenDevice(NULL, ALC_DEFAULT_DEVICE_SPECIFIER); if (device == NULL) { // Handle Exception } //Create a context context=alcCreateContext(device,NULL); //Set active context alcMakeContextCurrent(context); // Clear Error Code alGetError(); Now for the second part, loading a wav file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time for some new tools and editor</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/time-for-some-new-tools-and-editor/</guid>
      <description>Holy cow, this is my 100th post. “Insert epic sentence”
Depending on how much time you follow my blog or Different Pixel activity you may know that we have an internal Editor called Sapphire
Past
It was developed over a year ago with the intent of being a “All in one” 2D game editor for our games, built on XNA. It started out pretty well and I’m very happy with the outcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indie and day job, making it work</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/indie-and-day-job-making-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/indie-and-day-job-making-it-work/</guid>
      <description>A large percentage of the indie developers have to work on their project at night and/or weekends.
In order to pay the bills they have to maintain a day job. There’s no shame in that, many do it, I do it, not everyone can make a mega jump right into fame and fortune with a single project.
The rest of us mere mortals have to gradually build a fan base, learn from past mistakes, do better PR, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGL Render to Texture</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/opengl-render-to-texture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 09:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/opengl-render-to-texture/</guid>
      <description>Render to texture is a very handy functionality.
Imagine your game allows for some character customization. You have the body, some different hats, different clothes and other small stuff. Now the easiest way to render this is to just draw it piece by piece every frame. With the proper Z coordinates everything falls in place.
But you now have like 4-5 draw calls for one single object. Worse, you might have different textures and swamping textures is expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking/Identifying individual touches on iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/tracking-identifying-individual-touches-on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 12:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/tracking-identifying-individual-touches-on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>I got this question the other day, how to track individual touches if you are using a couple of fingers for a game?
Actually it’s pretty easy if you can access the touch previous position and it’s current position.
Let’s start with a small class to store the information
class Touch { public: Touch(); ~Touch(); void update_position(float x, float y){ _current_position.x = x; _current_position.x = y; } bool is_same_touch(float x, float y) { if(_current_position.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little on how to initialize and use GameCenter</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/a-little-on-how-to-initialize-and-use-gamecenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 10:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/a-little-on-how-to-initialize-and-use-gamecenter/</guid>
      <description>Small side-note first, Vizati is now available for the Super Nintendo, more info.
For my third idevblogaday post I’m going to talk about Game Center.
Game Center was released only a couple months ago (September or so) but already tons of applications are using it and even more, players ask for it.
It’s a way to track achievements, leader boards etc. Unfortunately It’s only available from iOS 4.1+, so some compatibility check has to be done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripting week</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/scripting-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 11:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/scripting-week/</guid>
      <description>This week I’ve been working on replacing my current scripting system. It worked great for Vizati but I need something with a little more flexibility.
Instead of explaining what I’ve managed to get working I’ve made a screenshot with some notes.
I think I’m going to make this my #ScreenshotSaturday</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loading images into OpenGL in iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/loading-images-into-opengl-in-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 10:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/loading-images-into-opengl-in-iphone/</guid>
      <description>So you can’t make a game without images, right? Well, actually you can but that’s another story.
But how can you load a jpg or a png and use then on OpenGLES?
First let’s make a simple class Texture2D
class Texture2D { public: Texture2D(int id, int width, int height) { _textureId = id; _width = width; _height = height; } virtual ~Texture2D(void) { // Delete Texture from HGL Memory glDeleteTextures(1, ((GLuint*)&amp;amp;_textureId)); } int getTextureId() {return _textureId; } protected: int _textureId; // The reference ID of the texture in OpenGL memory int _width; int _height; }; Now for the code to actually load the image</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing a game from PC to iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/bringing-a-game-from-pc-to-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 11:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/bringing-a-game-from-pc-to-ios/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post to http://idevblogaday.com/, I’ve been waiting since November so I’m pretty excited about writing to a broader audience =P. Even though I only have one product on the App Store I have gathered some knowledge on how stuff works to get there.
I’ll start by talking a bit about how we made our PC game Vizati to iPhone.When we started, this represented our chance of making games and putting ourselves into test.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playtesting and Tech support, the other side of the coin</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/02/playtesting-and-tech-support-the-other-side-of-the-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 12:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/02/playtesting-and-tech-support-the-other-side-of-the-coin/</guid>
      <description>Something that has always been scary (well, it’ still is) before launching Vizati is tech support.
No matter how much you tested your game, it’s bound to have bugs. Also what I’ve realized is that I don’t spend enough time testing the game, oh and you too, yes YOU (I’m assuming you’re a developer of course).
The past year I gather around a few friends who never played it to test the game for 2 days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>officially a Mac developer too, wait, what?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/01/officially-a-mac-developer-too-wait-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 01:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/01/officially-a-mac-developer-too-wait-what/</guid>
      <description>It’s little over a month since I said I wouldn’t do any more porting for Vizati. Lesson learned, don’t say never again…
When I started making the engine in C++ with an OpenGL/DirectX layer, I tried to keep in mind a multi-platform environment.
Keeping rendering and OS specific calls abstract from the game itself and the engine to a certain level was one of my goals. Easy to say, hard to accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No more porting for Vizati, time for something new</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/12/no-more-porting-for-vizati-time-for-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 10:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/12/no-more-porting-for-vizati-time-for-something-new/</guid>
      <description>It’s been awhile since my last post.
Regular visitors know that for the last months I’ve been working mainly on Vizati, bringing it first from the Xbox360 (never released, no xblig here) to a PC digital release, followed by a complete rewrite of the engine to C++/OpenGL for a iPhone port, next there was the Windows Phone 7 version. I had the iPad on a backburner since I don’t own a device and optimizing code without seeing the result is crappy but about 2 weeks ago it went gold and it’s finished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing if a point is inside a Polygon</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/11/testing-if-a-point-is-inside-a-polygon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/11/testing-if-a-point-is-inside-a-polygon/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing with polygons and collisions lately so I decided to share some stuff.
Using rectangles to detect if the mouse is inside is handy for Buttons and rectangular shaped objects, but what about other irregular shaped objects?
Taking this into account I decided to create a Polygon class that basically has a List of Vector3 points. Although I’m just covering 2D collision you should use Vector3 for a more generic class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A* Pathfinding</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/a-pathfinding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 10:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/a-pathfinding/</guid>
      <description>For my current project I’ve been working with A* as a path-finding solution.
Basically it’s a way to get from point A to point B.
This is used for AI in games mostly on tiled based games, It’s very simple to understand and implement.
As A* traverses the graph, it follows a path of the lowest known cost, keeping a sorted priority queue of alternate path segments along the way. If, at any point, a segment of the path being traversed has a higher cost than another encountered path segment, it abandons the higher-cost path segment and traverses the lower-cost path segment instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Platform engine progress</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/cross-platform-engine-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 14:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/cross-platform-engine-progress/</guid>
      <description>If you read my recent posts you know I’ve been bringing Basalt to C++.
The plan is to support both DirectX and OpenGL render API’s and OpenGLES for iOS devices. I’m tired of porting stuff so I want to make a better framework for future projects and I’ll leave the XNA branch for Xbox360 and Windows Phone 7. I really wished I had this before.
Since the iPhone branch is stable I move on to making it compatible with Win32 and MacOSX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati for iPhone is now available at App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/vizati-for-iphone-is-now-available-at-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 17:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/vizati-for-iphone-is-now-available-at-app-store/</guid>
      <description>People who follow me on twitter are probably aware, or maybe not:
After 3 months tacking an iPhone port it was finally approved by Apple to the App store and it’s on sale today!!!
Hypnotizing start…
Buy buy buy….
On the count of 3 you will feel refreshed and happy for buying this awesome game…
1
2
3
Oh right, here’s the trailer:
I’ve searched some forums and found some talking about it and that they liked, general feedback looks positive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating tombstone (suspended state) on Windows Phone 7 emulator</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/simulating-tombstone-on-windows-phone-7-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 21:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/simulating-tombstone-on-windows-phone-7-emulator/</guid>
      <description>Since Windows Phone 7 doesn’t have multitask, at least for now, Microsoft implemented a Tombstone notion in WP7 apps.
It’s basically a suspended state where you receive a notification that it’s going to suspend but there is no guarantee that it will resume, it might be terminated so you must treat this as an exit and a might start again state.
So depending on you app you might want to save the current state just in case the app really closes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another milestone reached, first App sent to Apple Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/another-milestone-reached-first-app-sent-to-apple-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 16:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/another-milestone-reached-first-app-sent-to-apple-store/</guid>
      <description>Finally and after several weeks locked inside Different Pixel “dungeon” making my engine compatible with iOS, namely with iPhone/iPod touch I submitted today my first App to the Apple Store.
The binary didn’t reported any issues so as of 15 September 2010 it’s “Waiting For Review”
I have mixed feelings about either it’s going to be approved or rejected. On one hand we tested as much as we could, handed to some testers using iPhone 3, iPhone 4 and iPod touches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPad launch images support for all orientations</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 23:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</guid>
      <description>When loading an application on an iPhone or iPad, a launch image can be shown to provide feedback to the user that the application is loading.
On the iPhone a Default.png was used, with the iPad we need to anticipate the device being started in any orientation.
Filename Dimensions Default-Portrait.png * 768w x 1024h Default-PortraitUpsideDown.png 768w x 1024h Default-Landscape.png ** 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeLeft.png 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeRight.png 1024w x 768h Default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting OpenGL view for iPhone 4 retina hi resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/setting-opengl-view-for-iphone-4-retina-hi-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 09:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/setting-opengl-view-for-iphone-4-retina-hi-resolution/</guid>
      <description>This had me scratching my head for awhile.
At first I thought that glGetRenderbufferParameterivOES would properly detect Retina screen at 960×640 but it keeps returning 480×320.
A little explanation on Retina screen first. Older devices have 320×480 screen resolution. With new iPhone 4 and iPod Touch 4G the screen has 640×960 but on the same physical area. This means that each pixel is 4 times as small.
To properly simulate older games resolutions iOS will replace each of your 320×480 game pixel by 4, this way your game will look identical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targetting iOS devices hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 12:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I decided to compile all iOS devices specs here so we can get a better glimpse on their hardware and what we can expect from them.
This covers iPhones, iPod Touches and iPad.
iPhone/iPhone 3G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPhone 3GS – 600 MHz / 256MB / 320×480
iPhone 4 -~800MHz / 512MB / 640×960
iPod Touch 1G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPod Touch 2G – 532 MHz / 128MB / 320×480</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone OpenGL screen orientation using the accelerometer</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/iphone-opengl-screen-orientation-using-the-accelerometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 14:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/iphone-opengl-screen-orientation-using-the-accelerometer/</guid>
      <description>Even tough it’s not mandatory to support all screen orientations it’s always nice to support at least 2 of them.
Let’s imagine your game is landscaped, by some reason the user may want to use either with the home button on the left or on the right. Most games support this, if you flip the device, the game will too.
I’ve been using OpenGL to support the device orientation, most people on forums want an automatic solution, but belive me, it’s best that you have control on this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developers log stardate 26082010</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/developers-log-stardate-26082010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 19:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/08/developers-log-stardate-26082010/</guid>
      <description>It’s been awhile since I last updated this, I’ve have my hands full with Vizati iPhone.
Ever since I got an IPod Touch 2G it was easier for Rita to get a sense of the screen size (although we knew to be 320×480) it’s different when you are testing on the real thing, text looks smaller, other stuff looks way too big.
Here’s a picture she took after a few adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are your target platforms for games?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 20:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</guid>
      <description>I decided to run a little poll to track what platforms do you target as a game developer. I think this should be interesting. Please share this post link or the direct link to the poll (http://twtpoll.com/dar51l) so that we can have more accurate results.
The poll closes in about 6 days and you can select various options of course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing dark borders sprites on iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 12:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>I ran into this issue a couple hours ago working on the iPhone sdk:
See the darker borders around the image?
It’s a png image and that’s was supposed to be a gradient of alpha. So why am I getting this strange stuff around it?
Well that’s because that alpha isn’t 0 or 1 or 0 or 255.
The first thing I found out is that XCode grabs the png images and multiplies the RGB component with the alpha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing on Mac and Basalt running on the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/developing-on-mac-and-basalt-running-on-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/developing-on-mac-and-basalt-running-on-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>It’s been around two weeks since my last post. Basically because I’ve been busy porting my engine Basalt to iPhone/iPad.
If you follow me on twitter you might have known this already since I ranted pretty much at start, moving platform and language is always painful if you are used to other conventions/shortcuts etc.
So it all started with my wish to port Vizati to the iPhone, since the game is already running on PC, Xbox360 and Windows Phone 7 one can only wish for an easy and quick port since pretty much all base code is done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need XBOX Live Indie Games in Portugal!!</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/we-need-xbox-live-indie-games-on-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 18:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/we-need-xbox-live-indie-games-on-portugal/</guid>
      <description>See the little black country on the map? It’s Portugal. The green zone are countries around Portugal that have XBOX Live Indie Games. We are surrounded by countries that can place their games on Creator’s Club but we were left behind. I won’t say there aren’t many others but they can speak for themselves.
I’m tired of watching developers from other countries being able to place their games there and we have to sit and watch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a XNA Game Installer</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/making-a-xna-game-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 22:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/making-a-xna-game-installer/</guid>
      <description>I am going to start with a little rant about Visual Studio default Installer, you know, the one you can make for yout XNA games inside VS. Ugly and not very handy, sure it installs every dependency but doesn’t leave many options like….hum…I don’t know choosing the location where you want to install?
Moving along…I discovered this little cool installer called InnoSetup, and best of all it’s free.
InnoSetup has different ways of you building a proper installer but I am going to cover the script way, much more control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who wants to try Vizati Demo?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/who-wants-to-try-vizati-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 22:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/who-wants-to-try-vizati-demo/</guid>
      <description>Ok, I know I’ve been making far too much posts about Vizati but this time it’s for a good reason, anyone interested in trying out the game can do it…right about NOW…
http://www.differentpixel.com/2010/06/vizati-demo-available/
Also on a quick update, yesterday I had the chance to test Vizati at Windows Phone 7 Developer’s Hub on a real WP7 device, which was awesome. I want to thank João Antão, Nuno Costa, Ben Riga and Neil Hutson for the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A good Reference system can help your game</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/a-good-reference-system-can-help-your-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 09:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/06/a-good-reference-system-can-help-your-game/</guid>
      <description>How many times has it happened where you have this one class, let’s say it’s a spaceship that was destroyed.
Now you have tell all other dependent objects that she died, any independent sprite animation class, AI, etc etc because they were relying on her. Another thing is, in my case, having a scene that contains all the objects and by deleting the ship It won’t get removed from the scene, keeping the reference alive and so Garbage collector won’t kick in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yay, my first Game as Indie Developer is almost out</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/yay-my-first-game-as-indie-developer-is-almost-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 20:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/yay-my-first-game-as-indie-developer-is-almost-out/</guid>
      <description>No, I’m not dead….yet…
It’s just that I’ve been stuck on Different Pixel development dungeon for the past weeks finishing and polishing (bug hunting) my first game, Vizati.
Most of you have been following the process and asking things every since we showed the beta version at XNA Pizza Night, after which we decided to finish the game and try to sell it to see how it goes.
Three months later and here I am, making the final touches on the game before it’s release on 11th June.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati on Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/vizati-in-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 20:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/05/vizati-in-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>It’s been awhile since my last post. I’ve been utterly busy so I haven’t had the time for any tutorials.
This week I got an invitation from João Antão to showcase Vizati as part of his XNA Framework presentation. This occurred during the Imagine Cup final on Portugal.
I’ve been playing with the WP7 tools and I decided to try and port Vizati to XNA 4.0 and give it a try on the emulator so I could show all 3 versions running simultaneous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Big Grass Tiled Backgrounds in XNA</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/04/making-big-grass-tiles-in-xna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/04/making-big-grass-tiles-in-xna/</guid>
      <description>I’ve seen this quite a bit around on XNA forums and got 2 emails last week asking about this:
I want to make a 3000×3000 grass background by tiling this small grass image I have. Should I make one big image or should I make a for cycle drawing the image (3000/TileSize) times?
My answer is neither of them. The big image has a huge impact on every Draw and more, you are limiting your map to the max Texture Size the graphic card can handle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA 2D Independent Resolution Rendering</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-2d-independent-resolution-rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 22:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-2d-independent-resolution-rendering/</guid>
      <description>Note: 22/04/2013 – Due to popular request I made an article about achieving this effect in OpenGL
Independent Resolution Rendering?? What’s this all about?
Basically a way of not caring what you resolution is. Ever had Gui elements misplaced because you changed the resolution? Or getting out of the screen?
If you are doing a game on Xna just for Xbox360 you can basically use a 1280×720 base resolution and the Xbox will scale the game for you making the proper Letterbox.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA 4.0 CTP and Windows Phone Developer Tools CTP now available for download</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-4-0-ctp-and-windows-phone-developer-tools-ctp-now-available-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 23:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/xna-4-0-ctp-and-windows-phone-developer-tools-ctp-now-available-for-download/</guid>
      <description>So I was watching Microsoft Mix10 and while talking about the new Windows Phone 7 Series, Scott Guthrie announced the availability of the Windows Phone Developer Tools CTP. What? But like now now?
I went to http://developer.windowsphone.com/ and XNA Creator’s Club and there it was. The packages contains:
A CTP of the new Visual Studio 2010 Express for Windows Phone Tools and framework to develop Windows Phone applications and games with Silverlight A CTP of XNA Game Studio 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati wins XNA Pizza Night 2010</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/vizati-wins-xna-pizza-night-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 10:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/03/vizati-wins-xna-pizza-night-2010/</guid>
      <description>Damn you should see my face when they told me we won the competition XNA Pizza Night 2010 at Microsoft.
Originally we developed Vizati to enter Dream Build Play 2010. We started developing the game on the beginning of February and during that month we discovered another competition would be held near Dream Build Play deadline.
We went there with the same demo we sent to DBP. The audience really liked the game and we got very positive feedback.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati Teaser</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/vizati-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 23:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/vizati-teaser/</guid>
      <description>Rita and I have been working on a demo for entering Dream Build Play competition and today she has finally finished the teaser for Vizati. It’s our game for entering the Dream Build Play 2010 competition and XNA Pizza Night. We started working on this around 3 weeks ago so it’s still an early draft from our vision of the game.
Vizati is a puzzle game made by Different Pixel for Dream Build Play 2010 in which you need to connect the little vizati stones by color.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA Particle System 2D</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/xna-particle-system-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 11:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/xna-particle-system-2d/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a long week.
Even though I’ve always pointed to a make a very simple game for Dream Build Play so that I may actually have the time to finish it I just lost almost two day doing something to show for about 3 or 4 seconds per level. Discussing how we should make our puzzle appear and disappear between each level we decided that a particle system or an effect of such nature would be nice to show apart from some fading or something on the puzzle itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I maed a Custom Script Language for my Xna Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/i-maed-a-custom-script-language-for-my-xna-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/02/i-maed-a-custom-script-language-for-my-xna-engine/</guid>
      <description>Well the title is an Homage to James Silva‘s I MAED A GAM3 W1TH Z0MB1ES!!!1
I’ve been really busy with my Dream Build Play game lately. Although being a simple game somethings always turn out to be harder that we initial think. I’ve been debating myself with some bugs on my engine, had to redo tons of code yesterday due to XBOX360 compatibilities (should have tested earlier :P). Two days ago Rita started doing the assets and it’s looking really good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Lines in XNA</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/01/drawing-lines-in-xna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/01/drawing-lines-in-xna/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I realized is very handy when prototyping or debugging is to draw a line on a specific location. Like drawing lines around collision boxes to see if your character is making a proper collision. For my games I’ve made a small LineBatch.
Basically LineBatch uses a SpriteBatch to draw the lines by stretching a 1×1 white Texture2D to your line size.
You can give it 2 points ( start and end point of course) and a color.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xna Screen Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/01/xna-screen-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 18:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/01/xna-screen-manager/</guid>
      <description>I know there’s lot’s of this stuff over the internet but I keep bumping into people asking for this.
A way to easily switch from a Game Screen to a Menu or Options without having tons of flags and “if” clauses on the class Game.
I’ve made a small project with a Screen Manager. The ScreenManager is static and can contain Screens. Instead of having typical Draw Update functions drawing SpriteBatches on the Game class we should have something like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt and Sapphire Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 21:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/12/basalt-and-sapphire-updates/</guid>
      <description>Lately all my free time has been spent adding new features to Basalt and developing Sapphire.
Some months ago, I started building Sapphire, a 2D editor for helping me creating to create my maps. Unfortunately I made a bad choice and decided to integrate XNA with Windows Forms, although I managed to do it it was a real pain to add something simple and eventually I dropped it.
Here’s a screenshot of the previous alpha version:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to do a XNA fps counter</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/how-to-do-a-xna-fps-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 17:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/how-to-do-a-xna-fps-counter/</guid>
      <description>Frame rate or FPS, how it is most commonly known is a way for you to know how many images per second is you game drawing. The more the better. Less then 30 and you start to see hiccups.
So how can you measure your frame rate in XNA?
Inside your game1 class declare these vars:
SpriteFont _spr_font; int _total_frames = 0; float _elapsed_time = 0.0f; int _fps = 0; On function LoadContent() do</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to do a Xna Log file</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/how-to-do-a-xna-log-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 10:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/how-to-do-a-xna-log-file/</guid>
      <description>Although the title says XNA log file this is actually a C# log file, I’ve just thrown this title cause lot’s of people search for xna log instead of C# log file.
Many have asked me why take time to do a log file when you can throw exceptions when something goes wrong. Well the answer is simple, to keep track of what’s happening, log steps, write to the file exactly what when wrong even if you are on Release mode, and more, if someone complains the game is crashing you simply ask for the log file and see what when wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using PerfHUD with XNA</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/using-perfhud-with-xna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 15:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/using-perfhud-with-xna/</guid>
      <description>I am definitely a fan of ATI cards. Had a few Geforces but didn’t liked them very much. I actually noticed image quality decrease when switching from an old Radeon 9800 to a Geforce 8k something. I’m very happy with my Radeon 4890, now for the downside, PerfHUD, a very handy tool for Game Developers is only available for NVIDIA chipsets and although ATI has it’s own GPUPerfStudio it’s not the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unreal Engine 3 is now free</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/unreal-engine-3-is-now-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 15:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/11/unreal-engine-3-is-now-free/</guid>
      <description>Epic decided to offer Unreal Engine 3 for free to non-commercial applications. Sounds kind of weird considering it’s one of the best and most licensed engine out there, but maybe the recent release of Unity 3d free for all uses made them consider this option.
Named UDK (Unreal Development Kit) you can download it here and have access to all tools and features that the full commercial Engine contains, well, except for the source code of course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prototype for xna7day competition</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/prototype-for-xna7day-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 12:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/prototype-for-xna7day-competition/</guid>
      <description>I decided to make a game for the xna7day competition, in which we have to make a game that only uses 2 keys, so absolutely no analog input and it has to be built on xna of course.
This is a great opportunity to test my engine Basalt.
I decided to make a puzzle game, basically the rules are the same of a 3 in line game.
This is what I have so far.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an 2D Game Engine in XNA - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/building-an-2d-game-engine-in-xna-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/building-an-2d-game-engine-in-xna-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I decided to starting writing a series of tutorials for building an 2d XNA game engine.
Keep in mind that while the main focus is 2d nothing prevents us from adding the 3d stuff later but for now we will stick to 2D.
It’s not very original but I’ll call this the Bay Engine. If anyone else has a better idea let me know.
Requirements:
You must have some Object Oriented Programming background to full understand what we will do here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA Camera 2d with zoom and rotation</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/xna-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/xna-camera-2d-with-zoom-and-rotation/</guid>
      <description>07/01/2011 – By popular request updated to XNA 4.0, xna 3.1 code is still there too
One of the things I keep finding is people asking how to do a simple camera 2d in XNA. Today I decided to contribute with my own solution.
Most of the time the solution given is to have a class camera with a Vector2 position and when drawing the sprite batch to subtract the camera position to the sprite position itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basalt gains a media player</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/basalt-gains-a-media-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 18:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/basalt-gains-a-media-player/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve been working on a sort of media player in order to play movies on my 2d engine Basalt made on top of XNA.
By extending my class Object2d I manage to get this pretty cool result. You can even apply shaders to it. Since I extended the class from Object2d I can rotate, scale and set a position to the video besides regular options like play/pause, fullscreen etc. For those who don’t know the video playing is a chunk of the series Naruto Shippuuden</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Competition</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/09/game-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/09/game-competition/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I decided to launch a new website with a 48h Game Competition.
We are now 2 days away from the Compo#1. This is for every indie game developer wannabe =)
[Edit]
The first competition is now over. Check the results here
One of the games made in the competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XNA Sprite Sheet</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-sprite-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 10:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-sprite-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I decided to take the morning to make a small sprite sheet editor for our Xna engine. This way the artist can easily define the sprite areas and their origin saving in a file that can later on be loaded on the engine.
Not very fancy yet but it gets the job done.
Next step will be making an animator editor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xna 2d Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/xna-2d-engine/</guid>
      <description>Lately whenever I’m off work and I have the time I’ve been working on a 2d Engine in XNA. We named it Basalt.
Cool hum? lol
I have almost everything done, since sprites, to sprite animations, scenes, layers, resolution independent engine, game state and a lot of other cool things.
On a recent post I’ve showed a 4 split screen prototype, that was made in Basalt.
Also I’ve been working, even though on a slower pace on Shappire, the editor and a sprite sheet editor, for the animations etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DBP deadline is over, maybe next year.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/dbp-deadline-is-over-maybe-next-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 15:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/dbp-deadline-is-over-maybe-next-year/</guid>
      <description>Dream Build Play submission deadline is over. Unfortunatly I didn’t had the time to put my prototype working. Maybe next year. I always had the impression I would finish it on time cause the main goal was always IGF.
Meanwhile I’ve been busy making the arrangements for The Indie Bay 48 hour game development competition.
The idea is for every entrant to make a game in 48 hours using a given theme or topic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pugna prototype</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/pugna-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/08/pugna-prototype/</guid>
      <description>Hello there.
Yes i know I haven’t updated in awhile, I’ve been really busy. So the deadline for Dream Build Play is 5 days from now and up till yesterday I haven’t made anything.
My goal was to have a prototype by now to submit to DBP, but I ain’t got anything. So today I decided to see what I could do from scratch, and not related to the main idea that Rita and I have for the game we should have submitted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Contests</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/05/game-contests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 14:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/05/game-contests/</guid>
      <description>I finally decided to compete on IGF. It’s been for a long time I wanted to make a game but time is always short and It’s been postponed like forever, but this time I’m really going to do it.
I haven’t started the development itself but the ideas and what we want to do as a game is decided. I won’t reveal anything by now, just that I’ll be working with Rita, because the idea is to launch this as a Different Pixel game and that the target platform is PC/Xbox360.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing iPhone Sdk and MacOSX</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/testing-iphone-sdk-and-macosx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 11:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/testing-iphone-sdk-and-macosx/</guid>
      <description>So last weekend I finally got my hands on a fully operational Mac OSX with the iPhone SDK so I decided to give it a try.
First of all I had to set myself comfortable with this new OS since I’ve always used Windows. It’s not that hard and most of the things are straitgh forward.
I booted up X-Code and decided to test an iPhone Application and after 3-4 hours of researching and testing I managed to get a sprite on screen that moves to were I press on screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make a Game Week</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/03/make-a-game-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/03/make-a-game-week/</guid>
      <description>I work on a game creation company and this week the administration decided to give us a challenge, to make a game. Using whatever tools we want to whatever platform we like.
After we got divided between 4 teams the challenge was to make every minute count. My team got composed by me (programmer), a designer and a person from man resources. Of course I was going to handle every bit of code, the designer the art and the third person the level design and documentation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
