<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Development on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/categories/game-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Development on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/categories/game-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #2</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I missed last week devlog, mostly because I did almost no progress but also because it was a bad week overall, personally and in terms of work, nothing too bad but you know that feeling when you barely made any progress, despite tons of work hours? So one of those weeks.
But onto game5 progress.
Importers I managed to finish some of the importers (spreadsheets -&amp;gt; ScriptableObjects + prefabs) that I was working on, right now I can just glance over values on a spreadsheet, tweak, and have it export all the Scriptable Objects, generating the prefabs with corresponding data and images and test them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>game5 devlog #1</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/10/game5-devlog-1/</guid>
      <description>Nothing announced, not even a name decided, but I want to vaguely blog about it as a means of brainstorming with myself. I’ll be vague as heck until I’m sure I have something worth “here’s a new game”, if that ever turns out to be the case.
So this week’s it’s progress on my “on-going not yet announced game because not ready and might be bad” game, which I decided to for now on call Game5 here, so it’s easier to know what we are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity enshittification round 2, moving on to custom tech.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/unity-enshittification-round-2-moving-on-to-custom-tech/</guid>
      <description>After mostly a week of anxiety, for thousands and thousands of developers, Unity changed the rules again, and first glance, it’s better for the immediate problems it would cause for active and in-development games. They removed the retroactive aspect of the “pay-per-game-install”, so only for someone on Unity 2023 LTS+ (launching next year) will that apply, current projects will not be affected. Small relief, as long as we can keep using existing versions with current Terms of Service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unity enshittification, proprietary tech dangers, and mostly not talking about what I&#39;m doing.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 11:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/the-unity-enshittification-proprietary-tech-dangers-and-mostly-not-talking-about-what-im-doing/</guid>
      <description>So this was an “eventful” week in the game dev community. Unity, one of the most well know, and used game engines out there, after years of doing mostly good for the community, pulled a reverse card and broke years of trust the community had on them. Unity announced that they are retroactively charging (for example $0.2) for each game install, after developers hit a certain yearly revenue threshold, which sounds insane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some things to consider in multi-platform gamedev</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2023/09/some-things-to-consider-in-multi-platform-gamedev/</guid>
      <description>Decided to write a couple things I feel can help a game in the long run when it comes to porting it to other platforms. It’s always inevitable we have to change elements in a game when targeting a new console/device we never considered, but some considerations, if done from start can save a lot of time, headaches, porting budget, and equally important, avoiding introduction of new bugs due to code changing drastically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vizati 10th anniversary and making if free.</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2020/06/vizati-10th-anniversary-and-making-if-free/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; Hey everyone, wow ok so first of all it’s been a long time since my last post, I keep telling myself I need to return to do more regular posts, but twitter kinda replaced it in many ways for my daily-rambles. However I’ve been trying to work on something new and gotta get back to more regular blogging, but more on that later.
Second, but not least important, Vizati is turning 10 years old today (11 June 2010), feels only yesterday we (me coding and Rita with the art) were doing the first puzzles and trying to figure out the best way for making this a fun game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made a small game for Ludum Dare 42</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2018/08/made-a-small-game-for-ludum-dare-42/</guid>
      <description>Hey,
It’s been ages since my last post, feel like things keep getting in the way, also not much exciting stuff lately.
But decided to take a break from my current project to participate in Ludum Dare 42, it’s been years since the last time, also I liked the theme “Running out of Space” so I decided to hack something. To try and get out of my comfort zone I made my first game in Unity, so that was a fun experiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about a 4 year game dev cycle</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 12:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2016/12/some-thoughts-about-a-4-year-game-dev-cycle/</guid>
      <description>As I’m starting to write this post I’m on my way to my home town for the holidays, so I may not post it in a couple days.
It’s been a crazy year(s)(?) and I’m taking these near 4h of travel to write down some things. I’m sorry if it’s incoherent, this is mostly a dump of thoughts.
For those who follow my work a bit more closely you probably know that for almost 4 years the project I dedicated more time was Quest of Dungeons, which started development in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first ever console game is out</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/09/my-first-ever-console-game-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Hey, it’s been a while.
For the past few months I’ve been working on porting Quest of Dungeons to Xbox One, and I’m super happy that it’s finally out. It was released around a week ago, on September 4.
This took some time but I’m happy of the way the game is played with a gamepad, after a lot of changes to the UI I really feel like it was worth all the effort I put into it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestion for where to store save games</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/suggestion-for-where-to-store-save-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 09:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2015/04/suggestion-for-where-to-store-save-games/</guid>
      <description>Standards are a lovely thing, but hard to achieve, it depends on one thing, everyone actually using it, otherwise it’s just a rule no one cares about.
There is one thing that is very common to see in the “game sphere”:
Where are [X] save games located?
There are a couple of common directories used but I think as game developers we could do a bit better and using a common location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Xbox One developer now, QoD getting a port</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/im-a-xbox-one-developer-now-qod-getting-a-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/im-a-xbox-one-developer-now-qod-getting-a-port/</guid>
      <description>So a lot has happened since my last post. Even before EGX I was already in talks with Microsoft for becoming a Xbox One developer and maybe get Quest of Dungeons to XO. I was extremely happy when they accepted both, so right now I’m working on porting the game to Xbox One.
I don’t think this would have been possible without all the gamers that have played and are still playing the game, that’s what brought all the positive vibe surrounding the game, so a big thank you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indie Dev &amp; Day Job, Making it work / Building Quest of Dungeons</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 11:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/10/indie-dev-day-job-making-it-work-building-quest-of-dungeons/</guid>
      <description>During Gamedev Camp 2014 in Lisbon I got to talk a bit about the development of Quest of Dungeons, and some of the problems that I had making it while still having a day job.
Most indie developers don’t have enough money to work on their game full-time so they have to keep a day job in order to support it, so this is a bit of my own personal experience doing it, some of the problems that came with it and mistakes I did during the development and launch of the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Native game on Android &amp; Porting Quest of Dungeons</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 13:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/08/native-game-on-android-porting-quest-of-dungeons/</guid>
      <description>Quest of Dungeons was made in C++ and OpenGL, it runs on Windows, Mac and Linux in native code. iOS is not a problem either since I just have a thin layer of Objective-C to access some functionality like touch, accelerometer, etc and the rest of the code just runs.
I never made anything for Android, in fact I never even used one before this, so when I decided to port QoD to it, I had no idea of what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 11:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>I’m pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is finally out.
I didn’t get to make a post on day one, and it’s been nearly two weeks since launch but these past 2 weeks have been one crazy roller coaster.
It was released on March 25th, for PC, Mac and iOS. You can get it on Steam, iOS App Store or directly from the site via Humble Store.
I released all platforms on the same day, which was something I always wanted to try, and I have to say that it didn’t went as bad as I thought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons approved on Steam</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/02/quest-of-dungeons-approved-on-steam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 21:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/02/quest-of-dungeons-approved-on-steam/</guid>
      <description>A lot of stuff happened since my last post.
I launched a GreenLight campaign for Quest of Dungeons on Jan 16 and it got greenlit on Jan 21, votes were coming in like crazy, I did not see that coming.
Some sites posted about the game, like TouchArcade and PocketGamer, which was also very cool.
So right now I’m working like crazy to implement everything from steam onto the game (Mac/PC) but I still don’t have an exact launch date, although the iOS version is 90% certain to come out this February.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
