<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iOS on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iOS on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 11:40:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>QoD iOS and Android update 1.1.1 released</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/qod-ios-and-android-update-1-1-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 11:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/12/qod-ios-and-android-update-1-1-1-released/</guid>
      <description>A new patch for iOS and Android went live, v1.1.1
There are some differences in what’s new for each one of the platforms, the biggest change being support for iPhone 6 and 6 Plus on iOS and x86 architecture support on Android.
The reason why there are more tweaks on the iOS is because the Android version was updated more recently. After this update they are on par on features and fixes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 11:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2014/04/quest-of-dungeons-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>I’m pleased to announce that Quest of Dungeons is finally out.
I didn’t get to make a post on day one, and it’s been nearly two weeks since launch but these past 2 weeks have been one crazy roller coaster.
It was released on March 25th, for PC, Mac and iOS. You can get it on Steam, iOS App Store or directly from the site via Humble Store.
I released all platforms on the same day, which was something I always wanted to try, and I have to say that it didn’t went as bad as I thought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons development update</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/12/quest-of-dungeons-development-update/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on Quest of Dungeons and I’m nearing Gold. I’m attempting to release every version on the same day, which I never managed to do before but would like to do this time.
I have both the iOS, Mac and Windows version very stable, the Mac and iOS apps were already accepted by the App Store, for Windows I’m still trying to wrap up the process of getting it on a digital store too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puwang - a 5 day work</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 20:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/09/puwang-a-5-day-work/</guid>
      <description>Hi, how’s everyone doing?
So this was a different week for me. It’s been a long time that I had the chance to work on a small prototype or a 48H competition because of my work on Dary’s Legend so I decided to stop for a couple of days and do something else.
Also my cat’s been quite sick, and between the Vet and taking care of him, working on a fun project gave me more time do everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So what have I learned after eight months on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 21:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>First of all I think this is my last idevblogaday post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn. Actually it’s just the 9th.
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little on how to initialize and use GameCenter</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/a-little-on-how-to-initialize-and-use-gamecenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 10:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/04/a-little-on-how-to-initialize-and-use-gamecenter/</guid>
      <description>Small side-note first, Vizati is now available for the Super Nintendo, more info.
For my third idevblogaday post I’m going to talk about Game Center.
Game Center was released only a couple months ago (September or so) but already tons of applications are using it and even more, players ask for it.
It’s a way to track achievements, leader boards etc. Unfortunately It’s only available from iOS 4.1+, so some compatibility check has to be done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPad launch images support for all orientations</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 23:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</guid>
      <description>When loading an application on an iPhone or iPad, a launch image can be shown to provide feedback to the user that the application is loading.
On the iPhone a Default.png was used, with the iPad we need to anticipate the device being started in any orientation.
Filename Dimensions Default-Portrait.png * 768w x 1024h Default-PortraitUpsideDown.png 768w x 1024h Default-Landscape.png ** 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeLeft.png 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeRight.png 1024w x 768h Default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting OpenGL view for iPhone 4 retina hi resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/setting-opengl-view-for-iphone-4-retina-hi-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 09:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/setting-opengl-view-for-iphone-4-retina-hi-resolution/</guid>
      <description>This had me scratching my head for awhile.
At first I thought that glGetRenderbufferParameterivOES would properly detect Retina screen at 960×640 but it keeps returning 480×320.
A little explanation on Retina screen first. Older devices have 320×480 screen resolution. With new iPhone 4 and iPod Touch 4G the screen has 640×960 but on the same physical area. This means that each pixel is 4 times as small.
To properly simulate older games resolutions iOS will replace each of your 320×480 game pixel by 4, this way your game will look identical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targetting iOS devices hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 12:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I decided to compile all iOS devices specs here so we can get a better glimpse on their hardware and what we can expect from them.
This covers iPhones, iPod Touches and iPad.
iPhone/iPhone 3G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPhone 3GS – 600 MHz / 256MB / 320×480
iPhone 4 -~800MHz / 512MB / 640×960
iPod Touch 1G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPod Touch 2G – 532 MHz / 128MB / 320×480</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
