<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nintendo Switch on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/nintendo-switch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nintendo Switch on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/nintendo-switch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons Switch Physical Release</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got several other versions and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.
One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with Leoful, it’s finally happening, and soon too, release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (begin tomorrow, March 26).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leoful-QuestofDungeons-HeroImage-Physical-Switch-1024x576.png" alt="Quest of Dungeons Nintendo Switch Physical"  />
</a>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got <a href="/2015/07/quest-of-dungeons-coming-to-xbox-one-on-september-4/">several</a> <a href="/2016/09/qod-is-now-available-on-eshop-for-nintendo-3ds-and-wii-u/">other</a> <a href="/2017/01/quest-of-dungeons-is-out-now-on-playstation-4/">versions</a> and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.</p>
<p>One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with <a href="https://leoful.com/quest-of-dungeons-celebrates-7th-anniversary-with-a-nintendo-switch-physical-release/">Leoful</a>, it’s finally happening, and soon too, <strong>release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (<!-- raw HTML omitted -->begin tomorrow, March 26<!-- raw HTML omitted -->).</strong></p>
<p>This is a limited release, and for this special occasion we have a reversible cover, with the front art made by <a href="https://www.spacecoyote.com/">Nina Matsumoto</a>, and the reversible side by <a href="https://www.artstation.com/vascomarianoart">Vasco Mariano</a>, think it looks great and can’t wait for everyone to start receiving it.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Quest-of-Dungeons-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-edition.png" alt=""  />
</a><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Reversible and front cover<!-- raw HTML omitted --><strong><!-- raw HTML omitted -->-F.A.Q.-<!-- raw HTML omitted --></strong></p>
<p><strong>Where can I buy it?</strong><br>
[<em>PLEASE STAND BY FOR LINKS, I’LL LINK AS I HAVE THEM, UPDATE IN PROGRESS</em>]<br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Play Asia:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt">https://www.play-asia.com/quest-of-dungeons-english/13/70eaxt</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->NintendoSoup:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/">https://nintendosoup.com/product/quest-of-dungeons-physical-edition-nintendo-switch/</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bazaar-Bazaar:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.bazaar-bazaar.com/products/quest-of-dungeons</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->XtraLife:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724">https://www.xtralife.com/producto/quest-of-dungeons-switch-estandar-asia/66724</a><br>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Agugames:<!-- raw HTML omitted --> <a href="https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons">https://www.agugames.net/products/quest-of-dungeons</a></p>
<p><em>*Note: not in affiliation with any of the store links listed here, the order they are is random and not an indication of preference of any kind. Make sure to check where it ships from, for shipping costs &amp; possible import taxes etc.</em></p>
<p><strong>Is it region free?</strong><br>
Yes.</p>
<p><strong>Is it a cartridge or a downloadable code inside the box?</strong><br>
A cartridge, also has a reversible cover.</p>
<p><strong>How much does it cost?</strong><br>
Suggested Retail Price: USD24.99 / HKD195 / NTD710 / SGD34 (all prices exclude sales tax)</p>
<p><strong>Any differences between with the digital version?</strong><br>
Both versions contain the same content, if you already own the digital it’s the same game.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/shaman_assassin_conversation_switch_cartridge.png" alt=""  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</guid>
      <description>EDIT (09/09/2017):
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.
Hey,
So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.
Super happy to say that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>EDIT (09/09/2017):<br>
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hey,</p>
<p>So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.</p>
<p>Super happy to say that <strong>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</strong>. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away. In <strong>Japan is already releasing next week, August 10</strong>, <a href="http://flyhighworks.heteml.jp/games/">Flyhigh Works</a> is handing publishing in the Japanese territory.</p>
<p>I’ll be taking care of the rest of the world, but for <strong>Europe and America I’m still working on it</strong>, but hopefully it won’t take much more time.</p>
<p>Meanwhile a sneak peek at the new logo and the new main animation made by <a href="https://twitter.com/rephildesign">@rephildesign</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pixel_logo_v1_4x.png" alt=""  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/character_animations_1x.gif" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>I already got a couple questions asked via twitter so I’ll try to put here the most frequent ones.</p>
<p>F.A.Q. / tl;dr</p>
<p><strong>-Release date?</strong><br>
In Japan the game will be releasing in August 10. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->NA/EU dev still under way, I’ll update this when there are changes.<!-- raw HTML omitted --> It will be released on September 14 in Europe, America and Australia.</p>
<p><strong>-How much?</strong><br>
Same as the Wii U/Nintendo 3DS, $8.99</p>
<p><strong>-New features?</strong><br>
Yes there are some new things, there’s a new Mansion, so you have a couple more different themes and sprites. Also a new Feats system to track Achievements, there are several other optimizations/tweaks/changes, but those are the main changes.</p>
<p><strong>-Who ported the game?</strong><br>
Port was made in-house. Flyhigh Works is publishing in Japan, Upfall Studios will be doing the publishing on rest of the world.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press)I want to receive news from your studio</strong><br>
You can use the form at the bottom of the website to subscribe to our newsletter, only used for announcements etc, we don’t spam much<br>
<a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact">http://www.upfallstudios.com/#contact</a>. Direct email for any other questions or inquires is listed there as well.</p>
<p><strong>-(Press) Press-Kit?</strong><br>
There is one here with screenshots, videos and some info <a href="http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons">http://www.upfallstudios.com/press/sheet.php?p=quest_of_dungeons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 3 years old, a small message for the community</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.
Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.
A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.questofdungeons.com"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/quest_of_dungeons_steam_page_header.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/DJ_Link/status/419147399375118336"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Screenshot-2022-11-01-at-19.38.50.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p>A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</p>
<p>I wanted to take this chance to say thank you to everyone who purchased the game, who helped by making Youtube videos, streaming, recommending to friends, and all the support. If I was able to convince anyone to accept the game on their console/platform it was because the players were talking about it, purchasing and saying they cared. So while I may have built the game, without the community this wouldn’t have happen, I couldn’t have done this without you.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/gKx4R.gif" alt="Hugs"  />
</p>
<p><strong>What now?</strong><br>
Many of you have been asking if I’m working on something new, and the answer is yes, but it’s still a bit soon to discuss what it is, I’ll share more details at a later time. But I’m excited (although a bit nervous) to start working on something new after 4 years of dev in the same project.</p>
<p><strong>What about QoD now?</strong><br>
Although I’m moving to new projects that doesn’t mean work on QoD is completely halting. I intend to keep fixing issues with new devices/OS, this is particularly true with mobile devices which rapidly evolve. I don’t have immediate plans for new content (another popular question), but again, might happen if something makes sense to add in order to improve the game.<br>
As of recently a common question is “Quest of Dungeons on Switch when?”, and while I would love to have the game there, especially with Wii U fading out, and because the game fits well on a portable mode, the ultimate decision to have the game there is up to Nintendo. All I can say about this is that I’ll talk with them and will inform you of any changes.</p>
<p>That’s it for now, thank you for reading. As always feel free reach me via twitter, email, etc. Until the next update.<br>
-David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
