<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nintendo Switch on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/nintendo-switch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nintendo Switch on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/nintendo-switch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons Switch Physical Release</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2021/03/quest-of-dungeons-switch-physical-release/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy Birthday to Quest of Dungeons 7th anniversary, initially released on March 25th 2014 for PC and iOS. QoD eventually got several other versions and big content updates over time, and that’s all thanks to the support of the fans, making it possible for me to continue working on it, so thank you.
One thing I got asked frequently was about a physical release, and it took a bit of time but I’m happy to announce that, in cooperation with Leoful, it’s finally happening, and soon too, release date is April 13 and pre-orders are live (begin tomorrow, March 26).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/08/quest-of-dungeons-is-coming-to-switch-releasing-in-japan-august-10/</guid>
      <description>EDIT (09/09/2017):
Europe and America are now scheduled for a September 14 release date.
Hey,
So this will be a quick post, as news started appearing on twitter a couple moments ago and I wanted to answer some questions.
Super happy to say that Quest of Dungeons is coming to Nintendo Switch. Every since Nintendo announced the console that I’ve been getting questions so this will make a lot of people happy, and the best thing is that it’s not far away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quest of Dungeons turns 3 years old, a small message for the community</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2017/03/quest-of-dungeons-turns-3-years-old-a-small-message-for-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Exactly 3 years ago today, March 25th, Quest of Dungeons was released on Steam and iOS.
Feels unreal thinking what happened in these past three years, for those who remember I wasn’t even sure the game could make it to Steam, let alone end up being accepted by PlayStation, Nintendo and Xbox for their consoles.
A couple of days ago I was thinking I should do something special for today, but instead of discounts or promotions I decided to write a couple of words to you, the community.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
