<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>app store on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/app-store/</link>
    <description>Recent content in app store on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:05:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/app-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Puwang is out on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/10/puwang-is-out-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/10/puwang-is-out-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>So tonight, while I was sleeping, Puwang was approved and released on the App Store.
I made a small gameplay video where, directly from the screen.
and there’s another one, offscreen, on a real iDevice here
Spread the word, buy it if you like =)
App Store Link: http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?l=en&amp;amp;mt=8</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So tonight, while I was sleeping, Puwang was approved and released on the App Store.</p>
<p><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?l=en&amp;mt=8"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/puwang_icon.png" alt=""  title="Puwang"  />
</a></p>
<p>I made a small gameplay video where, directly from the screen.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EVFTiA2BZiQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>and there’s another one, offscreen, on a real iDevice <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AIiKBVTiEhM&amp;feature=g-upl">here</a></p>
<p>Spread the word, buy it if you like =)</p>
<p>App Store Link: <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?l=en&amp;mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/puwang/id566365237?l=en&amp;mt=8</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So what have I learned after eight months on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 21:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>First of all I think this is my last idevblogaday post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn. Actually it’s just the 9th.
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->First of all I think this is my last <a href="http://idevblogaday.com/">idevblogaday</a> post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn.<!-- raw HTML omitted --> Actually it’s just the 9th.<br>
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game<br>
there’s probably news to share in the next 2-3 months.</p>
<p>Around 11 months ago I registered my App Store developer account. The idea…put Vizati on the iPhone.<br>
I’ve never worked with Mac’s before, didn’t even have an iPhone/iPod or whatever. I just read that a bunch of people got rich and many more where making a living out of it.<br>
So here I go.</p>
<p><strong>Just placing an app there will sell</strong></p>
<p>My first BIG mistake was the general conception that “just placing an app there will sell”. That’s probably true on the very first months the App Store opened. Not now, trust me. You release a new game, will probably have a few sales on the 1st day because it’s on the new released games and that’s it, only on very rare conditions will the game start selling very good with just that.<br>
So keep in mind advertisement on iOS is mandatory, forums, twitter, mailing list, whatever.<br>
The first month I was sending dozens of emails every single day to websites, journalists, magazines, some paid off, others didn’t.</p>
<p><strong>Release my app at a Thursday to be featured at that week’s App Featured Apps</strong></p>
<p>Although this might increase your odds, we released Vizati on a Friday, 2 weeks later it got a feature on the App Store, so it can still happen. Just create something cool and appealing.</p>
<p><strong>$0.99 is the way to go</strong></p>
<p>Wrong, don’t EVER place your app at $0.99 right from start. Evaluate it well, start higher. Having a higher price will help to distinguish it from others, will give you margin for promotions without making it free. Many costumers, tired of the enormous lists of game will only seek higher priced games because logic mandates that they are indeed better. If you think your app is not worth more that $0.99 go back to the drawing boards. There’s no sense in having crappy apps, 100 bad apps may not sell as much as 5 really good ones.<br>
Selling at a low price will also bring all kinds of customers, they will give you a 1 star just because you haven’t updated the app in 5 months or so. Customers that buy pricier app are more forgiving and respectful.</p>
<p><strong>Making a Free promotion will help boost sales afterwords</strong></p>
<p>True, for the first 2-3 days. Then you’ll get back to whatever you where selling. Unless you have some in-game purchases it’s not worth it. Well only if you want to brag to your friends that your app got 100K downloads no matter the price. I’ve tried this 3 times, each time I place it at a smarter occasion getting successfully more downloads, thing is that after 3 days of getting back to regular price things would slowly return to normal. Depending on promotion amount of days you may end up with the same money you would have not making the promotion. Also usually you will see your rating decreasing half or a full star, keep in mind, all kinds of people will download it.</p>
<p><strong>Answering to customers Feedback helps sales</strong></p>
<p>Obviously implementing a highly demanded features will make them happy thus recommending to friends. Just don’t go making all the changes they ask. Choose a position and defend it, show that things are the way they are because you choose so, not because of some mistake.</p>
<p><strong>People will buy all kinds of crap, just place one level.</strong></p>
<p>Also true, but just because they bought a “fart app” doesn’t mean they wont’ complain about your 15m duration game.</p>
<p>Well, time to go work on top secret project, see ya later</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why cheap games are hurting gaming</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/why-cheap-games-is-hurt-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/05/why-cheap-games-is-hurt-gaming/</guid>
      <description>This has been discussed on thousands of forums and people way smarter than me have given reasons why selling games at $0.99 on the App Store is the future and others why it will hurt gaming and developers.
I’m giving my opinion as both a developer and a consumer.
As a consumer
As a consumer I feel like having thousands of games at that price and/or free makes me not appreciate any of them, there’s way too many and I usually get bothered easily.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This has been discussed on thousands of forums and people way smarter than me have given reasons why selling games at $0.99 on the App Store is the future and others why it will hurt gaming and developers.</p>
<p>I’m giving my opinion as both a developer and a consumer.</p>
<p><strong>As a consumer</strong></p>
<p>As a consumer I feel like having thousands of games at that price and/or free makes me not appreciate any of them, there’s way too many and I usually get bothered easily. Now, note that this is a personal problem of mine since most people can still play hours and hours of those games even though they have dozens of them, but I’m pretty sure more feel the same.</p>
<p>Usually the games I play longer and have more fun with are the ones I buy via PC, either mainstream like Portal 2 or indie games like Super Meat Boy, why? Not because they are better or worse games, but because I spent €30 on Portal 2 and €10 on Super Meat Boy. Play them for a couple of weeks and felt rewarded. The feeling was even better back when I was a kid, it was way hard to buy those SNES cartridges but when enough money was gathered I played them for months.</p>
<p>So what makes me feel more compelled to play these games? Probably the fact that I had to hand picked them since I’m not swimming in money. I had to work hard for that money, decided to spend it on some digital entertainment and got rewarded, that is all part of the process. Games are supposed to entertain you and give you a sense of achievement. I think now days they replaced that with actual “Achievements” and “GamerScore”‘s</p>
<p><strong>As a developer</strong></p>
<p>Applying the same rules as above, people have access to way too many games, and they feel like for $0.99 they have the right to a 10+ hours game, monthly updates with new free content so they feel compelled to play your game. If not you app is a crap even though most of the games on the App Store are worth much more than $0.99. But they don’t see it that way.<br>
Surviving in that ecosystem is hard and although you may (on a long shot of pure luck) make a couple of millions, for me it’s sad to sell this kind of software this cheap.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/screen3_large.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/screen3_large.jpg" alt=""  title="screen3_large"  />
</a></p>
<p>Take a look at this example. If you don’t know the Broken Sword series I suggest you grab a copy at any digital publisher. The first 2 games are awesome, both of them are pretty long since it’s a point ‘n click adventure, a lot of thinking, puzzles and cut-scenes.</p>
<p>Now look at this comment on the Mac App Store:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/broken_sword_2_review.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/broken_sword_2_review.png" alt=""  title="broken_sword_2_review"  />
</a></p>
<p>He feels like the game has a “lite” feel? For $7.99 it’s a great game, doesn’t feel lite to me, but this user is too spoiled.<br>
He doesn’t comment anything else. Now imagine the next customer who walks by, doesn’t know the game and reads that, “oh, a pretty game but this other buyer complains that it may be a sort of rip-off, a lite version in disguise”.</p>
<p>I just woke up a couple of minutes ago so most of this may not make any sense.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
