<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>idevblogaday on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/idevblogaday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in idevblogaday on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 21:14:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/idevblogaday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So what have I learned after eight months on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 21:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/06/so-what-have-i-learned-after-eight-months-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>First of all I think this is my last idevblogaday post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn. Actually it’s just the 9th.
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->First of all I think this is my last <a href="http://idevblogaday.com/">idevblogaday</a> post for a while. I my math doesn’t fail me this is my 10th post and it’s time for someone to take turn.<!-- raw HTML omitted --> Actually it’s just the 9th.<br>
I hope my words have somehow enriched your knowledge, in case you want to stick around just bookmark my feeds. I keep this fairly updated. Also since I’ve been working on a new game<br>
there’s probably news to share in the next 2-3 months.</p>
<p>Around 11 months ago I registered my App Store developer account. The idea…put Vizati on the iPhone.<br>
I’ve never worked with Mac’s before, didn’t even have an iPhone/iPod or whatever. I just read that a bunch of people got rich and many more where making a living out of it.<br>
So here I go.</p>
<p><strong>Just placing an app there will sell</strong></p>
<p>My first BIG mistake was the general conception that “just placing an app there will sell”. That’s probably true on the very first months the App Store opened. Not now, trust me. You release a new game, will probably have a few sales on the 1st day because it’s on the new released games and that’s it, only on very rare conditions will the game start selling very good with just that.<br>
So keep in mind advertisement on iOS is mandatory, forums, twitter, mailing list, whatever.<br>
The first month I was sending dozens of emails every single day to websites, journalists, magazines, some paid off, others didn’t.</p>
<p><strong>Release my app at a Thursday to be featured at that week’s App Featured Apps</strong></p>
<p>Although this might increase your odds, we released Vizati on a Friday, 2 weeks later it got a feature on the App Store, so it can still happen. Just create something cool and appealing.</p>
<p><strong>$0.99 is the way to go</strong></p>
<p>Wrong, don’t EVER place your app at $0.99 right from start. Evaluate it well, start higher. Having a higher price will help to distinguish it from others, will give you margin for promotions without making it free. Many costumers, tired of the enormous lists of game will only seek higher priced games because logic mandates that they are indeed better. If you think your app is not worth more that $0.99 go back to the drawing boards. There’s no sense in having crappy apps, 100 bad apps may not sell as much as 5 really good ones.<br>
Selling at a low price will also bring all kinds of customers, they will give you a 1 star just because you haven’t updated the app in 5 months or so. Customers that buy pricier app are more forgiving and respectful.</p>
<p><strong>Making a Free promotion will help boost sales afterwords</strong></p>
<p>True, for the first 2-3 days. Then you’ll get back to whatever you where selling. Unless you have some in-game purchases it’s not worth it. Well only if you want to brag to your friends that your app got 100K downloads no matter the price. I’ve tried this 3 times, each time I place it at a smarter occasion getting successfully more downloads, thing is that after 3 days of getting back to regular price things would slowly return to normal. Depending on promotion amount of days you may end up with the same money you would have not making the promotion. Also usually you will see your rating decreasing half or a full star, keep in mind, all kinds of people will download it.</p>
<p><strong>Answering to customers Feedback helps sales</strong></p>
<p>Obviously implementing a highly demanded features will make them happy thus recommending to friends. Just don’t go making all the changes they ask. Choose a position and defend it, show that things are the way they are because you choose so, not because of some mistake.</p>
<p><strong>People will buy all kinds of crap, just place one level.</strong></p>
<p>Also true, but just because they bought a “fart app” doesn’t mean they wont’ complain about your 15m duration game.</p>
<p>Well, time to go work on top secret project, see ya later</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing a game from PC to iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/bringing-a-game-from-pc-to-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 11:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/bringing-a-game-from-pc-to-ios/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post to http://idevblogaday.com/, I’ve been waiting since November so I’m pretty excited about writing to a broader audience =P. Even though I only have one product on the App Store I have gathered some knowledge on how stuff works to get there.
I’ll start by talking a bit about how we made our PC game Vizati to iPhone.When we started, this represented our chance of making games and putting ourselves into test.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post to <a href="http://idevblogaday.com/">http://idevblogaday.com/</a>, I’ve been waiting since November so I’m pretty excited about writing to a broader audience =P. Even though I only have one product on the App Store I have gathered some knowledge on how stuff works to get there.</p>
<p>I’ll start by talking a bit about how we made our PC game <a href="https://dj_link.itch.io/vizati/">Vizati</a> to iPhone.<a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/vizati/id393099810?mt=8"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/box_vizati_11.jpg" alt=""  title="box_vizati_1"  />
</a></p>
<p>When we started, this represented our chance of making games and putting ourselves into test. Without any pre determined rules and/or a major company dictating what to do we were able to have full creative control to try and do something a bit different.</p>
<p><em>Vizati</em> is a casual puzzle game with a story as a background. The game is now available for Windows, Mac, iPhone, iPad and Windows Phone 7. Developed by only two people, it thankfully received several good reviews.</p>
<p><strong>Launching for Windows</strong></p>
<p>We started out building for Windows and Xbox360 because it was a very well known platform for us; we had tools and knowledge from other games so it felt right.</p>
<p>We launched the game on June 6<!-- raw HTML omitted -->th; <!-- raw HTML omitted --> and got some very positive reviews, being its freshness, graphics and music the most acclaimed features.</p>
<p>Right away we started making plans for bringing the game to iOS devices, iPhone, iPad etc. The mobile devices felt like a great platform for such a game.</p>
<p><strong>First speed bump</strong></p>
<p>For the PC we had built the game engine using XNA framework as a base, it is DirectX based but it uses .Net languages which are a no go for iOS devices of course. It was stable enough to ensure a high compatibility with all the different machines out there, and we never thought at start to make it for any other platforms. This was our first mistake.</p>
<p>For the next 3 months I had to rewrite all the game codebase to C++ including building the engine itself using render API OpenGLES. <a href="/2010/07/developing-on-mac-and-basalt-running-on-the-iphone/" title="Developing on Mac and Basalt running on the iPhone">[Dedicated Post]</a></p>
<p>During these 3 months we also had to adjust the game to the iPhone screen size. Just out of curiosity the native resolution on PC is HD, 1280×720 and the iPhone native is 640×426. <a href="/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/" title="Targetting iOS devices hardware">[See more on iOS hardware]</a></p>
<p>At first we considered using the same images and using the same feature we used on PC to <a href="/2010/03/xna-2d-independent-resolution-rendering/" title="XNA 2D Independent Resolution Rendering">automatically scale the game</a> to the screen size. But doing that would be a tremendous effort to the device since the iPhone screen size was almost 3 times smaller; memory and CPU cycles are more limited in mobiles so we had to make a smarter approach.</p>
<p>One of the problems was the game being extremely slow on older devices. The amount of particles and animations on some parts was a total killer. I eventually had to <a href="/2010/08/developers-log-stardate-26082010/" title="Developers log stardate 26082010">rewrite my primitive drawing code </a>to batch stuff as much as possible</p>
<p>Another problem was the aspect ratio, which would lead to either stretching the game vertically thus distorting the images or making it letterboxed.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/vizati_letterbox.jpg" alt=""  title="vizati_letterbox"  />
</p>
<p>The screen is already small so it would be a mistake not to take advantage of all the area. Rita had to redo some of the art to fit a different aspect ratio.</p>
<p>Fortunately touch felt a very natural way for controlling the game, even more than a keyboard. Using the fingers to rotate, shake and flip the cube feels right and natural.</p>
<p>The iPad version was easy once we had the iPhone version made, basically we just had to bundle high-resolution images since its screen resolution is 1024×768. This version features the HD graphics that so many loved in the PC version.</p>
<p>Most recently the hard work I did doing a somewhat multi-platform engine payed off and we released it for <a href="http://www.differentpixel.com/2011/02/vizati-now-available-for-mac/">Mac on the App Store</a> with around just <a href="/2011/01/officially-a-mac-developer-too-wait-what/">4 days of extra work</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
