<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 what a year huh?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/12/what-a-year-huh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/12/what-a-year-huh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025&#34;&gt;2025!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been, for the lack of a better expression, a stressful year. I still remember around end of 2024 many people saying &amp;ldquo;things will change next year&amp;rdquo;. And change they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me personally, professionally and overall worldwide events turned this year into a constant state of alert that made almost every week in sync with my weekly &lt;a href=&#34;https://bsky.app/profile/djlink.bsky.social/post/3ma6yoweqm22a&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cloud it&amp;rsquo;s Wednesday&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intraconnected-world-&#34;&gt;Intraconnected-world 🕸️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if someone&amp;rsquo;s work doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on using the internet, we can&amp;rsquo;t escape it these days.
The problem for me really is that &amp;ldquo;The Internet&amp;rdquo; as I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to know it, is for the most part gone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="2025">2025!</h2>
<p>This has been, for the lack of a better expression, a stressful year. I still remember around end of 2024 many people saying &ldquo;things will change next year&rdquo;. And change they did.</p>
<p>For me personally, professionally and overall worldwide events turned this year into a constant state of alert that made almost every week in sync with my weekly <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/djlink.bsky.social/post/3ma6yoweqm22a">&ldquo;Cloud it&rsquo;s Wednesday&rdquo;</a> post.</p>
<h2 id="intraconnected-world-">Intraconnected-world 🕸️</h2>
<p>Even if someone&rsquo;s work doesn&rsquo;t depend on using the internet, we can&rsquo;t escape it these days.
The problem for me really is that &ldquo;The Internet&rdquo; as I&rsquo;ve grown to know it, is for the most part gone.</p>
<p><img alt="IT Crowd this is the internet" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/it_crowd_this_is_the_internet.jpg"></p>
<p>It used to be like a library with a few rooms for leisure and games, but now it looks like a night-club with music blasting where everyone is shouting, trying to be louder than the rest, and relegated to the backrooms are a few of the places you might still like/identify with, the knowledge sections, non-fake-content and positive collaboration vibes, finding them is the problem. The majority of people are in the main hall now, if we only enter and stay, we are exposed to all the noise that comes with it, it&rsquo;s exhausting.</p>
<p><img alt="Tired computer anime" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tired_computer_anime.gif"></p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been over a year since I mostly stopped using Twitter (yes I still call it that) as my main social network, for over a decade that was my daily website to post, check on mutuals, cool stuff being made and overall news. That&rsquo;s why I used it, I enjoyed going there, but that is no longer what I find when I open it, everyone is angry, trying to drive traffic through negativity which algorithms push even higher (although that can be said of most social networks).</p>
<p>Weirdly I thought it would be harder to leave Twitter, but it wasn&rsquo;t, once in a while I&rsquo;ll poke around, but I leave quickly.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been using <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/deck/@djlink">Mastodon</a> and <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/djlink.bsky.social">Bluesky</a> via cross-posting but it&rsquo;s not the same. Which in a way has been good, it&rsquo;s not like I felt pressure to post on Twitter, for me was always natural, but maybe I was too addicted to posting regardless. I spend less time on social networks now, which also helps with not feeling the urge to &ldquo;post that I&rsquo;m making cool stuff&rdquo;, and most times I can&rsquo;t talk about anything.</p>
<p><img alt="Break NDA" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/cant_break_nda_not_active.jpg"></p>
<p>There is contract work I&rsquo;ve been doing only for next year and maybe even beyond. In 2024 I was working on stuff that was only launched this year, an example is <a href="https://www.kinmoku.games/videoverse">VideoVerse</a>, which for several months I was in touch daily with Kinmoku so that we could try and get the console versions as polished (and as humanly fast) as possible, and it wasn&rsquo;t something that none of us was publicly talking about; dopamine of feedback when you are working on neat stuff via social network is cool but learning to live without it is quite liberating. A funny thing actually about this one, and why I mentioned it specifically, is by coincidence I ended up working on the same game as <a href="https://luiscorreia.pt/">Luis Correia</a>, which I&rsquo;ve known IRL for years, and for the longest time he didn&rsquo;t know as well xD.</p>
<h2 id="gaming-industry-">Gaming Industry 👾</h2>
<p>This year was the continuation of a cycle that started a couple years ago now, many layoffs, even in profitable studios, which while baffling is probably fueled by other external factors like the rise of the <a href="#agents-era">&ldquo;agent era&rdquo;</a> and keeping stocks rising. This last one was something that I had a friend point out last year, usually layoffs in public companies are accompanied by stocks rising, investors predict a leaner company with less expenses. Ever since I was made aware of this I can&rsquo;t unsee it, it&rsquo;s true, it&rsquo;s a vicious cycle.</p>
<p>The problem with the big companies doing this is that it trickles down to mid and smaller companies and indie developers. Projects get cancelled, funds get pulled out of nowhere.</p>
<p>I was feeling this last year as several teams I was in touch with were having some projects canceled, but by end of 2024 a bunch of stuff for Q1/Q2 2025 got cancelled; many teams do contact work for bigger studios, and those contracted studios sometimes outsource additional help from smaller external teams or individuals, and I&rsquo;m one of them, so I was seeing the cascading effect happen in real-time.</p>
<p>A lot of times I am enquired about work time for a potential project (additional programming or port-work) months before, which gives a good idea of my runway of work, it shrank tremendously from &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t have time for the next 6 months&rdquo; to &ldquo;Oh wait I got next month with nothing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>This year I was in touch with many other devs I know in similar situations, questions from &ldquo;hey let me know if you find something that could be a good fit for me&rdquo;, or just generally enquiring if anyone had found anything, in hopes to get some good news that things could be improving for someone.</p>
<p>Luckily and better than most I guess, I was able to find some short-term stuff stuff to minimize this and did a few random work tasks to fill that time the best possible. I even used some of it to start learning <a href="#unreal-engine">Unreal Engine</a>. Eventually found other stuff that wasn&rsquo;t just a couple weeks of work, so at the moment, while not super stable, (but this is a general thing for everyone), I have a couple things for the next months and through 2026 in my hands, fingers crossed nothing caves.</p>
<p>But it is a scary situation for everyone, and it reminds me that time back in 2009, the bank-house-finantial-market-bubble <a href="/2009/12/updates-about-different-pixel-and-sapphire/">where I found myself out of job</a>, I couldn&rsquo;t quite understand why back then (ah young and oblivious), but now it makes more sense, it wasn&rsquo;t just the company, but external stuff too.</p>
<p>But ending on a positive note, and even though according to Steam sheer amount of games launched the competition for &ldquo;digital shelf space&rdquo; is increasing at a rapid pace, it seems the % of studios finding success is growing, the problem really is on the other end it&rsquo;s a trail of destruction for people who can&rsquo;t make it.</p>
<h2 id="agents-era-">Agents-era 🤖</h2>
<p>A lot of digital ink has been used in the last few years, and especially this one, about &ldquo;AI&rdquo;, agents, large models, and the for better-or-worse, the digital revolution (?) with real life impact that is causing.</p>
<p><img alt="Agent Smith with Agents in The Matrix" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/agent_smith_with_agents_in_the_matrix.jpg"></p>
<p>We are all feeling it&rsquo;s impact, either directly, if someone is using it for work or got layoff due to the perceived reality that &ldquo;AI will replace everyone&rdquo;; or indirectly, subscriptions getting more expensive due to addition of AI features, regardless if you use them or not, Power plants being activated (and built) for the sole purpose of keeping up with increasing GPU demands, electricity prices likely increasing due to that, chips are getting more expensive, RAM prices are through the roof, and overall companies are becoming less and less interested in selling stuff at affordable prices to consumer market and instead profit from the increasingly demanding AI-Data-GPU-centers being used and built.</p>
<p>This stuff is happening, in real-time, regardless of what we think about it, my humble opinion here is that it will eventually land in the middle, it won&rsquo;t be a bubble that pops, but neither will it &ldquo;full replace everything and everyone and is so much better&rdquo;. There are benefits (just not the way it&rsquo;s being used) but it will also leave a trail of tech debt everywhere. Those who can position themselves in cleanup-completet-asks-ai-is-not-good, might find a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Ocean_Strategy">new blue ocean</a>. If in the future everyone uses AI, then that&rsquo;s the new average, regardless if it&rsquo;s much faster than today or not, and whom ever breaks from that, stands out.</p>
<h2 id="unreal-engine">Unreal Engine</h2>
<p>While searching for new contract work this year I found myself with a couple weeks of slower, even dead time, and while in insight <a href="#taking-vacations-time-or-lack-of">I should have taken some time off</a>, I decided to use the time to start learning Unreal Engine. I&rsquo;ve been thinking about it for several years, but never had the time, and the decision was helped by seeing lot of job postings for that, seems to be growing at a steady pace of demand, many studios shifting towards Unreal, even AAA that had built-in-house engines.</p>
<p>I had never even opened it, so this was the perfect opportunity for in 2-3 years I wouldn&rsquo;t be a complete noob, maybe even applying for such positions, so starting now with no expectations would be nice.</p>
<p>After talking with <a href="https://www.stevestreeting.com/">Steve Streeting</a> a bit, who I look up to when it comes to game engines (I mean he created <a href="https://www.ogre3d.org/">OGRE 3D</a> after all), I decided to enroll into an online course to get started faster. This was the first time I did this approach, I usually just start working on a new tool with small tests or a prototype and learn as I go, like <a href="/2025/04/switching-unity-to-godot-my-experience-so-far/">I did with Godot</a> (and still am working with it). But since my time was a bit more limited, and I did not wanted to start yet another prototype, I went the course route instead.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I coded so much in C++ and I forgot how both elegant and obnoxious this language can be, but the Unreal way of doing things is quite interesting. In a way there&rsquo;s a lot of the same things we have in Unity, linking stuff to inspector, a more editor-oriented approach, but I think the interesting part is there it kind of expects you to do things a certain way, instead of Godot/Unity more &ldquo;sandbox type&rdquo; approach.</p>
<p>The advantage I guess is that very rapidly we have stuff working, like character movement, collisions etc, which speeds up early development/learning.</p>
<p>I learned that Blueprints vs C++ is not necessarily &ldquo;one vs the other, but more &ldquo;there&rsquo;s a good time for either&rdquo;, and I&rsquo;m glad the course is approaching both, pros and cons of either in different situations.
I like it so far, even if the dev machine sys requirements are very high, it took SOOO much to install, create and build the first project that I thought &ldquo;omg my computer sucks&rdquo;. Luckily it gets faster after that, I&rsquo;m using Rider which also helps, Visual Studio has become quite a resource hog in last few years on my machine. It will take a bunch of time for me to learn how to be at ease in Unreal, and I would need a real project for this later, but I don&rsquo;t consider it wasted at the moment even if I&rsquo;m not using it now professionally (yet).</p>
<h2 id="personal-projects-">Personal projects 💻</h2>
<p>With all that&rsquo;s been happening this year, as much as it makes me sad, I had my pet prototypes mostly in &ldquo;pause&rdquo;, contract work taking priority, which really feels like the &ldquo;excuse&rdquo; these last few years, but &ldquo;life am I right?&rdquo;. And this year FINDING work was the main priority of course.</p>
<p>That doesn&rsquo;t mean I stopped but it&rsquo;s been harder to find time to work on things, <a href="/2025/09/the-degradation-of-our-attention-spans/#accountability">streaming helped</a> and I&rsquo;ve been happy working on that silly-duckuban-rogue-game (wonder if I can turn it into a real game!), but I&rsquo;ve slowed down quite a lot since I landed a few new work gigs.</p>
<p><img alt="Duck duck prototype" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/duck_prototype.jpg"></p>
<p>But even if I haven&rsquo;t launched nothing by myself (in quite a while!), I&rsquo;ve been working enough on Godot that I feel more comfortable in it, to the point that I&rsquo;ve started finding a few frustrating things (a conversation for another day), which means I&rsquo;m on the right track if I started scratching the surface, as nothing is perfect. Also I&rsquo;ve worked on many projects via contract work in last few years and as I mentioned before, that is very fulfilling on it&rsquo;s own.</p>
<h2 id="games-">Games 🎮</h2>
<p>What a year indeed. After years of speculation, Nintendo finally released the sequel to it&rsquo;s best selling console, and a numeric version, breaking their pattern. The Nintendo Switch 2, very similar, bigger size, better screen, better specs and backward compatible with Switch 1. Joy-cons can be used as a mouse, on all accounts a very safe and unlike-Nintendo bet.</p>
<p>I grabbed mine on launch with Mario Kart World bundle, unfortunately the digital version as it was cheaper than the €90 the physical version was being sold at launch.
The screen is great, obviously playing on a bigger screen is nice. The Joycons are also more comfortable to hold and play, I find myself playing with them instead of the Pro Controller (1st version) now even in TV mode.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th><img alt="Nintendo Switch 2 Mario Kart World Bundle" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/nintendo_switch_2_mario_kart_bundle.jpg"></th>
          <th><img alt="Nintendo Switch 2 vs Nintendo Switch 1 screen size" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/nintendo_switch_2_vs_switch_1_size.jpg"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>But as usual with Nintendo, it&rsquo;s about the games, not necessarily just the hardware.</p>
<h3 id="mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</h3>
<p>A launch title, I&rsquo;ve played tons of hours of every entry (with exception of GBA and Wii version), and it&rsquo;s always a cool franchise to grab. The tracks are way bigger now, 24-players, and I loved exploring the world for giant creatures.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th><img alt="Mario Kart World screenshot" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/mario_kart_world_02.jpg"></th>
          <th><img alt="Mario Kart World screenshot" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/mario_kart_world_03.jpg"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Unfortunately while fun at start, I bounced off quickly to my surprise. Once I played all the tracks, the online was not as fun to grab me, can&rsquo;t really put my finger on why. I guess the smaller more handcrafted levels of MK8 especially, were more fun. I do enjoy the new game modes, but the excitement ended quickly. Maybe I&rsquo;m too spoiled at this moment, or had high expectations.</p>
<h3 id="donkey-kong-">Donkey Kong 🍌</h3>
<p>On the other hand, to my surprise, especially because I&rsquo;ve never played any Donkey Kong games (a sin I know, hold on, don&rsquo;t leave yet), and I grabbed this mostly because &ldquo;might as well try to justify the Switch 2 purchase&rdquo;, I love this game, and OH DID does it justify the Switch 2 and more. It&rsquo;s a system seller in my opinion.</p>
<p>I ended up almost doing 100% of it, it&rsquo;s immensely fun, the dopamine hits of that game is almost perfection, I&rsquo;m so glad this is a pay only once title, it could be a problem.</p>
<p><img alt="Donkey Kong Bananza" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/donkey_kong_bananza_01.jpg"></p>
<h3 id="ball-x-pitt">Ball x Pitt</h3>
<p>I initially purchased Clair Obscur: Expedition 33  because everyone was talking about it, but did not enjoy the combat, the timing thing felt off, and while I enjoyed games like Mario &amp; Luigi: Superstar Saga for example, which also has that, this one would not click for me.</p>
<p>I was thinking about returning it, but a friend took it off my hands in exchange for a few digital indie games. I picked Ball X Pitt and Crow Country based on a quick search. Ball X Pitt was random chance, but it&rsquo;s great, arkanoid on steroids, seriously go play.</p>
<p><img alt="Ball X Pitt" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/ball_x_pitt.jpg"></p>
<h3 id="dragon-quest-i-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest I HD-2D Remake</h3>
<p>Somehow I never played any Dragon Quest game until now, but when this was announced, I saw this screenshot&hellip;</p>
<p><img alt="Dragon Quest I HD-2D Remake" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/dragon_quest_1_hd_2d_remake.jpg"></p>
<p>&hellip; and bought the game. It comes packed with Dragon Quest II Remake as well. It reminded me a lot of the vibe of Phantasy Star IV. DQ1 is simple, short and not very feature packed compared with modern RPG standards, however that&rsquo;s exactly why I enjoyed it a ton, it was simple to pick, play a few combats and grab later. The modern Remake features helps a ton, also the fact that we only play as 1 character through the entire game, it needs a lot more grinding with 1 char only but if you are bored you can toggle invincibility on for those tougher fights. If you never picked any of the DQ games, I highly recommend picking this one.</p>
<h3 id="metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th><img alt="Metroid Prime 4" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/MetroidPrime4Beyond.jpg"></th>
          <th><img alt="Metroid Prime 4 Switch 2 Physical Edition" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/metroid_prime_4_switch_2_physical.jpg"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t finished this one (~10h in) so it&rsquo;s hard to judge it, but I decided to talk about it just because it&rsquo;s been SO DAMN LONG we&rsquo;ve been waiting for this, this game has been though dev hell for sure. Visually the game is stunning, solid 60FPS gameplay, smooth as butter movement. Sadly I don&rsquo;t have a 120Hz 4k tv so I can&rsquo;t experience the full thing but the base version is already stunning. I&rsquo;m enjoying it so far, let&rsquo;s hope I don&rsquo;t end up leaving it pending for years (I still haven&rsquo;t completed Metroid Prime 1 Remaster).</p>
<h2 id="taking-vacations-time-or-lack-of-">Taking vacations-time or lack of 🏝️</h2>
<p>Something to do better next year, I need to take proper vacation time, once in a while through the year, not just a burst session when I&rsquo;m near a wall and power through the rest of the year. 2025 was almost work non-stop, I only took a few days of proper &ldquo;completely off work&rdquo; during my birthday in March, and it was also partly related to personal-emotional issues I wanted to process.
So I ended up spending 4-5 days trekking and climbing mountains in the snow, which I have say is pretty cool and really helps, because it clears your mind, it&rsquo;s just kind of dangerous at times to do this alone. Also was a neat way to find the Apple Watch trekking app when you go off route really helps backtracking, battery isn&rsquo;t that great though when that is on, but I&rsquo;ve had this device for 4 years or so with original battery still.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_08.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 8" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_08.jpg"></a></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_02.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 2" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_02.jpg"></a></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_04.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 4" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_04.jpg"></a></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_07.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 7" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_07.jpg"></a></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_05.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 5" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_05.jpg"></a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_01.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 1" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_01.jpg"></a></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_03.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 3" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_03.jpg"></a></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_06.jpg"><img alt="David in the snow mountains March 2025 picture 6" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/david_switzerland_trip_march_2025_06.jpg"></a></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>I took tons of pictures and have a few videos that would be cool to share but it would be beside the point of the post.</p>
<h2 id="journaling-">Journaling 📝</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a habit I picked up in 2025 that I&rsquo;m having fun with, I&rsquo;ve always have a physical notebook in my desk but it&rsquo;s usually for random misc work-phone-calls quick notes stuff I need to take note of, consider or just brainstorm. But I grabbed a specific notebook just for writing down tasks of todos on a daily basis, and what I managed to get done. It seems silly but it really helps putting things in perspective, also I always like to do my crappy-art-doodles on the sides.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Journaling" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/journaling_01.jpg"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Journaling" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/journaling_02.jpg"></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="movies--tv-recommendations-">Movies &amp; TV Recommendations 🍿</h2>
<p>Had the chance to watch several Movies and TV Shows this year, leaving you with some of the stuff that stood out enough for me to recommend in no particular order.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
          <th style="text-align: center"></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="The Pitt" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/the_pitt_poster.webp"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Andor" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/andor_poster.jpg"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Severance" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/severance_poster.jpg"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Alien Earth" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/alien_earth_poster.webp"></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Weapons" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/weapons_poster.webp"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="F1" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/f1_poster.webp"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Blackberry" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/blackberry_poster.webp"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Until Dawn" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/until_dawn_poster.webp"></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="She Rides Shotgun" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/she_rides_shotgun_poster.webp"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Plur1bus" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/plur1bus_poster.jpg"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="The Running Man" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/the_running_man_poster.jpg"></td>
          <td style="text-align: center"><img alt="Ballerina" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/ballerina_poster.jpg"></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>If you have anything you watched and want to recommend let me know.</p>
<h2 id="heres-to-2026">Here&rsquo;s to 2026!</h2>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have a crystal ball so I have no idea what&rsquo;s going to happen, and usually I&rsquo;m more of the &ldquo;plan for the worst, hope for the best&rdquo; kind of person. Majority of stuff happening in the world we have little to no control whatsoever. We can be optimistic but also realistic.
And if I look objectively to the things that most impacted me directly this year, I took action on some, and it helped, and the rest that pending because I have yet to take action on them.</p>
<p>Someone wiser than me once said that most of stress is not taking action when we can, not when things fail.</p>
<p>In case you made it this far, thanks for reading, I do really appreciate it, it took me a couple days of writing in smaller sessions, so glad to know it&rsquo;s not only posting to the void.</p>
<p>So if you had a stressful year, remember, this too shall pass.
Wish you a great 2026!</p>
<p><img alt="2026 Nintendo Shop Calendar" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/2026_nintendo_calendar.jpg"></p>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Degradation of our attention spans</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/09/the-degradation-of-our-attention-spans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2025/09/the-degradation-of-our-attention-spans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-interruption&#34;&gt;An interruption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, how did you get here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it a notification, scrolling a feed, did you saw my post and pressed the link, an RSS feed perhaps? What was the interruption that broke your flow, and do you remember the last thing before? Or even before, before you were on socials or scrolling whatever got you here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Gandalf I don&amp;rsquo;t remember&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.david-amador.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/gandalf_I_have_no_recollection.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, maybe an exaggeration here, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been that long, but how often does that happen? That rabbit-hole where you set your time to do a certain thing and by the end you don&amp;rsquo;t even remember what it was?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="an-interruption">An interruption</h3>
<p>Ok, how did you get here?</p>
<p>Was it a notification, scrolling a feed, did you saw my post and pressed the link, an RSS feed perhaps? What was the interruption that broke your flow, and do you remember the last thing before? Or even before, before you were on socials or scrolling whatever got you here?</p>
<p><img alt="Gandalf I don&rsquo;t remember" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/gandalf_I_have_no_recollection.jpg"></p>
<p>Sorry, maybe an exaggeration here, it hasn&rsquo;t been that long, but how often does that happen? That rabbit-hole where you set your time to do a certain thing and by the end you don&rsquo;t even remember what it was?</p>
<h3 id="the-best-time-was-yesterday-now-its-today">The best time was yesterday, now it&rsquo;s today</h3>
<p>The irony of this title is I&rsquo;ve had it on my mind for a couple months, but kept postponing for later. <em>Oh &hellip; the lack of time, too much work, something got in the way&hellip;</em> nah, let&rsquo;s be honest here, there&rsquo;s always something that I (we?) keep leaving for later and could be done rather quickly.</p>
<p>If only I had focused, giving it the proper and full attention for the required time it needs to get done, no side-quests. And I&rsquo;m not just talking about big tasks that take weeks or months, but smaller ones, quick ones, that I could finish, snowballing the piece of mind that comes from taking action and getting things done.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s rarely just lack of time, if I sum up the wasted time looking at useless stuff or context switching since April (been a while since my <a href="/2025/04/switching-unity-to-godot-my-experience-so-far/">last post</a>) I could have gotten this post done a long, long time ago. <em>queues Star Wars theme</em>, speaking of that, Andor is just great isn&rsquo;t it?</p>
<p>See, our brains have this tendency of stretching and tethering to other subjects. Or maybe it&rsquo;s a <em>me</em> problem.</p>
<h3 id="stress-from-not-taking-action">Stress from not taking action</h3>
<p>Being overwhelmed by things to do, tasks we want to finish, tasks we SHOULD finish, side projects, freezing over selection of what to do next; is a natural occurrence as we want to do more, and have more on our plate, are handed over more tasks to do, or //TODO: that we kept on delaying.</p>
<p>It can be work, personal things, asking for something, replying to that email/text, a difficult conversation.</p>
<p>The more we pile the worst it gets because the possibilities are now so many. And the process of freezing while selecting the best use of our time, becomes the time sink itself.</p>
<p>Procrastination, leaving it for later, I&rsquo;ll do that in a bit, but first I guess &hellip; hold on  &hellip;. let me just &hellip;. watch check this notification first&hellip;</p>
<p><img alt="A few moments later" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/few_moments_later.jpg"></p>
<p>Wait where did the time go? It&rsquo;s that easy isn&rsquo;t it?</p>
<h3 id="free-time-guilt">Free-time guilt</h3>
<p>Have a bit of time you could actually relax, rest and recharge your batteries but feel guilty you should be working?</p>
<p>In a way that might be because there isn&rsquo;t a clear separation of tasks time and &ldquo;me time&rdquo;, so if we context-switch a lot in allocated time for work, in the time you should be resting the brain doesn&rsquo;t feel like it accomplished what it should have. Limbo.</p>
<p>Do you start a movie and pick up the phone while the title is rolling?</p>
<h3 id="doom-scrolling">Doom scrolling</h3>
<p>An expression that gets thrown a lot to define how the internet is (attempting and succeeding) to trap us on an endless scrolling of brainrot content. The quality really doesn&rsquo;t matter, their whole goal is to keep us there, and that&rsquo;s also one of the reason why the internet overall feels <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enshittification">enshittified</a>.</p>
<p>And while that is a whole different topic, it does prey and augments the issue that our attention span is being reduced, harder to stay focused on something.</p>
<h3 id="donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</h3>
<p>Wait, what? Yeah sorry, bear with me for a second. 🍌</p>
<p>I got Donkey Kong Bananza at launch (July 17th), so around 2 months ago, it&rsquo;s great, been playing a lot of it, has that right mix of gameplay and dopamine hit.</p>
<p>I found myself ONLY playing that on Switch 2, whenever time allowed, for these 2 months, no switching (bad pun intended) to other games in between. There have been many games where I&rsquo;ll start and finish over time (still gotta complete Metroid Prime), but also a lot that I&rsquo;ll just eventually give up as time passes, not because I don&rsquo;t like them, but switching to other games usually makes it happen faster, because the attention span is now elsewhere, and then something else.</p>
<p>So DK Bananza made me have that strange and comfortable feeling that whenever I had time to play, I wouldn&rsquo;t idle-freeze considering &ldquo;what should I play now? &hellip;. omg I&rsquo;m out of time&rdquo;.
A bit like if you boot up Netflix and you&rsquo;re not sure exactly what to watch, you scroll a bit, time passes and &hellip; wait a notification &hellip; shit it&rsquo;s 2am.&quot;</p>
<h3 id="multiple-things-at-a-time">Multiple things at a time</h3>
<p>I guess I&rsquo;ve always had that issue a bit, I remember back when I was working on Vizati or QoD (because it took years), many times that I decided to do a gamejam during on-going projects, my brain would get invested in that new thing and the old thing seemed like well &hellip; old now.</p>
<p>When you reach a more complicated part in #gamedev, or boring phases you might be a bit stuck, or unsure of the quality, everything else seems more exciting so it&rsquo;s easier to think &ldquo;what if I do a smaller project, this new idea seems better&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Most times it isn&rsquo;t that, but our brain trying to get the next dopamine hit that comes from the initial stages of something, where the ideas just flow and our brain lits.</p>
<p>Learning can be quite interesting but we, as a population, are mostly consuming &ldquo;knowledge&rdquo; 10 seconds at a time and moving on, it doesn&rsquo;t matter anymore, this becomes a cycle.</p>
<p><img alt="Calvin and Hobbes short attention span" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/calvin_hobbes_short_attention_span.jpg">
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes">Calvin and Hobbes comic strip</a></p>
<h3 id="one-thing-at-a-time">One thing at a time</h3>
<p>I was having this conversation with a friend the other day about TV Shows, he watches multiple weekly-released TV Shows at a time, I wait for full seasons, so we are always out-of-sync if we want to discuss about a particular show.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll try to watch just one show at a time, not necessarily binge watching in one weekend, but only one, until I finish the season or quit watching, very often I&rsquo;ll wait weeks (waiting for Alien TV show to wrap up) for something to complete. I can watch at my own speed, but only one. This is probably the only situation where I can control that very well, no pressure, I don&rsquo;t even think about it, I know it usually pays off, I can wait, know how much time I&rsquo;ll need to watch, when I fill that in, and with it comes a certain liberation of either finishing or quitting them.</p>
<p>So can I do this with other things? Well&hellip;. not quite, for example this article you are reading (still there?), it wasn&rsquo;t written in one go, not because it needs research, or it&rsquo;s a super complicated topic, or even that long to write; but because when I searched that image of Calvin and Hobbes you saw a bit above, I got side-tracked and ended up watching unrelated stuff and then decided it was already late and might as well do it &ldquo;tomorrow&rdquo;.</p>
<p><img alt="Han Solo It&rsquo;s not my fault" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/han_solo_not_my_fault.jpg"></p>
<p>Except it is!</p>
<h3 id="social-networks-">Social Networks ⛓️</h3>
<p>Well sure the world seems crazy now (or I am?), and a big part of our lives is interacting online somehow, we are constantly bombarded by things to trigger us.</p>
<p>One can logoff and &ldquo;touch grass&rdquo;, that is actually surprisingly easier than I anticipated (I managed to not use Twitter for months now, and I thought it would be a problem), I don&rsquo;t miss it, although I do have that feeling that I might &ldquo;be missing something&rdquo;. I can&rsquo;t deny that a lot of work opportunities came from that platform!</p>
<p>But that enshittification spreads quickly, recently I&rsquo;ve being going to LinkedIn more often; to search for work and/or maybe something a bit more stable (btw do tell me if you are looking, or know someone in need for a programmer with my &ldquo;particular set of skills&rdquo;); and that Feed is absolute trash fire, people are using it as they used Twitter and other networks, most stuff I see there almost always unrelated to work, but instead &ldquo;the drama&rdquo; of the day.</p>
<p>So it&rsquo;s everywhere now, it used to be more contained to certain corners of the internet.</p>
<p>And the problem is that there is no winning there, not worth trying, fuelling arguments will just take your time, sanity, and kill your mood. I&rsquo;ve seen mutuals enrolling in discussions that I know are topics close to their hearts but it won&rsquo;t help at all unfortunately.</p>
<p>And that&rsquo;s why those algorithms push certain posts to the front of the page, for &hellip;</p>
<h3 id="engagement">Engagement</h3>
<p>By now I imagine a large percentage has stopped reading the article, maybe because it&rsquo;s not that interesting or any good, but some got a notification and &ldquo;quickly check&rdquo; and are not on another path, who knows where they are now, keeping someone engaged is hard on it&rsquo;s own, especially if there are millions of possible distractions.</p>
<p>Many freemium games have that gotcha thing, to keep you hooked, engaged, if you aren&rsquo;t paying with money, you are paying with time. Your life time!</p>
<p>An interesting argument I heard once &ldquo;David you can say that about anything, a book wants to keep you engaged, a movie as well&rdquo;.
And while we can agree, I disagree on the fundaments, because a company doesn&rsquo;t care much if you read the book as long as you pay for it, or buy the ticket, or the DVD. The intention of quality will come from the creator to make you satisfied enough to see/buy their next work, to recommend to friends. If they trick you once they probably won&rsquo;t do it again.</p>
<p>But with a shift to live-services, subscriptions and freemium models, things are specifically designed to keep us hooked all the time, they HAVE to trick us constantly, the money doesn&rsquo;t come directly from each purchase, not even from each user, but from carefully handcrafted/manipulated loop to exploit our time.</p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250826100802/https://automaton-media.com/en/news/almost-19-of-japanese-people-in-their-20s-have-spent-so-much-money-on-gacha-they-struggled-with-covering-living-expenses-survey-reveals/"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/19_percent_japanese_people_gotcha_games.jpg"></a></p>
<p>Isn&rsquo;t this article crazy? This is the result over time, it&rsquo;s insane and quite upsetting.</p>
<p>I went on a weird tangent there, let&rsquo;s talk about &hellip;.</p>
<h3 id="work--routine">Work &amp; routine</h3>
<p>Work is something that luckily I&rsquo;ve managed to keep in a more controlled state, and I don&rsquo;t find it as problematic, but it&rsquo;s a combination of multiple things that help with that, and two of the ones I consider most important for me is a clear set of decided things that need to be done and routine.</p>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;m not a good &ldquo;decider of things&rdquo;, but I can usually be better at getting them done, or finding a way, or just asking someone else for help. The goal is clear, I just have to get there. Even if there&rsquo;s a bug where I don&rsquo;t know anything, there&rsquo;s a clear goal &ldquo;fix this issue&rdquo;. The problem really comes from a blank canvas, or until I can decide the first stroke of paint and color I guess.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s why planning is so important, and some people are great at planning but not starting; I&rsquo;m better at starting if I don&rsquo;t have to plan much. None is necessarily better that the other, but knowing your strengths is good.</p>
<p>I few times I got asked &ldquo;why are you doing this?&rdquo;, and the answer is often &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know but if I don&rsquo;t start I&rsquo;ll never know&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Lack of planning might only take you so far, but lack of action takes you nowhere. So usually just starting is great, but focus, and that&rsquo;s usually the advice I give to anyone asking me &ldquo;How can I learn gamedev?&rdquo;. Just &hellip; start!</p>
<p>Routine is extremely important as well, I could not have accomplished working remotely for so many years if I didn&rsquo;t set a clear &ldquo;time to start working&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s always flexibility sure, but I quickly learned the best way is just habits and routine, your brain and body knows it&rsquo;s time and it&rsquo;s much easier.</p>
<p>Getting up, going for a walk, not random, mostly always the same path so that I don&rsquo;t get distracted but still get some exercise and it helps with stress, coming back sort yourself and just start working.</p>
<p>I guess the third factor that is important is &hellip;</p>
<h3 id="accountability">Accountability!</h3>
<p>A month or so ago I read two different things within a couple days apart that got me curious.
One person was saying that they were building a game and sharing the progress on social but the lack of engagement from sharing the progress was making them unsure and demotivated about the project and they haven&rsquo;t been able to progress much. That&rsquo;s rough, and very relatable.</p>
<p>A few days after I read on an unrelated forum someone talking about marketing and video-promotional-content not being great for people who don&rsquo;t feel comfortable doing that. A few comments deep there was someone talking about streaming, and that streaming themselves working, even if most of the time for 0 viewers, had made them more productive because they had to plan something doing online.</p>
<p>Now that got my attention. 👀</p>
<p>I talked with <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/sorcerystory">a friend</a> who&rsquo;s been streaming gamedev for a while and she confirmed that there are things that she plans, otherwise it would be harder to just &hellip; be here.</p>
<p>So I decided to give it a try, been doing it for a month now, and yeah it&rsquo;s pretty cool, I plan a few tasks, some take longer, others are shorter, but if I run out of planned things, I have to just come up with something on the fly (sometimes I&rsquo;ll see bugs while live so it helps). Most of the time I&rsquo;m at zero viewers, but it doesn&rsquo;t really matter because it keeps you motivated to work on your own stuff, also you never know who might show up.</p>
<p>A great side effect is that I found myself talking while typing, like reading the code out loud and the process behind it, even if alone (again because you never know), and that helps a ton, I realize how dumb some solutions might be before hand, like when you rubber duck it with someone.</p>
<p>I am not using a face camera, it was actually Joana who mention that to me, that a lot of people don&rsquo;t use cameras, and it doesn&rsquo;t matter depending on the streamer&rsquo;s goal. So I just grabbed an old GoPro, it&rsquo;s showing a view to my Keyboard, I have a Mic and I just work, it&rsquo;s fun. I even added a task list on screen which I update as I go (this was a viewer suggestion).</p>
<p><img alt="Twitch layout" loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/david_twitch_streaming_setup.jpg"></p>
<p>That thermal printer on the right corner was yet another side-project that I thought &ldquo;what if I hook up a python script to receive notifications of new followers and trigger a print by USB?&rdquo; as you can see, the getting distracted by other things still does happen, luckily this one was short, it&rsquo;s done and I got it out of my system.</p>
<h3 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h3>
<p>I think in the past humans were able to stay focused more time mostly because there were less things in front of us, with a more modern connected-world comes a new challenge of being able to filter our the noise from what we need, while still staying in it, connected and alert to knowledge.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t think this all comes from technology, like it&rsquo;s the worst thing ever, but it uses our weakness against us. People will always be distracted and not fully focused for long, it&rsquo;s natural, but the problem now is we are getting distracted with things that add little to our lives. Better to have a bunch of failed projects than 300h of videos, because the failed projects you got them out of your system.</p>
<h3 id="its-been-a-minute-">It&rsquo;s been a minute ⌚</h3>
<p>Thank you for reading all of this, some of it might not make sense, but this is usually the result of my brain dumping a bunch of thoughts in one post, something I wanted to talk about, the best part is that I&rsquo;ve cleared this from my mind, it feels good, even if no one reads it, it was something I wanted to do and now it&rsquo;s done.</p>
<p>That thing you&rsquo;ve been meaning to do? Start, just do it, don&rsquo;t end this just to browse the next YouTube video, or Instagram. We overestimate how much we can get done in a week, but we underestimate how much we can get done in a year.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll paraphrase something I&rsquo;ve once read on a book (which I now can&rsquo;t remember).</p>
<p>Giving meaning to life comes from having a purpose, and having a purpose comes from taking action.</p>
<hr>
<p>See you in the next post!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So where is that motivation?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/so-where-is-that-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 22:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/03/so-where-is-that-motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I follow a couple of dev blogs, some are game developers, others make websites or software.&lt;br&gt;
In the last couple of months I’ve been reading a lot of them complaining about lack of motivation to develop their idea of the lack of motivation for development in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happens to me too, heck it happens to everyone once in a while…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s something that happens usually half way though or after you get the initial prototype running.&lt;br&gt;
Around one year ago (Feb 2010) when I started developing our first game it was all great, new stuff every day, things starting to work, replacing my crappy programmer art by Rita’s drawings.&lt;br&gt;
The real endurance was after we had a working demo, and the decision of actually finishing the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I follow a couple of dev blogs, some are game developers, others make websites or software.<br>
In the last couple of months I’ve been reading a lot of them complaining about lack of motivation to develop their idea of the lack of motivation for development in general.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Happens to me too, heck it happens to everyone once in a while…</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s something that happens usually half way though or after you get the initial prototype running.<br>
Around one year ago (Feb 2010) when I started developing our first game it was all great, new stuff every day, things starting to work, replacing my crappy programmer art by Rita’s drawings.<br>
The real endurance was after we had a working demo, and the decision of actually finishing the game.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Should be 2-3 weeks, it’s just making more levels</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I really said that, worst, I was convinced that would be the case. But it wasn’t, and fine tuning stuff is the worst part, when the game mechanics are there and you are lacking the patient to add that one more feature that will probably induce 5 bugs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Finish you game</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many indie devs never finish their game due to time constrains and/or their real job, but there’s a bunch that never finish anything because half-way though they loose interest and move to another project.</p>
<p>Moving to another project can sometimes be forced, you don’t have the money to pull it off, you don’t have the time to make such a big project or the game simply sucks, these are all valid. I have some projects on the back-burner that are not possible at this moment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>New ideas can be a bitch…</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But how to deal with the fact that you are tired of making the game, even though it has potential?<br>
When first starting I always think, nah, that’s not going to happen, it’s a great idea. But how many times are you making one game and thinking on the next idea, and damn, that new idea is even greater, why not drop everything and make that one instead?</p>
<p>That’s when problems start, because even though you won’t switch when bugs/problems for the current project start popping you won’t have as much patient as you should, because in your mind you should be doing something else.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Working with someone or showing you game to friends helps.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you are working with someone else it’s a bit easier to work this out. 2 people working for the same goal gives a sense of “this is it” to the whole thing.<br>
Working alone sucks a bit more, but you just have to set some goals.<br>
Make a working prototype, give it to some friends, collect feedback, they will probably make tons of suggestions, and you’ll get more excited with it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Easy to say, hard to to so.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I still find it hard to do so, especially the whole “I shouldn’t have any more ideas while working on this”.<br>
But it happens, the other night I woke up at 6AM, had an idea for something so instead I wrote it down on a notepad, and I’ll grab it when I’m out of ideas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
