<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 12:47:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s take a look at SDL Game Development book</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/07/lets-take-a-look-at-sdl-game-development-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 12:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2013/07/lets-take-a-look-at-sdl-game-development-book/</guid>
      <description>I use SDL 1.2 on my engine, but just for the window creation and input handling. That prevents me for writing boring window handling code for each platform, it just works.
These days SDL can be use on almost every platform, Windows, Mac, Linux, iOS, Android. They recently launched the a new version, SDL 2.0 and I was lucky to receive a copy of SDL Game Development written by Shaun Mitchell that covers that new version.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I use SDL 1.2 on my engine, but just for the window creation and input handling. That prevents me for writing boring window handling code for each platform, it just works.</p>
<p>These days SDL can be use on almost every platform, Windows, Mac, Linux, iOS, Android. They recently launched the a new version, SDL 2.0 and I was lucky to receive a copy of <a href="http://www.packtpub.com/simple-directmedia-layer-game-development/book">SDL Game Development</a> written by Shaun Mitchell that covers that new version.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.packtpub.com/simple-directmedia-layer-game-development/book"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/6821OT_cov-243x300.jpg" alt="6821OT_cov"  />
</a></p>
<p>For anyone who is starting on game development and wants to use SDL this is a good book, it has simple code and everything is very well explained. But make no mistake, I don’t recommend this for someone who doesn’t know code at all, you need to know some C++ to use it, or at least some object oriented language, but chances are, if you are reading my blog you know a OOP language already.</p>
<p>Everything in the book is explained in a simple way and I don’t see anyone having any problems, I really liked the code examples, usually some books have a very “non real” code, stuff that while it works no-one usually does it like that, but this one has stuff that I would do that exact same way. It guides you from making the first hello project to loading an image, a game state machine, getting input from Keyboard, Mouse and Joysticks, a manager to handle textures, and creating a tilemap using <a href="http://www.mapeditor.org/">Tiled</a>. The Tiled chapter was a positive surprise since not many beginner/intermediate books go much into a data-driven design, and this is very important to make modern games, while it might seem hard to implement for a beginner, trust me it is well worth it.</p>
<p>Now for things that you might be expecting but are not covered, the book doesn’t cover any OpenGL/DirectX specifics, so if you are looking for that you won’t find it here. It is possible to directly call GL/DX instead of using SDL draw calls, this is something I do, but you might lose platform independence if not done properly. Shaders are something also not covered, but then again SDL has no native support for that, you have to do it yourself.</p>
<p>I also would have liked if the book covered more on configuring SDL on Mac, Linux too, since most people who choose SDL usually do want to build on those platforms.</p>
<p>To end this short review, I would say that for everyone that are starting in gamedev, or never used SDL this is a good book, for someone who has already used SDL 2.0 or even 1.2 in the past you probably won’t find much here that you don’t already know.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I was not payed in any form to take a look at this book, nor was this post redacted/altered in any way. I reviewed the book by reading the digital format. You can find both the digital and physical book on the link above.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rage</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 16:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2011/12/rage/</guid>
      <description>So being a big fan of Quake, Quake 3 Arena and Doom I was eager to get my hands on id Software latest game, Rage.
Like most developers out there I’ve been impressed by John Carmack’s work and breakthroughs in gaming and computer graphics for years. When I first heard Rage was targeting 60FPS I got intrigued.
Almost every game targets 30FPS and targeting twice as that leaves less time to render each frame, even more since they were promising vast wastelands, detailed characters, top notch animations and AI.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So being a big fan of Quake, Quake 3 Arena and Doom I was eager to get my hands on id Software latest game, Rage.</p>
<p>Like most developers out there I’ve been impressed by John Carmack’s work and breakthroughs in gaming and computer graphics for years. When I first heard Rage was targeting 60FPS I got intrigued.<br>
Almost every game targets 30FPS and targeting twice as that leaves <a href="/2011/08/hurry-you-only-have-16-ms-to-render-everything/" title="Hurry you only have 16 ms to render everything">less time to render each frame</a>, even more since they were promising vast wastelands, detailed characters, top notch animations and AI.</p>
<p>But enough of that. I got the PC version since I’m old fashioned and I think shooters are best played with Mouse/Kb. Besides that shooters are always a tad slower on consoles to compensate the lack of Mouse for aiming.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg" alt=""  title="WP_000105"  />
</a></p>
<p>The game comes packed on 3 DVD summing a 23GB install.</p>
<p>The story takes place after a meteor crashing into the earth, several arks where placed underground with people in order for mankind to survive. You are one of those survivors.<br>
There isn’t much more into, after you wake up you discovered most of the planet is a wasteland ruled by bandits, mutants and others.</p>
<p>From there you jump from mission to mission against the several factions.</p>
<p>Apart from some technical issues I first encountered, after updating the drivers I managed to play it smoothly on my laptop, my desktop rig is quite old now (6+ years) so it doesn’t quite handle it at 1080p.</p>
<p>I’m very impressed with the game’s smooth animations and enemy AI. The story itself is crap but the whole fun in this game is just playing it, the battles always feel fresh, holding the shotgun feels like an id gun indeed. You keep encountering new enemies with new tricks, near the end you are still trying to get the hang of that new enemy tactics.</p>
<p>If you have the chance try it.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00001.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00001-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00007.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00007-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00010.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00010-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00012.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00012-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00005.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00005-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00008.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00008-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00009.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00009-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00010.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-23_00010-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00015.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-10-22_00015-300x168.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/WP_000105.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Meat Boy, meat dissection</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/super-meat-boy-meat-dissection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 20:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/10/super-meat-boy-meat-dissection/</guid>
      <description>I don’t usually write reviews about games, maybe mostly because I don’t play as often as I used to. Most games today are just graphics graphics, I use super shader ray-traced lights but I forgot gameplay because I’m a tech demo.
I grew up with a Super Nintendo playing Super Mario World and Zelda A Link to the Past, yeah shocker, no Spectrum to me :P, so I’m 2D gameplay type lover.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don’t usually write reviews about games, maybe mostly because I don’t play as often as I used to. Most games today are just graphics graphics, I use super shader ray-traced lights but I forgot gameplay because I’m a tech demo.<br>
I <a href="/2010/08/games-and-systems-from-childhood/">grew up with a Super Nintendo</a> playing Super Mario World and Zelda A Link to the Past, yeah shocker, no Spectrum to me :P, so I’m 2D gameplay type lover.</p>
<p>I always loved Mario games, the precision and the rush of making a level without stopping or speeding down was as good as it gets for platform games in my opinion. This is the key point in Mario games, not the story, why else would people still be playing those games? The princess keeps being kidnapped by the same dude, there’s basically no story so what keeps gamers coming around is gameplay and fun.</p>
<p>This is what Super Meat Boy brings us, excellent gameplay with all the frustration and deaths that actually brings meaning to reaching the end of a level. I’ve been following Meat Boy development ever since it was announced, well in fact I’m an avid Edmund Mcmillen fan even since <a href="http://www.chroniclogic.com/gish.htm">Gish</a>, I even bought his “This is a cry for help” cd, comes packed with 18 games and great comics, you should get it if we is still selling them.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/edmund_mcmillen_this_is_a_cry_for_help_cd.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/edmund_mcmillen_this_is_a_cry_for_help_cd.jpg" alt=""  title="This is a cry for Help Edmund Mcmillen CD proof :P"  />
</a></p>
<p>Sorry Tommy Refenes but I don’t know any of your past works. Anyway, back on track…</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/1269147417.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/1269147417.jpg" alt=""  title="1269147417"  />
</a></p>
<p>The game is a fast paced platform game with a block of meat which mission is to reach Bandage Girl (it’s Super Meat Boy “princess peach”) on every level, for that we must jump, jump, jump, avoid traps, jump, did I mention we has to jump?</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/snessmb.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/snessmb.jpg" alt=""  title="snessmb"  />
</a></p>
<p>The entire game is about precision and button timing, you fail you die, too slow? goodbye.<br>
This will put you swearing at the TV like you never did, believe me, and not because the buttons feel dumb or the game didn’t respond but because you sucked and died. The controls are so well responsive that it feels like they grabbed Super Mario controls code and improved it.<br>
Plus the Xbox360 controller buttons colors are almost the same as the SNES controller, I felt like going back in time.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/xbox360controller1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/xbox360controller1.jpg" alt=""  title="xbox360controller"  />
</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/Snes_control.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/Snes_control.jpg" alt=""  title="Snes_control"  />
</a></p>
<p>A curious thing is, there’s a run button, the X and another for jump, the A button. Most of the time you will be running so the run button feels almost useless. Well the obvious thing is, on tight platforms you won’t be running, the other thing is this was the first time since those early hardcore platform games which I felt that pressing that button all the time helped me grasping the controller better, and jump seem more timed because you are using the same finger to press them both. Just try it, you’ll see what I mean.</p>
<p>Graphically the game is simple but pretty with small details that you’ll probably miss the first time you play each level. My only complaint is that the cutscenes don’t feel like they belong in the game, because the lack of detail in scenarios and characters, luckily most will put a smile on your face so no harm done.</p>
<p>The game is packed with unlockable characters from other indie games like Beat Trip, Braid, Gish, you name it. For that you need to collect bandages all across the levels. The other things is that each level has a Light and Dark World, (Zelda Link to the Past memories for me) and you unlock the Dark World, which is even harder when you score an A in the Light World.</p>
<p>So the game is a blast and I highly recommend it, even more because right now is at 800 MS Points.</p>
<p>Here’s a video of me playing, be warned I’m not a very good player 😛</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8gwh1O1OpyQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
