<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wordpress on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wordpress on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 17:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting the blog from WordPress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/01/converting-the-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2024/01/converting-the-blog-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I shutdown the VPS that has been hosting all my websites for the last ~10 years. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved everything to static content, including this website.
📝 WordPress Since the very beginning (~2008) this blog has been powered by WordPress, it served me well, it worked, had a nice backend to make the posts, plugins and themes. After a couple years I moved from shared hosting to a VPS, I had other websites and services I needed running and all in same machine was better and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search and Replace in MySQL</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/search-and-replace-in-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 11:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/10/search-and-replace-in-mysql/</guid>
      <description>I found something very handy today, search and replace on Mysql databases. You can do it on phpmyadmin or make a php script with this.
After moving a wordpress site from server I discovered that all image links were broken because they are placed directly inside each post. They were still linking to the old server. Changing it manually would be a nightmare.
Luckily MySql is your friend. To search and replace a text string, start up phpMyAdmin, and click on your database name that you want to run the search and replace through.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/wordpress-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 10:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2009/04/wordpress-gallery/</guid>
      <description>During my efforts to combine Rita’s website to wordpress and with a cool gallery I came up with a few problems.
Mainly because the top navigation bar was built using J-Query, which I’ve already made quite some time ago, and even after switching to mootools I didn’t want to be rebuilding it again.
So yesterday after a few searches I managed to install NextGen gallery plugin for wordpress and using LightBox for popups.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
