<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iPad on David Amador</title>
    <link>https://www.david-amador.com/tags/ipad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iPad on David Amador</description>
    <image>
      <title>David Amador</title>
      <url>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</url>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/david-amador-pixel.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 13:38:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.david-amador.com/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dary&#39;s Legend alpha released</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/12/darys-legend-alpha-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 13:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2012/12/darys-legend-alpha-released/</guid>
      <description>Yay, so a milestone was reached with this project. If you follow my blog you probably already know that between small projects like Puwang and other mandatory freelancing stuff my big project in hands for these past few months is Dary’s Legend, a roguelike.
Around two months ago I coincidentally bumped into a conversation about funding and the whole kickstarter thing where one of Desura staff members was participating, and while talking about my own problems funding a whole game out of my pocket he mentioned that he knew the game and that Desura’s Alpha Funding might be a good place for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPad launch images support for all orientations</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 23:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/ipad-launch-images-support-for-all-orientations/</guid>
      <description>When loading an application on an iPhone or iPad, a launch image can be shown to provide feedback to the user that the application is loading.
On the iPhone a Default.png was used, with the iPad we need to anticipate the device being started in any orientation.
Filename Dimensions Default-Portrait.png * 768w x 1024h Default-PortraitUpsideDown.png 768w x 1024h Default-Landscape.png ** 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeLeft.png 1024w x 768h Default-LandscapeRight.png 1024w x 768h Default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targetting iOS devices hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 12:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/09/targetting-ios-devices-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I decided to compile all iOS devices specs here so we can get a better glimpse on their hardware and what we can expect from them.
This covers iPhones, iPod Touches and iPad.
iPhone/iPhone 3G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPhone 3GS – 600 MHz / 256MB / 320×480
iPhone 4 -~800MHz / 512MB / 640×960
iPod Touch 1G – 412 MHz / 128MB / 320×480
iPod Touch 2G – 532 MHz / 128MB / 320×480</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are your target platforms for games?</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 20:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/what-are-your-target-platforms-for-games/</guid>
      <description>I decided to run a little poll to track what platforms do you target as a game developer. I think this should be interesting. Please share this post link or the direct link to the poll (http://twtpoll.com/dar51l) so that we can have more accurate results.
The poll closes in about 6 days and you can select various options of course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing dark borders sprites on iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 12:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.david-amador.com/2010/07/fixing-dark-borders-sprites-on-iphone/</guid>
      <description>I ran into this issue a couple hours ago working on the iPhone sdk:
See the darker borders around the image?
It’s a png image and that’s was supposed to be a gradient of alpha. So why am I getting this strange stuff around it?
Well that’s because that alpha isn’t 0 or 1 or 0 or 255.
The first thing I found out is that XCode grabs the png images and multiplies the RGB component with the alpha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
